Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
It’s eating the Angel?
Those bindings were what allowed us
to control the Eva’s power.
But now the Eva is removing the
web that binds it to our will.
Unit 01’s been awakened and set free!
SEELE won’t stay quiet for this.
The Eva series isn’t capable of
generating S2 organs themselves.
But we never imagined that it would
be able to take one into itself this way.
This incident is at extreme odds with
the scenario SEELE created.
It will not be easy to correct this.
Gendo Ikari...  It was a mistake to
entrust NERV to him, wasn’t it?
But he was the only one who could
achieve this project’s goals.
Ikari, what’s going on in your mind?
It’s begun, hasn’t it?
Yes, this is the beginning.
Episode 20:
Form of the Mind,
Form of the Man
Damage on both Evas is over
the Hayflick limit, beyond
any normal restoration.
It may be a while before we can
restore everything to normal.
Fortunately, the MAGI system can be
transferred to a new location.
We may be able to start
working tomorrow.
But this place will have
to be scrapped.
It’s just a matter of time before the
brass decides to abandon it.
That’s true.
For the time being, we’ll have to use
the Secondary Command Center.
You mean, without the MAGI?
That’s right.
We can clean the dust off and be
working again by this afternoon.
But the chairs are too cramped down
there, and the sensors don’t operate
smoothly.  It’s difficult to work there.
But at least the layout is the same
as our original Command Center.
It just feels like we don’t belong there.
At least we have an alternative.
We have no choice when it
comes to using Unit 01.
It may be restrained by the cage,
but are you sure it’s safe?
No heat emissions, free electrons,
electromagnetic fields or chemical
reactions are being detected.
The S2 unit is completely inactive.
Nevertheless, on three
separate occasions Unit 01 has
moved without power.
You can’t judge this situation just by
the things you can see and measure.
Yeah, we can’t take any chances,
that’s for sure.
It’s as unpredictable as
you are, Katsuragi.
I’m sorry.
However, our concerns are
not limited to Unit 01.
Correct.  Serious damage was
sustained by Units 00 and 02.
Headquarters was partially destroyed,
exposing Central Dogma.
The destruction was enormous.
We can’t even estimate how much
money and time have been lost.
This all is because we didn’t put
a bell around Ikari’s neck.
A bell was there, but it didn’t ring.
A bell that doesn’t ring
serves no purpose.
We’ll make sure the bell
works next time.
My, my, what an unexpected situation!
How will you explain to
the committee...  I mean, how will
you explain this to SEELE?
Unit 01 wasn’t under our control.
This was an accident.
Unit 01 will remain frozen until the
committee gives us further orders.
That’s a very appropriate decision.
However, isn’t your son
still trapped inside it?
It’s hopeless.  It’s not accepting the
code to eject the entry plug.
What about the backup codes?
Also refused.  Even a direct circuit
isn’t getting through.
The plug’s video monitor
is active, though.
Switching to main screen.
What in the hell is this?
I’d say that’s the truth behind
a 400% synch ratio.
I can’t believe it.
What happened to Shinji?
Apparently the Eva has taken
him into itself.
What does that mean?!
Just what is an Eva?!
It is something created by man in
man’s own image.  I really can’t
describe it any other way.
You didn’t create anything!
You just copied something you
found in the Antarctic!
What was the original?
That’s what I want to know, Doctor!
This is not just a copy.
A human will is inside it.
Are you saying somebody willed
this to happen?
No, the Eva did.
Do something, damn you!
You created this, didn’t you?!
Take responsibility for it!!
On the issue of the Nansa Islands...
...the government and the Ministry of
Internal Affairs have announced that
there is no federal involvement.
In other news, it has been a
month since the terrorist
incident in Tokyo-2...
...and the government has announced
new legislation to prevent another...
I’m still alive.
...and the government has announced
new legislation to prevent another...
I know that Wonder Girl is still alive!
Why are you bothering me with trivial
crap like that, Misato?!
I can’t believe it.
I couldn’t do anything.
I can’t believe that stupid Shinji
outperformed me.
Not again!
What do you mean,
you’re going to “salvage” Shinji?
Well, theoretically, Shinji’s life
force still exists in there.
And you’ll be respecting
that life this time?
Losing Shinji is out of
the question now.
I don’t know.
What NERV wants is Unit 01
as their tool, not Shinji.
I don’t deny it.
Our assumption is that Shinji’s body
lost its Ego border and he’s floating in
the entry plug in quantum form.
You’re saying that Shinji has shifted
into a form we can’t see?
Yes, the LCL has chemically altered
into something very similar to the
sea water of primitive Earth.
You mean, like a primordial soup?
All of the substances which composed
Shinji are still preserved in the plug...
...and his soul exists there as well.
In fact, his Ego image is giving a sort
of substance to his plug suit.
In other words, this salvage operation
must both reconstruct his body
and fix his soul in it.
Is that possible?
With the MAGI’s support, yes.
This is all theoretical, isn’t it?
You won’t know what will really
happen until you do it.
What is this?
Where am I?
In the entry plug?
That’s right.  But there’s nobody here.
Not even myself.
What is this?  What is this?
What is this?
I don’t understand.
These people...
Yes, they’re people I know.
People who know me.
I understand now.  This is my world.
What is this?
This is supposed to be my world,
but this I don’t understand.
An image from outside?
A hostile image?
That’s right!  The enemy!
Enemy!  Enemy!  Enemy!  Enemy!
Our enemies are something called
Angels, they have the names
of the Angels, too.
They are the targets of
Eva and NERV.
This is our revenge for the
death of Misato’s father!
Why do I fight?
Despite all the pain and suffering?
What are you, stupid?
An unknown enemy is attacking us,
of course we have to fight them!
Am I odd to try to find
a reason to fight?
Am I not supposed to think about it?
Enemy!  Enemy!  Enemy!  Enemy!
All are my enemies!
Us...  That which threatens us
is the enemy.
Of course, how can I be faulted
for protecting my own life and
those of others?!
Enemy!  Enemy!  Enemy!  Enemy!
My enemy!  My enemy!
Damn it!  Damn it!  Damn it!
You hurt Toji and killed my mother!
Father!
Why do you hate your father?
Anyone would hate such a father!
You don’t understand him, do you?
Of course not.
I’ve hardly ever seen him.
Is that why you hate him?
Yes!  My father doesn’t need me!
My father deserted me!
And am I his substitute?
Yes!!  It must be so!!
He abandoned me because
he had Ayanami!
As if you didn’t run away
all by yourself.
Shut up!  Shut up!  Shut up!
It’s all his fault!!
That time I was actually going
to tell him I hate him!
Did you tell me to pilot this just
to make me suffer, Father?!
Correct.
That can’t be true!  It can’t be!
How can you say that?!
You don’t need me, do you?!
I called you because you had a use.
Why me?
Because there was no one
else who could.
No way, I’ve never seen this before!
It’s impossible!!
Yes, I knew it was true.
It’s true!  I knew Eva.
Then I escaped!  I really escaped!
Leaving my father and mother behind!
The concentration of LCL is
currently stable at 36%.  No problem
with oxygen concentration.
Electromagnetic radiation pulse is
normal.  Wave pattern is 0.
Counters are functioning normally.
Salvage Plan Guideline
and Procedures...
It’s amazing that you could create
all this in only one month.
Thanks for giving me credit,
but it wasn’t my idea.
This was already experimental
ten years ago.
This kind of thing happened
during the development?
It was before I worked here.
My mother was here, though.
I only know the data.
And how did it come out?
I’ve heard they failed.
Kindness...
Warmth...
Is this the warmth of a human?
I was never aware of it.
What is loneliness?
I was never aware of it,
but now I think I know it.
What is happiness?
I was never aware of it,
but now I think I know it.
Are others kind to you?
Why?
Because I am Eva’s pilot.
Because I pilot Eva,
they treat me well.
That is the reason I can exist.
That is the everything to support
my reason to be.
So, I must pilot Eva.
And then?
Enemy!
Yes, I must fight what they
all call the enemy.
And then?
And I must win!
Right, I can’t lose.
As they tell me to, I must pilot Eva.
As they tell me to, I must win!
Otherwise...
Nobody...
Do your best.
Get to work, idiot.
Good work, Shinji.
Misato, Ritsuko, Asuka,
Toji, Kensuke...
...and Father.
They all respect me.
When I pilot Eva, they all respect me.
They respect this worthless being.
Everyone says to pilot this.
I’ll prove to my dad I’m worthwhile.
Do your best.
Yes, I’m doing my best.
I am doing my best!
Somebody be nice to me.
I fought so hard.  I’m doing my best!
Treat me well!  Be nice to me!!
I’m nice to you.
Tell me, Shinji, do you want
to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It could be very, very nice.
Ask me anytime.  I’m ready.
Hey, Shinji-idiot, don’t you want
to be one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It could be very, very nice.
You ought to appreciate your
good fortune.  Come on.
Ikari, do you want to become
one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It could be very, very nice.
Ikari?
Do you want to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body and soul?
It could be very, very nice.
Relax and release your soul.
All investigative needles fixed.
Fixed at electromagnetic radius
of 0 minus 3.
Ego border pulse
connection is complete.
Roger.
Start salvage.
Roger.  Transmitting first signal.
Eva has received the signal.
No rejection confirmed.
Proceeding to second and third signals.
Subject cathexis is normal.
Destrudo is not confirmed.
Roger.  Shift the subject to stage two.
Shinji...
Hey, Shinji-idiot!
Shinji!
Hey, Shinji!
Yo, Shinji.
Ikari...
Shinji!
Shinji-idiot!
Hey, Shinji!
Yo, Shinji.
Ikari...
Shinji!
Shinji-idiot!
Hey, Shinji!
Yo, Shinji.
Ikari...
Shinji!
Shinji-idiot!
Hey, Shinji!
Yo, Shinji.
Ikari...
It’s no good.  The Ego borderline
is frozen in a loop.
Irradiate the wave patterns in
all directions.
It won’t work.  The signals are
trapped in Klein space.
What does that mean?
It means we failed.
Abort intervention!  Reverse tangent
plug!  Return additions to zero.
Yes, ma’am.
Destrudo reaction in the old area!
Pattern Sepia!
A change is confirmed on the core
pulse, too!  Plus 0.3 is confirmed!!
Maintenance of the status quo is top
priority!  Prevent backflow!
Yes, ma’am.
Plus 0.5!  0.8!  This is odd!
I can’t stop it!
What is this?!  Why?  Don’t you want
to come back, Shinji?
I don’t understand.
I...  I...
What do you wish?
Eva has rejected the signal!
LCL self-replenishment is dropping!
Pressure in the plug is increasing!
Abort all operations!  Cut the power!
It doesn’t work!  Plug is being ejected!
Shinji!
Where am I?
Inside of Eva.
Inside of Eva?
Did I pilot Eva again?  Why?
You won’t pilot the Eva anymore?
I decided I will never pilot Eva again.
But you have just piloted
Evangelion Unit 01.
Shinji, you are here because you
have piloted the Eva.
Piloting the Eva has created
your present.
You can never deny your past, Shinji,
nor can you deny the fact that you
did indeed pilot it once more.
That which is, is.  It’s true.
I just wanted to tell you that
only you can decide.
It’s your future.
I....  I...
What good is your damned science?!
It can’t even save one small life?!
Give me back my Shinji!
Give him back!!
That scent?
A human smell?
Misato?
Ayanami?
No, not them.
That’s right...
This is the smell of my mother.
Second Impact has occurred.
Will he live in this hell?
Anywhere can be heaven
if you try to live.
Because he has a life, as long
as he lives, he will have the chance
to attain happiness.
Yes, you’re right.
Mom...
Have you decided yet?
If it’s a boy, Shinji.
If it’s a girl, I’ll name the baby Rei.
Shinji...  Rei...
Mom...
Shinji!
I see, but let’s speak of what the old
psychologists called the oral stage.
Unit 01 will be restored in two days.
I see, but let’s speak of what the old
psychologists called the oral stage.
Even when given divine power,
humans still treat it as a matter of fact.
I see, but let’s speak of what the old
psychologists called the oral stage.
Even when given divine power,
humans still treat it as a matter of fact.
That’s when someone always depends
on another person, like his mother.
I can hardly agree.  Speaking of which, the
committee is considering freezing Eva.
That’s when someone always depends
on another person, like his mother.
I can hardly agree.  Speaking of which, the
committee is considering freezing Eva.
I know a lot of guys like that, and from
your letter, you’re just like them.
The Evangelion android...
I know a lot of guys like that, and from
your letter, you’re just like them.
The Evangelion android...
I feel sorry for your girlfriend.  She
can’t be your mate and your mother.
It may be man-made, but who knows
what lurks inside that black box?
I feel sorry for your girlfriend.  She
can’t be your mate and your mother.
Well, I’m just glad Shinji was saved.
Maybe your sister, too?  You’re just
taking advantage of her, aren’t you?
That wasn’t me.  It was you, probably.
Maybe your sister, too?  You’re just
taking advantage of her, aren’t you?
That wasn’t me.  It was you, probably.
Well, maybe that’s mean.  Girls are
very sensitive to how they’re loved.
Why don’t we go to a bar tonight?
Well, maybe that’s mean.  Girls are
very sensitive to how they’re loved.
Why don’t we go to a bar tonight?
So she’s already aware that you
want her as your mother.
Sorry, I’ve got to
go somewhere tonight.
So she’s already aware that you
want her as your mother.
I see.
So she’s already aware that you
want her as your mother.
I see.
See ya!
Seeing her man as soon
as Shinji is saved?
Well, I can’t criticize her.
Ritsuko must be thinking
I’m pretty disgusting.
Appearing to give in to our sexual
desires makes for a more realistic
and human appearance.
We might even fool them.
Fool the intelligence department?
Or the Commander and Ritsuko?
Or me?
No, I meant myself.
You want to fool the others?
You never show interest in others,
but you want their attention.
You really are just like my dad.
A cigarette?
I didn’t know you still smoke.
I only smoke after this sort of thing.
So nobody knows but you.
I see, I’m honored.
And how’s Instrumentality going?
Adam could wipe out mankind.
Why is it being kept there?
Did you come to see me
just to learn that?
Well, that’s one of the reasons.
It would be my honor to be used as
my lady’s cat’s-paw, but I can’t
tell you right now.
I just want you to know what I want.
What are NERV and Commander Ikari
really planning?
I’d like to know that myself.
Hey, you can’t dodge my
questions by doing that.
Hey, no!
Don’t put strange things in there!
I can’t believe this.  What?
Here’s a present for you,
the first time in eight years.
And maybe the last as well.
2015 AD
Vice-Commander Fuyutsuki is
abducted by SEELE!  It’s a mind warp
as the memories are pulled from his mind!
1999 AD
Kyoto
2000 AD
The South Pole
Second Impact
Encounters, separation,
and lonely deaths...
2001 AD
2002 AD
The beginning of everything,
starting in Kyoto, 1999.
2003 AD
Hakone
2005 AD
Nagano Prefecture
Tokyo-2
The memories form the present as
others delve into the organization Ikari
and Fuyutsuki have created...
2004 AD
Hakone
2nd Underground
Experimental
Station
2008 AD
...into the history of the secret
organization that they have devoted
everything to.
Inside Geo-Front
Headquarters
2010 AD
Could NERV really be a fortress
for all mankind?
S.C. MAGI
SYSTEM
COMPLETED
AND—
It’s the next episode,
“The Birth of NERV.”
2015 AD
AGAIN
Next Episode:
The Birth of
NERV