Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Lucky!
I’m so lucky that I can go
shopping with you today, Kaji!
What the?!  Isn’t this the
swimsuit section?
Please allow us to announce a
call for a customer.
What the?!  Isn’t this the
swimsuit section?
Please allow us to announce a
call for a customer.
Hey!  Hey!  How do you like this?
Mr. Yamazaki from Ibaragi City,
your friend is waiting for you.
Hey!  Hey!  How do you like this?
Mr. Yamazaki from Ibaragi City,
your friend is waiting for you.
Slow down, school girl.  You’re a little
young for something like that.
Please come to Customer Service
on the first floor.
You’re just being an old
fuddy-duddy, Mr. Kaji.
Please come to Customer Service
on the first floor.
This is what’s in fashion these days.
Oh, really?
I’m so anxious about this school trip.
I just know we’ll have a great time.
And where are you going for the trip?
O-ki-na-wa.
We’re even scheduled to go
scuba diving!
Scuba diving...
It’s been three years since
I’ve gone diving.
Say, where did you go for
your school trip?
Well, we didn’t have one.
Why not?
Because of the Second Impact.
Episode 10:
MAGMA DIVER
Whaaaat?!
I can’t go on the trip?!
Right.
Why not?!
Because you’re on standby
for combat duty.
You never told me anything about that!
I just told you.
Who in the hell decided that?!!
Me, the Operations Planning Manager.
Hey, you!  Why don’t you stop slurping
that tea and say something to her?
Be a man!
Actually, I kind of anticipated it
would be like this.
And you’ve already given up?
Talk about pathetic.  There’s nothing
more useless than a housebroken male.
Please don’t talk about me like that.
I know how you must feel...
...but there’s no other way.
There’s always the possibility that an
Angel may attack while you’re away.
It’s always “standby”!
Standby, standby, standby!
We’ve always got to be ready to
defend against an enemy who may
or may not be coming!
Why don’t you try to find out where
they are and attack them first?!
If we could do that we’d
have already done it.
Look, think of this as an opportunity
to catch up.
While the rest of your class
is on the trip...
...the two of you can study.
Or do you think I don’t know
about these?
If you thought I wouldn’t know about
your test scores unless you told me...
...you made a big mistake.  Finding out
what your grades are...
...is quite simple for me.
It’s ridiculous.  This school’s grades
are meaningless!
The old-fashioned numeric grading
scale system you use on your
exams means nothing to me.
When in Rome, do as the Romans do.
You could at least try to adjust to
Japanese school life.
Noooooooo way!
Asuka, I’ll bring you some souvenirs!
Well, it’s just too bad for you guys!
Don’t feel bad, I’ll have enough
fun for both of you!
Post the survey data on Mt. Asama
from Balthasar to Melchior
as soon as possible.
A school trip?
That’s pretty casual behavior for
times like these.
Well, it’s because the times are so
hard that they want to have a little
fun while they can.
What are you up to?
Studying physics.
You’re such an obedient
student, Mr. Big Shot.
Well, I’d have to anyway.
Ta-da!
Since I can’t go scuba diving in
Okinawa, I’m going to do it here!
Really?
What’re you working on?
Lemme see.
You can’t solve an easy
problem like this?
There!  Here you go!
It’s so easy.
How can you solve a difficult problem
like this and not make good grades
on your tests?
Because I couldn’t figure out
what the questions said.
You mean you couldn’t read the
questions in Japanese?
Right, I haven’t learned all
of the Kanji yet.
I didn’t have to study it in college.
College?
Yeah, I graduated last year.
What does this one say?
It’s about thermal expansion.
Thermal expansion?  Kid stuff.
To put it simply, things expand when
they get hot and shrink when
they get cold.
Well, it sounds easy enough in theory...
So, if I were to warm up my bust, do
you think they’d grow bigger?
How would I know such a thing?!
You’re such a boring little boy.
Looky, looky, Shinji!
Back Roll Entry!
This just isn’t clear enough.
But the report from the Mt. Asama
Earthquake Research Lab
would indicate...
...that we should take a closer look
at this shadow.
Of course, we can’t ignore this.
What’s MAGI’s judgment?
Fifty-fifty.
Is someone there yet?
Captain Katsuragi’s already on site.
You’ve gone too deep.
Not yet, descend another 500, please.
Depth 1200.  The pressure resistant
partition is cracking.
Ms. Katsuragi!!
If it breaks, we’ll pay for the damage.
200 more, please.
We’re monitoring a reaction!!
Begin analysis!
Right!
The probe has imploded due to
the extreme pressure.
Did you get a result?
Just barely.
The pattern is blue.
Then there’s no doubt.
It’s an Angel.
From this point forward, this laboratory
will be completely sealed off.
It’s under NERV’s jurisdiction now!
Any and all access to the outside
world is prohibited.
All records pertaining to the events of
the past six hours are classified.
I need an A-17 from Commander Ikari,
top priority!
Watch what you’re saying.
This is an open line.
I know.
Switch me to a scrambled line.
A-17?!
An offensive attack?
Correct.
Unacceptable, it’s too dangerous!
Have you forgotten what happened
fifteen years ago?
This is our chance to move from a
perpetually defensive posture to
an offensive one.
The risk is enormous.
However, I’m sure you’re aware how
important it is to obtain a living Angel
as a sample, aren’t you?
We will not tolerate failure.
Failure?
If we fail, it will result in the extinction
of the entire human race.
Are you really going to do it?
This is an Angel?
Yes, it’s something like a chrysalis
prior to reaching the adult stage.
This operation’s prime objective is to
capture this Angel.
We must capture it alive and in
a form as close to its original
state as possible.
And if we fail?
Then you must destroy it immediately.
Do you understand?
Roger!
The designated pilot for the
actual operation is...
Hey, let me!  I dive!
I know it’s going to be me.
...Asuka!
You will carry out the mission
using Unit 02.
Sure!  It’ll be easy.
And me?
The special equipment we’ll be using
isn’t standardized for use on
the Unit 00 prototype.
Rei and Unit 00 will remain at
headquarters on standby.
Yes.
Oh, too bad.
You don’t get to go to the hot springs.
Now that an A-17 has been ordered,
we must scramble immediately.
Get ready.
Roger!
This heat-resistant plug suit doesn’t
seem any different from our
regular ones.
Press the switch on your right wrist.
Oh, no!
What is this?
Unit 02 is also ready.
No!
I don’t believe this!
That suit’s designed to protect you from
heat, pressure and nuclear radiation.
This is Type-D equipment, for combat
under extreme environmental duress.
Is that my Unit 02?
No way!  I quit!!
I don’t want to appear in public
in this dorky outfit!
This is the sort of thing Shinji’s for!
I’m so disappointed.
I was anticipating seeing Asuka’s
gallant figure!
No!
I can’t let Mr. Kaji see me in
this awful looking thing.
We’re having problems?
Well, yes.
Excuse me, but I can.
I’ll go in Unit 02.
No, I don’t want you touching
my Unit 02!
I’d rather do it than let her
take my place.
I’m sorry about the look.
Please, forgive me.
Eva Units 01 and 02 have arrived.
Have both units stand by in position.
Move in the laser bore and
ready the crane.
Roger.
Hey, isn’t Kaji here yet?
That male buffoon won’t be coming.
He’s got no business here.
Oh, damn!  I wanted him to
see how great I am.
An A-17 has been ordered.
That includes the freeze of
all current assets.
I assume that means that some people
will be getting into a bit of trouble.
Why didn’t you stop them?
I had no excuse for stopping it.
This order is an official one.
But, surely you must know that if NERV
fails, the whole world will perish.
They’re not that arrogant.
What are... those?
The UN and the Air Force will be
on standby alert...
...until this mission has been completed.
Will they help us?
No, they’re here to clean up...
...in case we fail.
What do you mean?
They will employ N2 depth charges
to destroy the Angel and us with it.
That’s dreadful!
Who would order something like that?
Commander Ikari.
Laser operation, complete.
The bore path has been secured.
The Type D equipment is
functioning normally.
Unit 02 is in position to dispatch.
Roger.
Asuka, are you ready?
Anytime you are.
Launch.
It looks hot!
Unit 02 is entering the lava.
Look at this, Shinji!
Giant Stroke Entry!
Current depth: 170.
Speed of descent: 20.
No problems detected.
Visibility is zero.
I can’t see a thing.
Switching to CT monitor.
Even with this, the range of clarity is
no more than 120.
Depth is 400...
450...
500...
550...
600...
650...
900...
950...
1000...
1020...
We’re over the maximum safety depth.
Depth is 1300.
Unit 02 has reached estimated
target level.
Asuka?
Can you see anything?
No reactions detected.  It’s not here.
The lava circulation is faster
than we thought.
The target’s velocity doesn’t
match our predictions.
Hurry up and recalculate.
Continue the operation.
Maintain descent.
Depth is 1350.
1400...
A crack has occurred on the
second coolant pipe.
Depth is 1480.
We have exceeded the maximum
allowed depth.
It hasn’t made contact with
the target, yet.
Go on.
How’s it going, Asuka?
I’m okay.  I just want to finish this and
take a shower, as soon as possible.
There’s a nice hot spring near here.
We’ll hit it once this is finished.
Just hang in there a little longer.
Maximum allowed depth plus 120.
Eva Unit 02 has lost its
progressive knife.
Maximum allowed depth plus 200.
Captain Katsuragi, we’ve got to stop!
Have you forgotten that there’s a
human being in there?
I am in charge of this operation.
Proceed, please.
Misato’s right.
I’m okay.  I can go on.
Depth 1780.
Unit 02 has reached the corrected
target depth.
There it is!
Target in sight.
Prepare to capture.
All right, due to the motion of the
convection current moving you
and the target...
...you’ll have just one chance
to make contact.
I know.  Just leave it to me.
30 to contact.
Relative velocity 2.2.  On the axis.
The electromagnetic cage has been
spread.  No problems detected.
The target has been captured.
Nice, Asuka.
Operation completed.
I’m coming up now.
Are you all right, Asuka?
Who do you think you’re talking to?
Fear is often worse than danger itself.
It was an easy assignment.
Boy, this isn’t a plug suit.
It’s a sauna suit!
I wanna take a bath.
The tension let loose all at once.
Yeah?
You were scared about this operation
too, weren’t you?
Well, yeah.  Because if it’d gone wrong,
it could’ve caused another disaster.
Right, Second Impact.
Nobody would want to
repeat that again.
What’s going on?!
Oh, no!  It’s started to hatch!
It’s much earlier than we predicted!
Status of the cage?!
There’s no way it can withstand this!
Abort the capture!  Jettison the cage!
We’re changing the operation!
Destroying the Angel is
now top priority!
Unit 02, withdraw and
prepare for combat!
This is what I’ve waited for!
Damn it!  I forgot I dropped the knife!
It’s right in front of me!
Releasing ballast!!
It’s fast!
This is no good.  I’ve lost it.
In addition to that, I’ve got lousy
visibility, I’m too hot...
...and this disgusting suit’s stuck to my
body with sweat.
This really sucks.
Asuka!
We’ll drop you Unit 01’s knife.
Catch it!
Roger!
Oh, no!!
Have you dropped it, Shinji?
Contact with knife, 40 seconds.
The Angel is approaching rapidly!
No!  Go away!
Hurry up!  Come on!
What the hell?!?
Unbelievable!  How can it open its
mouth in such an environment?
Its construction must be incredible!
The left leg is damaged!
The heat shields!!
Damn you!!
If this thing can withstand such a
high-heat, high-pressure environment...
...then the progressive knife will
be useless against it!
Then what’s the solution?
I know!!
Like the one earlier!!
Eat this!!
I understand!  Thermal expansion!!
Transfer all coolant pressure to
cable three!!  Hurry!!
I’ve done it but...
Is this the end?  Looks like that’s that.
Shinji?
Idiot!  What a show off!
Hello?
Are the NERV personnel here?
Yes!
I need your signature here.
Thanks so much.
From Mr. Kaji?
What is this?
The bath’s over there, to the left.
This feels like heaven.
I never thought a bath could
feel this good.
Shinji, can you hear me?
Y...yes, ma’am!
Would you throw me the
body shampoo?
We ran out of ours.
Sure.
Here it comes.
Roger.
Ouch!
You idiot!  You dork, watch where
you’re throwing!
S...sorry.
He hit me in my most essential part!
Let me take a look.
Wow, your skin is so soft
and smooth, Asuka!
Don’t!  You’re tickling me!
How about right here?
Wow!  Don’t touch that!
Come on, what gives?
It expanded...
...how embarrassing.
Oh, this?  I got this in
the Second Impact.
You know all about my past, don’t you?
Well, yeah.  It’s a part of my job.
It’s all ancient history now.
We should just forget.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
The Angels aren’t Commander Ikari’s
only enemies.
When those who are displeased with
NERV cut off Tokyo-3’s power supply...
...an Angel arrives at NERV
Headquarters to find it
completely locked up...
...with no modernized
facilities operational.
Can three kids wandering through the
underground labyrinth...
...make it to headquarters in time to
intercept the Angel?
It’s the next episode,
“In the Still Darkness.”
You can expect more service
next time too!
Next Episode:
In the Still
Darkness