Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
In the year 2015 AD
As of 12:30 PM today, a special state
of emergency has been declared...
...for the Kanto and Chubu regions
surrounding the Tokai district.
All residents must evacuate to their
designated shelters immediately.
Repeat: As of 12:30 PM today...
All Rail Line Operations Canceled
...the Kanto and Chubu regions
surrounding the Tokai district...
...have been declared to be under
a state of emergency.
All residents must evacuate to their
designated shelters immediately.
Why did I have to lose him now?
All residents must evacuate to their
designated shelters immediately.
Why did I have to lose him now?
Christ, why at a time like this?
SHINJI IKARI
Due to the special emergency...
...all lines are currently unavailable.
It’s no use...
I shouldn’t have come here after all.
Shinji, I’ll come and pick you up.
PS: Look at this!!
Well, I guess we won’t be meeting here.
I’ll have to go to a shelter.
PROJECTED
COURSE
The unidentified object is
coming towards us.
We’ve got it on visual.  I’m
putting it on the main screen.
It’s been fifteen years, hasn’t it?
Yes.  Well, now we’re sure.
It’s the Angels.
Episode 1:
Angel Attack
Every missile hit the target!
I’m sorry!  Were you waiting long?
The target is still operational!  It’s still
heading towards Tokyo-3!
The Air Defense Force doesn’t have the
firepower to stop it!
Hit it with everything we’ve got!
Mobilize all the units from Atsugi...
...and scramble the squadrons
from Iruma as well!
Forget about the budget!
Destroy the target at any cost!
Why?!  That was a direct hit!
The tank battalion’s been annihilated.
Guided missiles and artillery
have no effect either.
Damn it!  We gave it everything we’ve
got and we’re not even touching it!
Is it protected by an AT Field?
Yes.  Conventional weapons are
no match for the Angels.
Yes sir, I understand.  We’ll execute
the plan at once.
Hey, wait a second...
They’re going to use an N2 mine?
Get down!!
We did it!!
Sorry, but it looks like you won’t
be getting a shot at it.
Shock wave approaching.
Are you all right?
Yeah... but my mouth is full of dirt.
That’s okay.  Now then... let’s go!
Push!
There...
Thanks for the hand.  I really
appreciate it.
Thank you too, Miss Katsuragi.
Just Misato is fine.
I’m glad we’ve met at last, Shinji Ikari.
Yeah...
What’s the target’s status?
We’re unable to confirm due to all the
EMP interference.
It must have been finished.  You saw
the size of that explosion.
Sensors restored.
We’ve got an energy reading at the
explosion’s epicenter!
It can’t be!
Visual display restored.
That was our last resort...
No effect, I can’t believe it!
It’s a goddamned demon!
Yes.  Don’t worry about it.
His safety is my top priority, so could
you get a car train ready for us?
The express one.
Right.
Well, I volunteered to pick him
up, so it’s my duty to make sure
he gets there.  See ya!
Damn it!  I just had my car restored
and it’s a total wreck already!
33 more loan payments to go,
plus the cost of repairs...
And look!  My only decent
dress has been ruined!
Um, Miss Misato...
And I was looking and feeling so nice...
Excuse me... Misato?
Huh?  What?
Are you sure you can just take those?
Never mind about that.
It’s an emergency, and we need a
working car right now, right?
And I am a government official, after
all, so everything’s going to be
perfectly fine, okay?
I don’t think anyone will buy that.
Don’t get so snotty.  You’re not as
cute as I thought you were.
You think so?
Oh, did I upset you?
Sorry, sorry!  You’re just a kid, after all.
So are you.  You’re not as mature
as I thought you were.
Entrance
As we predicted, it’s regenerating itself.
If it couldn’t, it wouldn’t be a practical
autonomous invasion weapon.
Impressive.  It appears it can even
upgrade its own operational functions.
And it’s also getting smarter.
It will renew its assault any minute now.
The gates are now closing.
Please stand clear.
The special agency NERV?
The gates are now closing.
Please stand clear.
Yes, it’s a secret organization under...
The gates are now closing.
Please stand clear.
Yes, it’s a secret organization under...
This is a B-22 Special Express
departing for G33-1
...the control of the United Nations!
This is a B-22 Special Express
departing for G33-1
And that’s where my father is, right?
This is a B-22 Special Express
departing for G33-1
Well... yeah.
This is a B-22 Special Express
departing for G33-1
Do you know what he does?
This is a B-22 Special Express
departing for G33-1
This train will bypass all other
stations.  Please stand back.
My teachers told me that it was
important to the safety of
the human race.
From this point forward, command of
this operation will be entrusted to you.
Show us that you’re capable.
Yes sir.
Mr. Ikari, we must admit that our
weapons have no effect on the target.
But are you sure you can
beat these things?
It’s what NERV was created for.
We’re all praying that you’re correct.
The target is still stationary.
Our current ability to intercept
is only 7.5%.
Even the UN forces are exhausted.
What are you going to do?
I intend to activate Unit 01.
Unit 01?  But we have no pilot.
That’s not a problem.  Another spare
will be delivered soon.
Are you taking me to my father?
Yes.  Yes, I think so.
Father...
Oh, yes...  Didn’t you get an
ID card from your dad?
Yes.
This is it.
Thanks.
TO: SHINJI IKARI
Come!  GENDO IKARI
Here, read this.
Welcome to NERV
NERV...
My father’s agency...
Am I going to work for him?
Of course.  He wouldn’t have sent
me a letter unless he needed
me for something.
Hmm, it looks like you don’t get
along with your dad.
It’s the same with me.
Awesome!
It’s a real Geo-Front!
That’s right.
This is our secret base.
NERV Headquarters.
This is the key to rebuilding our world...
...a fortress for all mankind.
What on earth?  Isn’t this
the right way?
NERV Headquarters
Central Dogma 1320
Bathrooms HERE!
Central Dogma’s closed
passages remain sealed.
It’s because of these things that I hate
to wear a skirt around here.
Central Dogma’s closed
passages remain sealed.
It’s because of these things that I hate
to wear a skirt around here.
Opening block B-26 in sequence.
And where in the heck is Ritsuko?
I’m sorry.  I’m just not used
to this place yet.
We passed this spot just a
little while ago.
Don’t worry about it.  And anyway,
they make these systems to be
used, you know.
Would the chairperson of Project E,
Technical Department Division 1,
Dr. Ritsuko Akagi, Dr. Ritsuko Akagi...
...please contact Captain Misato
Katsuragi of Operations,
Division 1, immediately.
I don’t believe it.
Has she gotten lost again?
Uh, hiya, Ritsuko...
Why are you wasting my time,
Captain Katsuragi?
Aren’t you aware that we’re short on
both time and manpower?
Sorry!
Is this the boy?
Right.  According to the Marduk
Report, he’s the “Third Child.”
I’m glad to meet you.
What?  Uh... sure.
He’s just like his dad... the
unfriendly part, that is.
Handle the rest of this.
Their first meeting in over three years...
Vice-Commander, the target has
started moving again.
Right.  Assume
battle stations, level one.
Repeat.  Battle stations, level one.
Prepare for ground-unit interception.
Here we go.
It sounds pretty serious.
So, how’s Unit 01 doing?
It’s currently undergoing refrigeration,
using the B-type equipment.
Does it really work?  It’s never
worked before, has it?
The possibility of activation is
0.000000001%.
We call it, pathetically
enough, the O-9 System.
Does that mean it doesn’t work?
Oh, don’t be insulting.
It’s “O,” not “zero.”
Well, it’s just a number.  Anyway, it’s
a bit too late to be saying
“Sorry, it didn’t work.”
Huh?  It’s so dark.
A face?  A giant robot?
You won’t find this in the manual.
This is man’s ultimate-humanoid
fighting machine...
...the first model of the synthetic life
form Evangelion, Unit 01.
Built here in secret, it is
mankind’s last hope.
Is this part of what my
father’s been doing?
Correct.
It’s been a while.
Father...
We’re moving out!
Moving out?!  Unit 00’s
still in cryostasis, isn’t it?
Wait a second... You’re going
to use Unit 01?
There’s no other way.
Now wait... Rei can’t do it yet, can she?
We’ve got no pilot!
One’s just been delivered.
Are you serious?
Shinji Ikari...
Yes?
You will pilot it.
But... even Rei Ayanami took seven
months to synchronize with her Eva.
It’s impossible for him to do it!
He just got here!
He just has to sit in the seat.  We
don’t expect more than that.
But...
Repelling that Angel is
our ultimate priority.
If putting someone who has a chance of
synchronizing into an Eva unit...
...gives us even the slightest chance,
then we have to do it.
You do understand that, don’t
you, Captain Katsuragi?
I suppose...
Father, why did you send for me?
You know exactly why.
So, you’re asking me to take this thing
and go out there and fight?
Precisely.
No way!  How can you do
something like this to me?
I knew you didn’t want me!
I called you because I have
a need for you.
Why me?
Because no one else can.
No, I can’t...  I’ve never even seen
anything like this before!  I can’t do this!
You will be instructed.
But... there’s no way!
I can’t pilot it!
If you’re going to pilot it, do it now
and quickly.  If not... leave!
It must have detected our location.
Shinji, we don’t have any time.
Get into it.
No!  I didn’t come for this!
This is all wrong!
Shinji...  Just why did you come here?
You must confront your father and
you must confront yourself.
I know it!  But I just can’t!
Fuyutsuki...
Wake up Rei.
Can we use her?
She isn’t dead.
I understand.
Rei.
Yes?
Our spare is unusable.
You will do it again.
Yes sir.
Reconfigure Unit 01’s system to
Rei, then reactivate!
Roger.  Call off the present work,
and begin reactivation.
I knew it.  I’m not needed after all.
Watch out!
The Eva moved!
How could it?!
It broke off the right arm-restraint!
No, that’s impossible!
It didn’t have an entry plug inserted!
It’s not possible!
It reacted without any interface...?
Or... was it protecting something?
It protected him?
We can do it.
I mustn’t run away.  I mustn’t run away.
I MUSTN’T RUN AWAY!
Let me do it.
I’ll pilot it.
Cooling process, completed.
Right arm repairs, completed.
Cage now in position for docking.
Signal plug terminator has been ejected.
Roger.  Inserting entry plug.
Plug fixed in place.
Connecting Unit 01.
Filling the entry plug.
W...what is this stuff?
Don’t worry.  Once your lungs are
filled with LCL, your blood will
be oxygenated directly.
You’ll get used to it.
I feel nauseous.
Stop whining!  You’re a
boy, aren’t you?!
Connecting main power.
All circuits transmitting power.
Roger.
Connecting secondary contacts.
A-10 nerve connection, normal.
Configure the language logic
interface for Japanese.
All preliminary contacts established.
Performance nominal.
Bidirectional circuits are open.
Synchronization ratio at 41.3%.
Amazing.
Harmonics are all normal.  No
disturbances identified.
We can do it.
Prepare to launch!
Disengage primary lockbolts!
Disengage confirmed.  Disengaging
the umbilical bridge.
Disengage secondary lockbolts.
Disengage primary restraints.
Disengage secondary restraints.
Release safety locks
numbers 1 through 15.
Internal batteries fully charged.
External battery outlet, normal.
Roger.  Move Eva Unit 01
to the ejector pad.
Launch path is clear.
All systems green.
Ready for launch.
Roger.
Can we really do this?
Of course.
Unless we defeat the Angels, we
have no future.
Ikari, are you sure about this?
Launch!
Shinji... don’t get killed out there.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Eva triumphs over the Angel!
However, this is just the beginning.
Misato decides to save Shinji, who ran
away from his father’s place...
...insisting that he not be left alone.
But that was simply arrogance.
That night, Shinji closes his mind.
Next episode: “Unfamiliar Ceiling.”
I’ll make you a bargain
next time, too.
Next Episode:
Unfamiliar Ceiling