Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
NERV Headquarters
Experimental Station 2
22 days ago...
Commence activation.
Connecting main power to all circuits.
Power supply connected.
Commencing activation system.
Activation voltage is approaching
critical level...  0.5... 0.2...
Rising...
Begin the second phase of the
activation system.
Pilot has begun linkup.
Start system phase 2.
Synapses inserted.
Junctions connecting.
Transmitting pulse.
All circuits are operational.
No problems with initial contact.
Power supplied to brachial muscles
in both the right and left arms.
All nerve links checking out normal.
Checklist satisfactory up to 2550.
Prepare for third stage connection.
Clear up to 2580.
Counting down to
the absolute borderline...
0.9...
0.7...
0.5...
0.4...
0.3...
The pulses are flowing backward!
Something’s going wrong in
the third stage!
Rejection occurring in the
nerve center elements!
Cease contact!  Break all circuits
through number 6!
Negative!
The signal’s not being received!
Unit 00 is out of control!
Abort the experiment.  Shut off
the power supply.
Yes, sir!
Unit 00 has switched to standby power!
35 seconds until it comes to
a complete stop.
It’s dangerous!  Stay back!
Auto ejection system activating!
Damn it!
Complete shutdown in 10 seconds... 9...
Use the special Bakelite!  Hurry!
8...
7...
Rei...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Zero!
Rei, are you all right?
Rei!
I see.
Episode 5:
Rei, Beyond
Her Heart
Rei Ayanami, age 14.
The first of the test subjects chosen in
accordance with the Marduk Report.
The First Child.
She is the designated pilot
for Evangelion Unit 00.
Her past has been eradicated.  All of
her personal records have been erased.
So, what was the cause of that accident
during the last experiment?
We still don’t know...
However, we believe that mental
instability on the part of the pilot
was a primary cause.
Mental instability?  In Rei?
Yes...  Her mind became more
disturbed than we had anticipated.
So, what did happen?
I don’t know...
But she could have...
Did something occur to you?
No, that can’t be...
The demolition of block B-3
has been completed.
All technical department personnel
are to submit their data to the
analysis group.
So, this is our enemy...
I see.  Everything except the core
has been left intact.  This is a
perfect sample.
Thank you, this will help us a lot.
So, did you find anything new?
What the heck is this?
That’s the code number for
“cannot be analyzed.”
You mean, you don’t know what this is?
Correct.  What we do know is that
the Angel is composed of...
...a type of matter characterized
by both particulate and wave form
properties, not unlike solidified light.
But you’ve at least found its power
source, haven’t you?
Something like that, anyway.
But we haven’t been able to figure out
any of its operating principles.
So, we’ve finally found something
completely outside our experience.
The world is filled with mysteries.
For example, take a look at this.
This is the Angel’s inherent
wave pattern.
What?  Let me see...
Could it be...?
Yes.
Although they are composed of a
different form of matter, their
actual composition...
...in terms of the arrangement and
coordinates of the pattern, fall within
a 99.89% match of a human being.
Unbelievable... 99.89%...
Once again, we must acknowledge
how limited our level of
understanding is.
Bring it down... slowly...
Once again, we must acknowledge
how limited our level of
understanding is.
Okay!
Once again, we must acknowledge
how limited our level of
understanding is.
Okay!
Keep it going... stop.
This is the core?
How’s the rest of it?
It’s pretty deteriorated.  We can’t
expect to use it as a reference.
That’s not a problem.  Dispose of
the remnants.
Yes, sir.
What’s wrong?
Well, um...  nothing’s wrong...
You know, are you aware that when
you say “nothing” that way...
...it’s the same as asking others to pay
attention to you?
Well... it’s just that my father seems to
have burned his hands...
Burned?
I was just wondering how it happened...
Burns...?  Do you know
anything about them?
It was before you arrived
here at NERV.
Unit 00 went berserk during the
activation experiments.  You’ve
heard about that, right?
Yes...
The pilot was trapped inside it...
Ayanami was the pilot, wasn’t she?
It was Commander Ikari who rescued
her.  He opened the super-heated hatch
with his bare hands.
My father did that...
That’s how he burned his hands.
Go Hideko!
You lose!!
You’ve got to treat us to pizza
if you lose!!
There, go on!
You won’t make it!
Now, let’s sink a shot!
Oh my gosh!  Those guys are
looking at us!
Pervert!
Man, they’ve all got such
incredible breasts...
Suzuhara’s ogling us!  Gross!
Hi, Shinji!!
Hey, Big Shot!
What’re you looking at so intently?
Uh... Nothing!
I think you’re looking
at Ayanami!  Right?
No.
Oh, come on, dude.  Am I stupid?
Ayanami’s boobs...
Ayanami’s thighs...
Ayanami’s...
...calves!
I told you, it’s nothing like that.
Then what were you looking at?
You can’t fool me.
I was just wondering why
she’s always alone.
Uh... come to think of it, she hasn’t had
any friends since she started here in
the 7th grade.
There’s just something about her
that makes her hard to talk to.
She’s probably just got a
lousy personality.
You two are both Eva pilots, right?  You
ought to know her better than any of us.
He’s right.
Well, I’ve hardly spoken to her.
Eva Unit 01 is now entering the third
stage cooling process.  Lower all
systems to phase 3 in Cage 6.
The earlier harmonics and
synchronization tests were all good.
All numerical conditions
have been satisfied.
Roger.  Transmit the result to Balthasar.
Roger.
Transmit the full range of the entry
plug’s personal data to Melchior.
Data transmitting.
This is Melchior, roger.
Circuits connected.
Initiating third stage cooling process.
CBL Circulation has begun.
Vent liquid wastes to the
second purification system.
The protein walls are in good
condition.  No problems detected.
T-minus 1,050 minutes until the
Unit 00 reactivation experiment.
What is this?!!
It’s curry.
So, you’re still eating this instant stuff.
Look, you’re a guest so you’ve got
no right to complain.
Here Misato...
Oh, here.
Here, put all of that into this.
Are you serious?
Oh, don’t you know how good this is?
Okay...
Ordinary curry flavored instant
ramen can’t be this good.  Yeah.
Let’s eat!
The trick is to put less hot
water in the soup.
You cooked this, didn’t you Misato?
Good gosh...
Oh, can you tell?
Yes, by its taste.
How can she make something that’s
ready-to-eat so awful?
Next time, invite me when
it’s Shinji’s turn.
Shinji, you really ought to move.  You
shouldn’t let one bad roommate
ruin your life.
I’m used to it now.
He’s right, Ritsuko.
Never underestimate the ability of
the human animal to adapt to
its environment.
And anyway, if he does move...
Shinji, why don’t you bring me
another one, please.
Right.
He’s going to have to go through a lot
of trouble and red tape.  He just got
his permanent security card, you know.
Oh, I almost forgot!
Shinji, would you do me a favor?
What is it?
Rei Ayanami’s renewal card.
I keep forgetting to give this to her.
Would you mind delivering this to her
before you go in to headquarters?
Sure.
What’s the matter?  You’re staring
at Rei’s picture, aren’t you?
No...
Oh, I think you are, Shinji.
No!
Oh, come on!  You’re embarrassed,
aren’t you?
Well, you’ve got an official excuse
to go to Rei’s place now.
That’s a great chance, don’t you think?
Stop teasing me!
But I love teasing you.
You always go ballistic!
Just like Misato.
I just find it strange that I know so little
about Ayanami, even though
we’re both Eva pilots.
She’s a very nice girl, but she’s like
your father.  She’s not very adept at...
Not adept at what?
Living.
Excuse me?
Excuse me, it’s Shinji Ikari.
I’m coming in, Miss Ayanami!
Are these hers?
Um... well...
I didn’t mean...
Will you get off?
Uh... I...
What?
Well, I mean... I was...
I... I was asked to, so...
What was it... the card, your card...
It’s been renewed...
So, I was asked to deliver it...
I didn’t mean for any of
this to happen...
Ritsuko said she forgot to
give it to you...
It’s true.  I rang your bell, but there
was no reply... and the door was
unlocked... so...
Central Dogma is currently open
to the public.
Group 3 should proceed directly
to the fourth gate.
This is your new card.  Ritsuko told
me to deliver this to you.
I’m sorry...
About what?
Um, aren’t you going to have a
reactivation experiment today?
Say, aren’t you scared?
Aren’t you... afraid of
piloting... Unit 00?
Why?
Well, I heard that you were hurt pretty
bad in an earlier experiment,
so I thought you might be...
Aren’t you Commander Ikari’s son?
Yeah.
Don’t you have faith in your
own father’s work?
Of course not.  How could I trust him...
What?
Rei, are you all right?
Rei...
The pilot was trapped inside it.
It was Commander Ikari
who rescued her.
He opened the super-heated hatch
with his bare hands.
That’s how he burned his hands.
Rei...
Can you hear me?
Yes.
We shall now commence the Unit 00
reactivation experiment.
Commence first connection.
Connecting main power supply.
Activation voltage has passed
the critical point.
Roger.
Shift format to Phase 2.
Connecting pilot to Unit 00.
Open circuits.
Pulse and harmonics are normal.
No problems detected.
In synch.  All links completed.
Central Nerve System elements
are nominal.
Recalculating, no error corrections.
Checklist is satisfactory up to 2590.
Approaching the critical mark...
2.5 more...
1.7...
1.2...
1.0...
0.8...
0.6...
0.5...
0.4...
0.3...
0.2...
0.1 and rising...
Borderline cleared.
Unit 00 has been activated.
Roger.
Beginning interlock test.
Ikari, an unidentified object is
approaching.  It may be the Fifth Angel.
Stop the test.  Go to first stage alert.
You’re not going to use Unit 00?
She’s not ready to fight yet.  What’s
the status on Unit 01?
It’ll be ready in 380 seconds.
Engage!
Yes, sir.
Rei.
Reactivation has been successfully
completed.  Return now.
The target is passing over Tonosawa.
Unit 01 is beginning launch
preparation.
Releasing primary lockbolts.
Release confirmed.
Roger.
Removing secondary restraints.
The target is now intruding into
Lake Ashino airspace.
Eva Unit 01 is ready for launch.
Launch!!
We’re detecting a high energy
reaction from inside the target!
What?!
It’s accelerating and massing
upon itself!
Is it possible...?
No, dodge it!!
Shinji!!
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Shinji is saved, but after being
injured, he deteriorates badly.
Rei is forced to kick off of him in
the heat of battle!
Meanwhile, Misato desperately tries to
pinpoint the Angel’s weak spot with
the ultimate in heavy artillery.
Will Shinji’s prayers and all of the
energy in Japan be enough to penetrate
the Angel’s shields?
Unit 00 is fused by the molten impact!
It’s the next episode,
“Showdown In Tokyo-3”!
Next Episode:
Showdown
In Tokyo-3