Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
We’re detecting a high energy reaction
from inside the target!
What?!
It’s accelerating and massing
upon itself!
Is it possible?
No, dodge it!!
Retrieve him, hurry!!
The target has gone silent!
How’s Shinji?
He’s alive!
Unit 01 has been recovered.
Send it to the 7th cage.
I’m going to the cage.  Take over
for me, please!
Unit 01 secured!
The pilot’s brain waves are
extremely erratic!
His cardiac readings are very weak.
Increase the power to the life support
systems.  Give him a heart massage.
Roger!
Pulse confirmed!
Force eject the entry plug!  Hurry!
Emergency LCL discharge!
Roger!
Come on, open the hatch!  Hurry!
Shinji!!
Episode 6:
Showdown
In Tokyo-3
The enemy’s accelerated particle beam
cannon has hit the balloon!
The decoy has been vaporized!
Next.
The Type 12 Mortar has
been vaporized!
I see.
From the data we’ve collected, we’re
assuming that the Angel automatically...
...attacks any opponents that come
within a certain range.
There’s a 100% probability that
anything that enters that range
will be targeted.
It is too risky for close range
combat in an Eva, isn’t it?
What’s the status of its AT Field?
It’s still active.
It’s strong enough that the spatial
changes in phase are visible.
Using conventional means of attack,
guided missiles, artillery and bombs...
...would inflict more damage on us
than on the Angel!
Yeah, offensively and defensively it’s
almost perfect.  A real flying fortress.
What’s the status on its drill?
At this moment the target is directly
above us, penetrating the
Tokyo-3 Null Zone.
A giant shielded drill,
with a diameter of 17.5 meters,
is boring towards NERV HQ.
The enemy is going to attack NERV
Headquarters directly.
Sassy bastard!
What’s its ETA?
00:06.54 AM, just after midnight.
By that time, it will have breached all
22 levels of defensive armor and will
penetrate NERV Headquarters itself.
Less than 10 hours...
The drill has contacted
the first armor plate.
What’s the condition of Unit 01?
The defensive armor was melted
down to the third layer...
...but the good news is that the central
control unit sustained no damage.
Given three more seconds, it would
have shot right through the Eva.
It will take three hours to install
replacement parts.
Roger.
What’s the status of Unit 00?
Reactivation itself should prove
no problem, but there’s still a
feedback error remaining.
So, it wouldn’t...
...survive combat.
What’s the condition of Unit 01’s pilot?
No physical damage.
However, nerve pulses are up by 0.8.
That’s still within acceptable limits.
Enemy arrival: 9 hours, 55 minutes.
Talk about your high
pressure situations.
Why don’t we raise a white flag?
Before we resort to that...
...there’s one little thing I’d like to try.
You want to use a sniper to shoot the
target from outside its firing zone?
Yes sir.
Instead of trying to neutralize
the target’s AT Field...
...I believe a pinpoint shot with a
focused high-energy beam is
the only way.
What do the MAGI say?
The responses from the MAGI
Supercomputers were 2 affirmative and 1
conditional affirmative.
Our probability of success is 8.7%.
It’s the highest value we could get.
I see no reason to reject your plan.
You may proceed, Captain Katsuragi.
Yes, sir.
You know how crazy this whole
operation is, don’t you, Operations
Director Katsuragi?
Don’t be rude, it’s not crazy.
It can be executed within the 9 hours
we have left and has the highest
chance of success.
It does?  Really?
But our positron rifle can’t handle
such a high output.
What are you going to do about that?
We’ll borrow one, of course.
Borrow one?  You don’t mean...?
Yeah!  The Strategic Self Defense
Force Lab’s new prototype!
NERV is hereby requisitioning
this Prototype Self Propelled Positron
Cannon as of 15:00 today.
But this is ridiculous.
We’ll try and return this in as close to
its original condition as we can.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Okay, Rei!  Take it away!
Be careful.  That’s a piece of
precision machinery.
But our calculations show that it will
take at least 180 million kW to
penetrate that AT Field.
Where are you going to get
that much electricity?
You know.  From all over Japan.
We apologize for interrupting our
regular programming for this
Emergency Bulletin.
From 11:30 PM tonight...
...until tomorrow morning,
there will be...
...a large scale power blackout
throughout most of Japan.
We appreciate your cooperation.
Repeat, from 11:30 PM tonight,
until tomorrow morning...
...there will be a large scale power
blackout throughout most of Japan.
We appreciate your cooperation.
The drill has just broken through the
seventh defensive layer.
What’s the status on the
energy supply system?
3.2% behind schedule, but we should
be finished by 23:10.
And the positron rifle?
For the honor of Technology
Development Department Section 3...
...we’re betting that we’ll have it
built in three hours.
And how’s our defense coming?
Well, using a shield is about
all we can do.
So, is this the shield?
Yes.  It was part of a single stage
trans-orbital rocket.
It may look ugly, but it’s got an
electromagnetic base coating
that Section 2 guarantees...
...will stand up to the enemy’s particle
beam for at least 17 seconds.
Good.  Have you determined
the sniper position?
Given the position and distance of the
target, and taking geographical
features and access to...
...power transformers into
consideration, this position
would be our best choice.
Right.  Looking good.
Our sniper will attack from the
top of Mt. Futago!
The operation will commence at 00:00
tomorrow morning.
From this point on, this operation will
be called “Operation Yashima.”
Roger.
Now, the only remaining problem
is the pilot.
Unit 01’s designated pilot
is conscious now.
His examination results look normal.
Good, then the operation will
proceed as planned.
Roger.
But...  I wonder if he’ll pilot it again.
Let’s get to Mt. Futago now!
Ayanami...
I’m here to brief you on the Operation
Yashima timetable.
The operation will begin at
midnight, 00:00 hours.
Prior to that, pilots Ikari and Ayanami
will arrive at the cage by 17:30.
At 18:00, Unit 01 and Unit 00
will activate.
At 18:05, both units will be deployed.
They will arrive at the temporary base
on Mt. Futago at 18:30.  There, they
will await further orders.
The operation will begin immediately
after midnight.
This is the new one.
Don’t show up looking like that.
Sorry.
I’ve been apologizing since yesterday...
Your meal.
I don’t want to eat anything...
We’ll be departing in 60 minutes.
Do I really have to pilot Eva again?
Yes, you do.
I don’t... want to.
You can be so cool about it
because you haven’t had the kind
of experiences I’ve had, yet.
I don’t want to go through it again.
Then you can just stay here, bedridden.
What do you mean by that?
I’ll pilot Unit 01.
Dr. Akagi is already prepared to
rewrite the personal data files
for Unit 01.
Ritsuko is...?
I’m leaving now.  Captain Katsuragi
and Dr. Akagi are waiting for me
in the cage.
Goodbye.
They’re really late.  We ought to
evacuate to the shelter.
I hacked into my dad’s data files.
I’m sure this is the time.
Why aren’t they here then?
The mountain is moving...
The Evangelions!
Cool.
Go for it, Evangelions!!  We believe
in you!!  Beat the Angel!!
The drill has penetrated through
the 17th layer of armor.
It will reach headquarters
in 3 hours 55 minutes.
Power supply transfer from Shikoku
and Kyushu areas completed.
Beginning tests of each cooling system.
This is a very delicate piece of
machinery!  Handle it carefully.
This thing wasn’t built for field
operations.  Will it really work?
Point taken, but we have no choice.
This was the most expedient way of
achieving our goal.
Are you sure it’s safe to use?
Theoretically, yes.
However, we’re not sure if the cannon
barrel and accelerator will be able to
handle the stress or not.
This is the first time it’s ever been fired
with such a high power output behind it.
Here are the battle plans
for the operation.
Shinji...
Yes.
Your Unit 01 will be the gunner.
Right.
Rei, you will cover him with Unit 00.
The reason for this arrangement is
because Shinji has a higher synch
ratio with Unit 01...
...and this operation will require an
exceptionally high degree of precision.
Since the positron beam will be
influenced by the Earth’s gravity,
magnetic fields and rotation...
...it will not fire in a straight line.
You must remember to adjust for these
deviations.  You must penetrate
the core precisely.
But I’ve never... practiced this!
Don’t worry...
...just do what the manual says.
As soon as the indicators in the
center converge, just pull the trigger.
The computers will handle the rest.
Also, be aware that before you can fire
the rifle a second time...
...you will first have to wait for the
unit to cool, then replace the
fuses and reload.
And if I miss or the enemy shoots back?
Don’t think like that.
You must destroy it with your first shot.
So, I have no choice.
I...
...I am just to defend Unit 01,
is that correct?
Yes.
Understood.
It’s time.  Get geared up.
Right.
Maybe...
...this will be our last day alive.
Why do you say that?
You won’t die.
I’ll protect you.
Why do you pilot this?
Because I’m bonded to it.
Bonded?
Yes, it’s a bond.
You mean... to my father?
To all people.
You’re very strong, Ayanami.
I have nothing else...
What do you mean you “have
nothing else”?
It’s time.  Let’s go.
Goodbye.
The time is now 00:00.
Commencing operation.
Shinji, we’re entrusting you with the
energy of the entire nation of Japan.
I’m counting on you.
Roger.
Initiate primary connection.
Initiating power transmission from
districts numbers 1 through 803.
Voltage is rising.  Water exchange unit
reaching pressure zone.
All cooling systems operating
on full power!!
Temperature stable.
No problems detected.
Positron charge is nominal.
Initiate second connection!
All accelerators engaging.
Activate convergence unit.
Transmitting all power to
Mt. Futago temporary substation.
No problems reported with
third connection.
Release final safety systems.
Pull sear up!
Error correction for Earth rotation
and gravity is 0.0009.
Voltage is 0.2 short of critical.
7th and 10th connections engaged!
Transmitting all energy to the
positron rifle!
8...
7...
6...
5...
High energy output detected
inside target!
4...
High energy output detected
inside target!
3...
It can’t be!
2...
1...
Fire!
No!
Did we miss?
The enemy drill has broken into
the Geo-Front!
Hurry!  Line up a second shot!!
Replacing fuses!  Initiating recharge!
Barrel cooling in progress!
We’ve got another high energy reading
building inside the target!
No, not now!!
Shinji!!
Ayanami!
That shield can’t last long!
Are we ready yet?!
10 more seconds.
Hurry up!!
We made it!!
Ayanami!
Are you all right?!
Don’t say... don’t say that you
have nothing else...
Don’t say “goodbye” when you
leave on a mission.  It’s too sad.
Why are you crying?
I’m sorry.  I don’t know what I should
do or feel at a time like this.
Why don’t you try smiling?
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
NERV isn’t the only agency that’s trying
to find ways to combat the Angels.
However, when the giant humanoid
type robot created by a civilian
corporation...
...goes out of control during its
official test trial...
...it’s up to Eva Unit 01 to catch
the rampaging Jet Alone.
Will Misato be able to stop its
nuclear reactor from melting down?
It’s the next episode,
“The Human Creation.”
And of course, I’ll give you lots of
fan service next time too!
Next Episode:
The Human
Creation