Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Correct, I have already arranged
it with the committee.
The cargo left from Sasebo Port
yesterday, and is now making its
way here across the Pacific Ocean.
A MIG-55 D transport helicopter!!
I’d never have believed I’d get a
chance to fly in one.
Thank God I have a buddy
like you, Shinji!
Well, I thought you guys would be
getting sick of being cramped up
in the mountains...
...so I just invited you on a date!
What?!  Today is really a date?
I bought this cap for today, Misato!
Where are we headed?
We’ll take a little jaunt across the
Pacific with a gorgeous cruiser.
Wow!!  One, two, three, four, five...
...aircraft carriers and four battleships!!
Whatta fleet!  I am absolutely sure
the best thing in life is having
a great buddy!
That’s your “gorgeous cruiser”?
Yeah, she sure is gorgeous!
That’s the pride of the UN,
the glorious regular carrier
“Over the Rainbow”!
It’s huge.
I’m surprised that such a relic
is still afloat.
Naw, it’s not so bad.
It’s a vintage model from just before
the Second Impact.
Damn, give me a break!
That ruffian’s gone and brought the
socket for the kid’s toy, so the little
gophers can run amuck!
Ohh!!  Cool!  Awesome!
Cool!  Incredible!!
Cool!  Mega-cool!  Wow!
This is way too cool!!
This kind of thing brings a tear
to the heart of a real man!
Cool!  Awesome!  Neat!  Wow!  Wow!
No!  Hey, wait!  Wait!
Damn it!
Stop!  Stop, now!!
Hello, Misato.
How have you been?
Fine, how ‘bout you?  You’ve grown
some, haven’t you?
And how!
I’m not just taller, my figure’s
filled out as well.
Let me introduce you.
This is the designated pilot of
Evangelion Unit 02, the Second Child...
...Asuka Langley Soryu.
Episode 8:
ASUKA
STRIKES!
What did you do that for?!
That’s the viewing fee.  Quite a
bargain, don’t you think?
What?  You think it’s worth that?!
Here, take a look at mine!
You insolent dork!!
So, which one is the famous
Third Child?
Don’t tell me it’s him.
Don’t worry, it’s him.
Well, he looks kinda dull.
I thought you were the leader of this
gang of boy scouts...
...but I was obviously mistaken.
Thank you for your
understanding, Captain.
Oh, no, thank you for giving me the
opportunity to baby-sit even more kids
after such a long time.
Well, thank you for your assistance
in the marine transport of Eva Unit 02.
Here are the specifications for the
emergency power supply socket.
In the first place, I’d never approve any
request to activate that toy while at sea.
Why don’t you just think of it as being
prepared for an emergency?
That’s why the Pacific Fleet
is guarding it.
When did the UN transform us
into a bloody cargo service?
If my memory serves me correctly,
it was just after a certain
organization was established.
Guarding a toy!  What a ridiculously
grandiose assignment for the entire
line of the Pacific Fleet!
It’s still not enough, not when you
consider the importance of the Eva.
Would you sign this document?
Not yet, Eva Unit 02 and its pilot have
been entrusted to us by the Third
Branch in Germany.
I won’t let you just waltz in and do
as you please!
Then when will you transfer them to us?
Once we’ve unloaded
in New Yokosuka.
The ocean is our jurisdiction.
You will follow our orders here.
I understand.
However, I should remind you that, in
the case of an emergency, our, NERV’s,
authority overrides yours.
She’s cool!
She looks like Ritsuko...
Well, you’re as gallant as always.
Kaji!
Mr. Kaji, I must insist that you not invite
yourself to the bridge.
Oh, sorry about that.
Well, excuse us.  Transport us to
New Yokosuka, as ordered.
This is a date?
Well, excuse us.  Transport us to
New Yokosuka, as ordered.
Cool!  This is just cool!
Well, excuse us.  Transport us to
New Yokosuka, as ordered.
I can’t take anymore!  Those kids are
really going to save the Earth?
The times have changed.
I understand that Congress has pinned
its hopes on that robot as well.
On that toy?  Idiots.
If they’ve got money to blow on that,
they ought to give a little more to us.
What are you doing here?!
Accompanying her.
I’m on a business trip from Germany.
Man, was I careless.
I should have anticipated this.
Hey!  Don’t touch me!
I can’t help it!
Squadron 3 will sortie as scheduled.
My God, why are you so cold?
Squadron 7 will stand duty on deck 2.
Do you have a boyfriend now?
My God, why are you so cold?
Squadron 7 will stand duty on deck 2.
Because your fire has gone out.
Do you have a boyfriend now?
Squadron 7 will stand duty on deck 2.
Outside it’s a hot summer, over 100 degrees.
That’s none of your business, is it?
How can you be so mean?
Outside it’s a hot summer, over 100 degrees.
What is this freezing cold?
My heart is below freezing.
I understand that you’re living with
Katsuragi here, aren’t you?
My heart is below freezing.
I understand that you’re living with
Katsuragi here, aren’t you?
My beer is frozen too.  I need a coat.
Y...yes.
Your heart has too much air conditioning.
So, tell me, is she still so wild in bed?
Why don’t you raise the temperature?
You’re the air conditioner.
Wha... wha...
You’re so stupid, venting your heat externally.
What are you implying?!!
The more heat you vent, the colder my heart.
So, she hasn’t changed,
Mister Shinji Ikari?
The more heat you vent, the colder my heart.
So, she hasn’t changed,
Mister Shinji Ikari?
Then, let us warm your frozen body together!
Um, well...
I’m sorry, you can’t light my heart...
How do you know my name?
Well, I ought to know you.
I’m sorry, you can’t light my heart...
...put logs on my fire and stoke me with oil.
You’re pretty famous in our business.
Who is it?  It can’t be.  Is it that guy?
The famous Third Child, who piloted an
Eva in his first battle with no training.
Who is it?  It can’t be.  Is it that guy?
The famous Third Child, who piloted an
Eva in his first battle with no training.
No, it’s this puppy.
It was just luck.
You’re telling me that I lost to this puppy?
Luck is a part of your destiny,
it’s your talent.
You’re telling me that I lost to this puppy?
Luck is a part of your destiny,
it’s your talent.
Yes, he’s a good boy...
Well, I’ll see you later.
...and he’s faithful, unlike some people!
See ya.
This has got to be a bad joke.
No, a nightmare.
So, what do you think about
Mister Shinji Ikari?
He’s boring.  That’s the great Third
Child?  What a disappointment.
And yet, his synchronization ratio
was well over 40% in combat,
with no prior training.
That can’t be true!
That captain’s attitude
gets on my nerves.
He’s got a lot of pride.
Too much pride’s bound to make
him cynical about us.
That Mr. Kaji is pretty... um, lively.
He hasn’t changed at all, that jerk.
Hey, Third Child!
Come with me!
Red?  I didn’t know that
Unit 02 was red.
The color isn’t the only difference.
After all, Units 00 and 01 were created
as part of a developing process,
prototype and test type respectively.
The fact that it synchronized with an
untrained pilot like you is proof of that.
However, Unit 02 is a little different.
Created for actual combat conditions,
this is the world’s first true Evangelion.
This is the final model!
W... what’s that?
An undersea shock wave!
Something exploded nearby!
What’s that?
Is that... an Angel?!
Is that a real one?
Oh, my gosh.  We’ve got to go back
and find Misato...
This is my chance!
All ships maintain formation
and take evasive action!
Status report!
The Cymbeline’s gone silent.  The Titus
Andronicus can’t locate the target!
Damn it!  What in the hell is
going on here?!
Hello, NERV delivery.
Would you like to order information on
this enemy and countermeasures
to use against it?
This is a combat situation!  No
unauthorized personnel allowed!!
This is just my opinion, but I’d say this
must be an Angel attack.
All ships, fire at will!
It’s pointless.
An AT Field can’t be penetrated with
this kind of firepower.
But why is an Angel here?
My God, is it after Unit 02?
Where are you taking me?
Just wait there a second.
I can’t believe this.
Don’t peep, you pervert!!
Sorry!
Why are all boys such perverted jerks?
Here we go, Asuka.
Why won’t it sink?!
I knew it... only an Eva can beat it!
Let’s go.
Come with me!
Hey, what are these
entry plug suits for?
Are you dense?
We’re going to beat it with my Unit 02!
No way.  Do you have an
approval from Misato?
I’ll get permission after I’ve beaten it.
Now, I’ll show you how magnificent
my piloting is!
Just don’t disturb me.
This is odd.  It seems to be
looking for something.
I didn’t expect to see an Angel here.
This isn’t how it’s supposed to be, is it?
That is what Unit 02 is for...
...and I’ve generously provided a
second pilot as a reserve.
If worst comes to worst, you can
escape by yourself.
I know.
LCL Füllung!
LCL filling entry plug intake!
Anfang der Bewegung!
Beginning activation!
Anfang des Nervenanschlusses!
Beginning nerve link-up!
Ausulsses vonlinks-kleigung!
Nerve link-up commencing!
Synchro-start!
Synchronization start!
Program error?  What happened?
Thought noise!  I told you not
to disturb me.
What do you mean?
You’re thinking in Japanese aren’t
you?  Think in German.
Oh, okay... strudel...
Idiot!
Fine, stop trying.  Switch the
language to basic Japanese.
Evangelion Unit 02, activate.
Telex from the Othello!  Eva Unit 02
is in the process of activation.
What the...?!
Nice going, Asuka!!
No!  Abort the activation
sequence!  Reset it!!
I don’t care!  Asuka!  Go for it!
What are you doing?!  Eva and its
pilot are under our control!
You’re violating my command authority!
What are you talking about?  This is
an emergency!  Who gives a damn
about your procedures?
You and your procedures!!
You’re not serious?  You do know that
Unit 02 is still using the B equipment?
If we fall in the sea, we’re done for!
And if we don’t, we’ll be fine, all right?
Shinji, are you in there too?
Yes.
Kids!  Two kids!
This is a good opportunity...
Asuka, launch!
It’s coming!
Charge!
Where is it?
That way!
We’ve only got 58 seconds left!
I am well aware of that!  Misato!
Get the external power supply
socket onto the flight deck.
I’ve got it!
What is she going to do?
Here we go!  Jump!
Jump?
Run!
The power socket is in place!
Reactor connection completed!
The deck is ready for Eva landing!
All hands, prepare for impact!
I can’t believe this!
Eva 02, landing on deck!
No!  Whatta waste...
Target is approaching rapidly!
It’s coming!  9 o’clock!
Switching to external power!
Switch completed.
But we don’t have any weapons.
The progressive knife should
be good enough.
It’s bigger than I thought!
That’s what I figured!
What are they going to do?!
Hand-to-hand combat is the best
way to defeat Angels.
Good work, Asuka!
This isn’t a game!  Look at the mess
you’ve made of the deck!
See?!  It’s sinking!
Asuka!
It’s impossible to fight underwater
with the B equipment!
You never know...
...till you try!
What a waste!
How much cable is left?
1,200 meters more!
What are you going to do?
We can deal with it... somehow.
I’ve got to do something...
The cable’s going to run out!
Brace for the shock!
Damn it!
Eva missed the target!
I’ve got to change the disk.
My God!  A Yak-38 Custom!!
Hey, Katsuragi!
Kaji!
I’ve got something to deliver,
so I’ll be taking off now...
Launch!
Take care of the rest of this,
Captain Katsuragi.
H... he ran away.  I don’t believe it!
The target is approaching Eva again!
It’s coming again!
I’ll finish it off this time.
What?!  It’s not working!
That’s because this is B type equipment.
What’re you gonna do?!
What am I gonna do?
You’re the Third Child,
aren’t you?  Do something!
Here it comes!
A m...m...mouth?!
That’s because it’s an Angel.
Eva 02 has entered the target’s body.
Does that mean that the
Eva’s been eaten?
This is like fishing!
Fishing?  Yes, fishing!
From a bad situation to a worse one.
Hey, get off me already!
Hey, get off me already, you pervert!
But we’ve got to free ourselves.
Asuka, do you read me?
Don’t let go of it!!
Captain.
What?
I’m requesting your cooperation.
A point-blank assault by the
two surviving battleships?!
Correct.
We’ll sink two of the evacuated
battleships on top of the umbilical
cable to set a trap.
When the Eva opens the target’s mouth,
both ships will rush into the opening.
They will fire all of their bow turret
cannons and then self-destruct,
destroying the target.
That’s absurd!
Absurd, perhaps, but not impossible.
I understand.
All hands abandon ship!  Repeat,
all hands, abandon ship!
The frigates will rescue the lifeboats!
But what about the Eva?
Not to worry.  They’ll be fine.
Hey!  Don’t use Unit 02
without my permission!
Do the two of you understand
the operation?
I’ll do my best.
I’m counting on you.
All ships, open the Kingston valve!
Scuttle at point z.
Roger!
Cable reverse!
Eva has started to surface!
T-minus 70 to contact!
Hey, you’re touching my... get off!
But we’ve got to open its mouth
or we’ll be killed!
T-minus 60 to contact.
Status on the Angel’s mouth?
It’s still not open!!
Both battleships are sinking
towards the target.
Eva is continuing to
surface, T-minus 50 to contact.
No, it won’t open!
No time left!
Target has passed beneath the Tempest!
Hurry!!  Or you won’t make it!
Don’t get any strange ideas.
What?
Anyway, just concentrate
on your thoughts.
You can say that again!
T-minus 20 to contact!
T-minus 15 to contact!
Open!  Open!  Open!  Open!
Fire!
Christ!  That was rather spectacular!
I had to improvise for underwater
combat, I should have anticipated it.
It’s rare for you to regret something.
Is this some kind of self-analysis?
Cut it out.  We’ve collected a lot
of valuable data.
Yeah...
Misato...
This really is something special.
P...pair of... look...
I don’t believe this.
They broke their synchronization ratio
records, didn’t they?
In only 7 seconds.  It must have
been due to the danger.
Hey, where’s Kaji?
He ran off earlier.  That idiot’s got to
be back at headquarters by now!
It was a pretty eventful trip.
Was it caused by this, I wonder?
It’s already restored itself this far.
It’s frozen inside Dura-Bakelite,
but it’s still alive.
This is the keystone of the Human
Instrumentality Project, isn’t it?
Correct.
This is the first human being...
...Adam.
She may have looked cute, but she
was a real bitch.
Well, we won’t have to see her again.
Yeah, ol’ Mister Big Shot has to
see her at work though.
I’m really feeling sorry for you.
My name is Asuka Langley Soryu.
I’m very pleased to meet you.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Deploying for large scale
shoreline interception...
...Asuka and Shinji’s first close
teamwork results in their being
roughed up due to their bad terms.
Misato gets a plan to achieve
their perfect unison.
A six-day-long drama for human
destiny shall begin.
The next episode:
“With One Accord in a Flash.”
Well, we’ll make you a bargain!
Next Episode:
With One Accord
in a Flash