Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
Hey, have you seen her yet?
Oh, yeah!  Yeah!
Seen what?
You dork, you haven’t seen the girl
who studied overseas yet?
Girl who studied overseas?
Yeah, she’s in 8th grade, Class A.
She just transferred here last week.
She’s hot!
Her name’s Asuka Langley Soryu,
did you know that?
Yeah, she’s so cute.
Since she was raised over there but
born here, do you think she
already has a boyfriend?
Don’t be stupid!
I bet she broke up in Germany,
and she’s here in a foreign land...
...with a heart that can’t be mended.
Oh, my gosh...
...did you hear all the cat talk?
Asuka!  Asuka!
They’re just ignorant.
Thank you, come again.
At least the pictures don’t
reveal her personality.
Hello!
Shinji!
Guten Morgen!
G...guten Morgen.
Why so gloomy?  This is the gorgeous
Asuka greeting you!
You should appreciate
your good fortune!
I’m the most popular girl in school!
Hey, the other one’s here too, isn’t she?
Other one?
What are you, stupid?  I’m talking
about the First Child, of course!
Oh, Ayanami...
Hello!
You must be Rei Ayanami, the pilot
of the prototype.
I’m Asuka!  Asuka Langley Soryu.
I’m the designated pilot of Eva Unit 02.
Let’s be good friends!
Why?
Because it’d be convenient.
You know what I mean?
If I’m ordered to, I will.
Talk about odd...
I’ll say.  Are only weirdos
chosen to be pilots?
You’ve lost some weight.
Is that so?
You must be enduring
an unrequited love.
How... did you know?
Because...
...“a woman with a mole in the
pathway of her tears is destined
to a life full of them.”
If you’re trying to put a move
on me, I’m afraid you can’t.
There’s a very ugly face observing us.
Long time no see, Mr. Kaji.
It’s been a while.
You’re a little less discreet
than I expected.
He hasn’t ever been discreet in his life!
You’ve finished handing over Unit 02,
haven’t you?!  You should
be leaving now!
I just received orders this morning
that I’ll be staying here “on loan.”
So, we can hang around again...
...just like we used to.
You’ve got to be kidding!
Enemy attack?!
We just got this report from the
battle cruiser Haruna.
“Have detected huge submerged object
off Kii peninsula.  Sending data.”
The data has been collated
and examined.
Wavelength Pattern Blue.
Confirmed to be an Angel.
All personnel, go to first stage alert.
Episode 9:
With One Accord
in a Flash
The recent battle severely damaged
Tokyo-3’s intercept system.
Only 26% of our defense capability
has been restored.
In addition, our operational capability
for actual combat is virtually nil.
Therefore, we’re going to have to
intercept the target at the water’s edge,
right before it makes landfall!
Units 01 and 02 will mount a
coordinated attack in a series of waves.
In other words, close in and take turns.
Roger.
This sucks.  My Japanese debut and
she won’t let me handle it solo.
Why do I have to bring you?!
SOP.  Procedures, you know.
Well, let me tell you something, just
don’t get in my way!
His selection as a pilot must have
been a joke, right?
Two against one is not what I call
a fair fight.  It’s not fair.
We don’t get a choice.
Survival takes priority.
There!
Commence attack!
I’ll handle this Angel!  You cover me!
C...cover you?!
Ladies first!
Damn it, don’t give me orders
you dumb rookie!
Charge!
That wasn’t bad.
Well, Third Child, what did you
think of that?
A fight should be clean and
elegant, without waste.
What’s this crap?!
Today, at 10:58.15 AM...
...Unit 01 was attacked
by Target Alpha...
...which had separated from the other
target submerged 2 km off Suruga Bay.
At the same hour, same minute, plus 20
seconds, Unit 02 was halted by
Target Beta’s attack.
We have a comment from
Project E chairperson.
This is pathetic.
This is all your fault!  You totally
screwed up my debut battle!
What are you talking about?  You’re
the one who charged in there acting
like an idiot!
Idiot?!  How dare you call me that?
You pathetic excuse for a combat pilot!
You’re just a jerk!
Look in the mirror!  You were in such a
rush to show off in combat that you
completely disregarded procedures!
What was that?  You look
like a drowned rat!
At 11:03 AM, NERV abandoned the...
What was that?  You look
like a drowned rat!
At 11:03 AM, NERV abandoned the...
You... you can’t say that
kind of thing to me!
...operation and transferred command
to the UN Secondary Force.
We’ve been humiliated.
At 11:05 AM, the UN forces made
an attack with an N2 mine.
We’ll have to redraw the map again.
They succeeded in burning off 28% of
target’s structural substance.
Did they kill it?
This is merely temporary relief.  The
second attack is just a matter of time.
At least we have time to reorganize
and regroup.  You can’t ask for
more than that.
Listen up, you two.
Do you know what your job is?
Piloting Eva.
No!
Your job is to defeat the Angels.
NERV does not exist to make grotesque
displays like this.
Therefore, you two must cooperate.
Why should we?!
Enough already!
Why does everyone get so angry here?
It’s because adults are much too
aware of their credibility.
Um, where’s Misato?
Clearing things up.  The person in
charge exists to take responsibility.
Here are the protests and damage
reports from the bureau concerned.
This is a bill from the UN...
...and here you have a complaint from
the Public Relations Department as well.
Read them all.
I can tell what they say without looking.
“If you’re going to fight,
do it here,” right?
Good guess.
I’ll do it as soon as we take
care of this Angel.
I swear I will destroy that Angel.
The Vice-Commander is pretty angry.
You’ll almost certainly be demoted
if you embarrass him again.
It was just good luck within bad luck
that Commander Ikari wasn’t here.
If he’d been here, you’d have been fired
before he ever saw these papers.
So, have you brought me an
idea to help save my job?
Just one.
I thank you, Dr. Ritsuko Akagi.
It’s good to have a friend
one can count on.
However, I’m not the one who’ll
be saving my old friend.
This is Kaji’s idea.
Kaji?
I’m home!  Not that anyone’s here,
of course, but...
What is this?!
Don’t be so rude!
Those are my personal belongings!
You!  What in blazes are you
doing in my house?!
Why are you STILL here?
Still here?
Yeah, you’ve been dumped
for the new model!
Misato will be living with me.
Of course, that’s a much more logical
choice when you consider
my superior abilities.
Although honestly, I’d rather
live with Kaji.
Say, just why are Japanese houses
so small anyway?
Not even half of my stuff fits!
And Japanese sure don’t have
any sense of privacy.
How can they live in a room without
locks?  Unbelievable!
It’s because the Japanese way is to
consider the priorities and needs of
others before one’s own.
Misato!
How are you?  You two are going
to get along real well, right?
What do you mean?
This is all preparation for
the next operation.
Say what?
There is only one way to destroy
the Seventh Angel!
A simultaneous two-point attack
on each target’s core while its
components are separated.
In other words, an attack by two Evas
with perfectly synchronized timing.
Cooperation and coordination between
the two of you will be paramount.
Therefore, I want the two
of you to live together.
No way!  “A boy and a girl should
never sleep under one roof after
the age of seven”!
The Angel is currently restoring itself.
It will begin its second assault
in six days, there’s no time.
But it’s impossible.
Now we have a way to
make it possible!
The master attack pattern will be
choreographed using this music.
In six days, as soon as possible.
I’m worried about Shinji.
He’s been gone three days, right?
Hey, there’s the class rep.
Two of the three stooges.
Why are you here?
To offer condolences to Miss Soryu.
What about you two?
To offer condolences to Ikari.
Why did you stop here?
Yes?
Y...you’ve betrayed us.
You look like two peas in a pod.
I can’t believe this!
Neither can we.  It’s all Misato’s fault!
We have to eat, breathe and
sleep together!
You’re living in sin!  How awful!
No!  It’s not like that!
Then just what is it like?
Hi, welcome everybody!
Why don’t you explain all this to us?
You should have told us that first.
How is the coordination coming?
Well, as you can see.
Well, so much for synchronization!
I could never sink down to the pathetic
level this animated turnip lives at!
If you ask me, this whole
idea is impossible!
Then you give up?
But you don’t have anyone
else, do you?
Rei...
Yes, ma’am.
Why don’t you try?
It looks like I should alter the operation
to make a pair of Shinji and Rei.
No!  I can’t stand this!
I can’t take it anymore!
Asuka!
Even the Devil cries sometimes.
Ikari!
You’ve got to follow her!
You made her cry!  It’s your fault!
Well...
Don’t say anything.
I know.
I have to pilot the Eva.
I’ve got no choice.
I’ll do it.
No matter what, I’ll put Rei and
Misato to shame!
You don’t have to squash them.
You’re being too simplistic, even if
you are a man!
I must avenge myself...
...my pride...
It’s a matter of honor now, you see?
Where’s Misato?
At work.  She called earlier.
She’ll be there all night.
So, that means we’re all
alone tonight, huh?
This is the impenetrable “Wall
of Jericho,” Third Child.
Take one step over this wall
and you’ll be a dead man.
And now, it’s time to go to bed, children!
Why do Japanese sleep on the floor?
This is so stupid.
Mama...
You’re just a child yourself.
No, somebody’s watching us.
Who’s watching?
Someb...
No!  There’s nothing between
us anymore.
Don’t do that again.
But your lips didn’t say no.
Which one should I trust?
Your lips or your words?
There you go.
Thanks.
You’re unusually sober today.
Yeah, a little...
Work?  Or a man?
A lot of things.
Still in love?
Don’t be ridiculous!!
Who’d want that idiot?!
I was young, and it’s still the biggest
blemish on my whole life.
I meant that he may still like you.
Did I scare you?
Why you lousy...
You’re only proving my hypothesis.
Why don’t you go with your feelings?
It’s not like it’s still eight years ago.
It hasn’t changed.  Not a bit.
He’s still immature.
Well, I’ve got to get to work.
Tomorrow is D-Day.
Target has broken through the
final defense line at Gora.
Here it comes!
We won’t fail this time!
Spread your AT fields as soon
as the music starts.
Then follow the operation
choreography.
Are you two ready?
Roger!
The target has entered the mountains.
Just remember Shinji, full power,
maximum performance.
I know that.  We’ll finish in 62 seconds.
Target entering ground zero.
Detach external power cables.
Launch.
Confirmation.  Both Evas are
operational.
Jeez...
This is pathetic.
You jerk!
What are you doing on my Unit 02?!
What are you talking about?  You’re
the one who fell on me!
You’re the one who lost
his timing first!
You’re always so slow!
What were you doing, staying up so
late last night?!
Image training for today’s battle!
Liar!  I know you tried to kiss
me while I was sleeping!
You cheat!  You were awake?
Oh, my gosh!  I was just kidding!
Did you really kiss me?!
No, I didn’t!  I stopped!
Pervert!  Fiend!  Idiot!
I can’t believe this!
You caused it by calling for your
mother and sleepwalking!
Those kids are embarrassing us again.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
The crater of Mt. Asama where an
unhatched Angel lies.
Misato immediately requests the
announcement of an A-17.
NERV personnel attempt the first
capture of an Angel under top
priority circumstances.
An Eva with limited area equipment
challenges the fires of hell!
It’s an extreme environment of
high heat and pressure.
What did Asuka see there?
It’s the next episode, “Magma Diver.”
And I’ll give you more service!
Next Episode:
MAGMA DIVER