Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
Cool!  I won a free ice cream bar!
Boy, the cost of doing laundry has
been killing me lately.
I just wish I had the time to wash
my clothes for myself.
You should appreciate the fact that
you can at least sleep at home.
Hello, Vice-Commander.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, sir!
Good morning.
You’re quite early today.
Well, I have to go uptown as
Ikari’s representative.
I see, isn’t today the City Council’s
regular meeting?
It’s a boring job.
He always forces the most
tedious work on me.
Without the MAGI’s help,
I couldn’t do it.
Speaking of which, election day
is coming up, isn’t it?
The City Council has no
authority at all.
Actually, the MAGI run
everything now.
The MAGI?
You mean the three
supercomputers?
Government by the majority decision
of three different computers.
It’s a sort of democratic system.
And the council just obeys
their decisions?
It’s a most effective form
of government.
This truly is a “city of science.”
We are fortunate to live in an
era when Almighty Science
reigns supreme.
Talk about old fashioned viewpoints.
Come to think of it, you have
an experiment to run on
Unit 00, don’t you?
Yes, we’re going to perform
the second prolonged activation
test at 10:30.
I’m expecting good news.
Abort experiment!  Cut the circuit!
Switching circuits.
Power supply restored.
This component is the
problem again.
Yes.
I think the problem is the conversion
efficiency is 0.008 lower than our
theoretical calculations.
It’s within the tolerance
though, barely.
What are we going to do?
Let’s try it again using the
same configuration...
...but lower the reciprocal
conversion rate by 0.01.
Roger.
Now, let’s recommence the
reactivation experiment.
Episode 11:
In the Still
Darkness
Hey, hold up!
Shit...
Man, I’ve never had to
run this much!
So what’s with the black expression?
It’s from having to see your
loathsome face first thing
in the morning.
Yes, hold just a moment please.
What?
Well, Father...
What?  Hurry up.
Well...
I’m supposed to...
...tell my parent that an interview...
...for Advanced Vocational
Education is going to be
held at school...
I’ve delegated things like
that to Captain Katsuragi.
Don’t bother me with such nonsense.
Don’t forward any more
of these calls to—
What?
A blackout?
No, it can’t be.  It’s not possible.
Something’s strange.  An accident?
Perhaps Dr. Akagi made a mistake?
The main power supply has
been interrupted.
Voltage level is zero!
It’s not my fault!
What do you think?
It’ll switch to the backup
power supply soon.
No, the backup circuits
aren’t working.
That can’t be.
Which circuits are functioning?
Only 1.2% of them!
Only nine circuits out of 2,567!
Route all of the remaining power
circuits to maintain the MAGI
and Central Dogma.
But that could interfere with
life support systems.
Do it!  That’s our top priority!
This is Nozomu Takahashi, who
wants a more cheerful government.
Boy, she’s such a lazy slob.
This is Nozomu Takahashi, who
wants a more cheerful government.
Boy, she’s such a lazy slob.
We need your support for this
righteous and honest candidate.
Can’t she pick up her own laundry?
We need your support for this
righteous and honest candidate.
Thank you!
Maybe Commander Ikari was
just really busy?
I doubt it.
It wasn’t like he hung up.  It was
more like a mechanical failure.
Hey, are you a man or what?
Stop letting every little
incident bother you!
What?
What do you think you’re doing?
Here, let me try that!
Damn!!  It must be broken, damn it!
Heave...
...ho!
We’d better head for the
command station.
It’s been seven minutes and the
power hasn’t restored itself.  This is...
...very unusual.
What’s the backup
power system here?
There are three circuits,
main, sub and reserve.
It’s virtually impossible for all
of those to fail at once.
Then that means...
...the circuit breakers didn’t go on
their own.  Someone must have
blown them intentionally.
Regardless of the cause, it would be
disastrous if an Angel were to
attack right now.
Radar has detected an
unidentified object.
Projected landing point is in
the former Atami region.
It must be number eight.
I agree, it must be an Angel.
What are we going to do?
Go to alert status.  That’s the
procedure, anyway.
This one’s destination
has to be Tokyo-3.
I agree.  Well, this is no job for us.
The Angel has landed.
It’s still advancing.
What about Tokyo-3?
It’s still silent.
What in the hell are those
NERV guys doing?
I never thought I’d actually have to
use one of these trap exits.
I thought they were just holdovers
from an outdated technology that
we kept for our peace of mind.
“To provide is to prevent.”
This one doesn’t work either!
None of the facilities work.
This is odd.
Could this mean that something’s
happened down in the Geo-Front?
It is natural to assume that.
In any case, let’s try to make contact
with NERV Headquarters.
No, the emergency phones aren’t
getting through either.
No, there’s no answer on Line 77.
No, no response.
Not on this one either.
So, the main and emergency
cables are both down.
What do we do now?
What’re you doing?
What are you, stupid?  I’m looking
for my emergency manual.
Anyway, let’s go to
NERV Headquarters.
Yeah, but before that we’ll need
to decide who will be the
leader of this group.
And naturally, I am the leader.
Any objections?
Now, let’s go.
We can proceed along
Route-07, right here.
But the doors don’t work.
We can open it manually.
There you go, Shinji, that’s your job.
I don’t believe it!  You always
want to control everything...
...but you always defer to me
in a situation like this.
Damn those Joint Staff Council
bastards!  They always defer
to us in a situation like this!
What does the government say?
Those Tokyo-2 buttheads?
They’re getting ready to run.
The Angel is still advancing.
In any case, we must contact NERV.
But how?
By going there yourself.
This is the 3rd District ASDF!
An unidentified object is moving
toward this area.
All residents must evacuate to
their designated shelters!
Big trouble!
I’ve got to report this
to headquarters!
But how?
Remember Takahashi, who remains
calm even in situations
such as this!
Please support candidate Takahashi!
Lucky!
It’s too hot.
Yeah, the air conditioners are out.
Katsuragi...
If you’re so hot, why don’t you
take off your shirt?
There’s no reason for shyness
between you and me.
Don’t even think about trying to
take advantage of this situation.
Okay, okay!
It’s getting even worse.
Now, the air is getting stagnant.
It’s hard to believe that this facility
represents the most advanced
technology on Earth.
But look at the Commander
and Vice-Commander.
Even in this much heat,
they’re cool and in command.
It’s getting warmer.
Yes...
...along with the declaration of
emergency in this district.
Emergency vehicle!
Passing through!
Oh, my!  Excuse me, it’s blocked!
It’s okay!  Charge!
This is an emergency!
Everything is permitted!
Aye, sir!
No!  Let me off!!
This Geo-Front was designed
to be a self-sufficient colony, even
when isolated from the outside.
Theoretically, it’s impossible for all
of the power sources to be shut
down at once.
You mean that someone
caused it to happen?
Their purpose would be
to map this facility.
You mean they could determine
our headquarters’ structure by
analyzing the restoration process?
Disrespectful bastards.
I’ll run a dummy program
through the MAGI.
That will make it harder for them
to get a complete picture
of the structure.
I’ll leave it to you, then.
Yes, sir.
I can’t believe the first havoc
wreaked upon our headquarters...
...wasn’t caused by some Angel,
but by another member of
our own species.
One of mankind’s greatest enemies
is man himself.
But it usually only takes
two minutes.
Are you sure this is the right way?
Of course I’m sure!  If we can
get beyond this point we’ll
be at the Geo-Front.
Haven’t I heard that four
times already?
You’re too picky.  You’re always
focusing on the most insubstantial
little tidbits.
Silence, please.
What now, Wonder Girl?
A man’s voice.
Ang...  ...proaching...
That’s Hyuga!
Hey!!  Hey!!  Hey!!
An Angel is approaching!
Repeat, an Angel is approaching!
An Angel?!
We can’t waste any more time.
Let’s take a shortcut.
Hey, I’m the leader!  Don’t take any
initiatives without my permission!
Now then, where is this shortcut?
This may be the quickest way,
but we look really stupid.
Say, just what do you think
the Angels are?
Why are you talking about
something like that at a
time like this?
Well, angels are messengers of God,
right?  But our enemies are
named after angels.
So, why are we fighting them?
What are you, stupid?
Strange beings started attacking us.
When someone’s attacking you,
you can’t just sit there and do
nothing, right?
To the right!
I think the correct path is to the left.
Stop bothering me!
What do you think, Shinji?
Well...
I’m not sure.
Damn it!  I’m the leader, so just
shut up and follow me!!
You know, I kind of expected that
this would be a little odd.
The path is going up.
What do you mean “you expected”?
You’re always nit-picking
and worrying!
Look, this has got to be it this time!
Well, we’ve visually confirmed
the Angel’s presence!
Now, we know we have to hurry.
An Angel is approaching!
An immediate Eva dispatch will
be necessary!
Oh, my gosh!
Fuyutsuki, take care of
the rest of this.
Ikari?
I will help prepare for the
launch in the cage.
Are you serious?
You mean by hand?
We have a diesel generator
for such emergencies.
But...
We have no pilots!
Not again!
This way.
I’ve heard that you’re the
Commander’s favorite, aren’t you?
You’re a favored smart ass who’s
treated differently from the rest of us.
Stop it!  This isn’t the time for that!
You’ve always got that smug
look on your face.
Hey, do you think you can
act superior just because
you’re treated better?
I don’t act superior.
And I’m not treated better either.
I know that quite well.
Roger.  The ejection of the
termination plug is complete.
Good, prepare to insert
the entry plug.
But the pilots aren’t here yet.
Don’t worry, they’ll come.
There’s no way I can open
this with my hands.
It can’t be helped.  We’ll have to
break into a duct to get through.
This First Child isn’t someone to
mess with.  She’ll do anything to
accomplish her objectives.
She’s a real self-righteous bitch.
The plug is fixed and ready.
Now, we just have to
wait for the kids.
If you dare look forward...
...I’ll kill you!!
You jerk!
Ignoramus!  Nincompoop!
I told you not to look!
I have to see to go forward...
Ah, there you are.
Prepare for entry!
Roger, open the hatches manually.
How are the Evas?
They’re in standby.
How?  Nothing’s working.
It was all done by hand.
It was the Commander’s idea.
My father’s?
Commander Ikari believed in you,
Shinji, and prepared everything.
Plugs inserted.
All units activated using backup
power supply.
Remove primary lockbolts.
Hydraulic locks numbers 2
through 32, released.
Zero pressure.
The situation is free.
Go ahead and remove the restraints.
Begin the attack!
The target has stopped
right above us.
Get ready!  Hurry up!
The emergency batteries
have been installed!
Well, we’re ready.
Launch!!
Jeez!  I look so pathetic!
We’re approaching a vertical shaft.
This is still pathetic.
Watch out!  Dodge!
No!
It would appear the target is going to
invade headquarters directly using
that liquid solvent.
What’ll we do?
We’re going to beat it, of course.
Sure, but how?
We dropped our rifles and the
battery packs on our backs
are running out.
They won’t last more than
another three minutes.
I have a plan.
One of us will take the defensive
position and stay here.
Their job is to neutralize
the Angel’s AT Field...
...and to protect the offensive
player from that acid.
The backup player...
...will go down, pick up the rifles and
hand them to the offense.
The offense will then fire a volley
to destroy the target.
How does that sound?
I see, I will take the defense.
Sorry, but it’s not you.
It’s me.
It’s too dangerous!
That’s why.
I’ll feel bad if I don’t pay you back
for the one I owe you from
the last battle.
Shinji will be the offense.
Wonder Girl is the backup.
Got it?
Understood.
Here we go!
CHARGE!!
Ayanami!!
Asuka, get out of the way!!
Now we’re even.
Oh, damn it!!  Why doesn’t it open?!
This is a desperate situation!  I’ve got
to go to the bathroom now!
Hey, I told you not to look up!
Okay!  Yes, ma’am!
Disgusting...
It’s ironic...
Without electricity and artificial
light, the sky can look so beautiful.
But without the lights, it’s as if
there were no humans there.
See?  I feel much more
comfortable this way.
Man has always feared the darkness,
so he scrapes away at its edges
with fire.
He creates life by diminishing
the darkness.
A philosopher.
Is that what makes mankind
a special species?
Is that why the Angels keep
attacking us?
What are you, stupid?
Who knows what they think?
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Misato’s achievements are evaluated
and she is promoted to Major.
However, her whole career has
merely been a result of her personal
drive to exterminate the Angels.
When Misato tells Shinji of her past,
he finds a similar sentiment
within himself.
The largest Angel yet comes flying
through the stratosphere, making
many people abandon all hope.
It’s the next episode,
“The Value of a Miracle is...”
Again, watch it with your friends.
Next Episode:
The Value of
a Miracle is...