Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Hey, Shinji, did you change
the soup stock?
Yeah, to dried fish flavor.
It’s a gift from Ritsuko.
Too hot!
I’m sorry.
You’re always apologizing!  Do you
always think you’re the one at fault?
Shinji, apologies are your conditioned
reflex to any kind of confrontation!
I’m sorry.
Exactly like that.
You’re too self-deprecating!
Now, now, that’s just his way.
It’s so easy to just accept his
pathetic habits, isn’t it?!
But haven’t you been a little
too easy on Shinji lately?
Have I?
Maybe you and Kaji have
hooked up again...
...but the fact that you’re happy doesn’t
mean that you can just ignore us.
There’s nothing between me and Kaji.
Hey, Katsuragi, I’ve found a bar
that serves a decent drink.
How ‘bout tonight?  Bye!
I’ve never been around anyone involved
in such an indecent relationship before!
You’re supposed to be our guardian!
You hypocrite!
It’s disgusting!!
Episode 16:
Sickness Unto
Death, and...
B-type harmonics test, all green.
Projected adjustment values
have been cleared.
You look tired, Misato.
Yeah, for a lot of private reasons.
Kaji?
Shut up!
Well, how’s the Third Child doing?
Take a look.
Let me see.
I hope that knowing this will
boost his confidence.
Can you hear me, Shinji?
Misato!  How were my test scores?
Yes!  You are Number One!
I lost!
He beat us easily.
He beat us so easily it’s pissing me off!
He’s great, wonderful, awesome,
too awesome!
The invincible Shinji!
So that makes our job a
little easier, right?
But it also means that we’ll have to do our
best to not be left behind.
Goodbye.
Next stop is Seisho Kabuse.
Next stop, Seisho Kabuse.
Convenient to the Bashar, used books
and video game stores...
Good.
Five minutes until evacuation of the
Western District is completed.
Target is advancing slowly
at 2.5 km per hour.
You’re late.
I’m sorry.
What’s going on?
The observation center in Fuji...
...didn’t detect it.  It just suddenly
appeared directly above us.
Pattern Orange.  No AT Field detected.
What is this?
A new kind of Angel?
The MAGI are withholding judgment.
Damn!  A situation like this and
Commander Ikari’s not here.
Can you all hear me?
I’ve sent you all of the target’s data.
This is all we know right now.
Approach it carefully and observe
its reactions and, if possible,
lure it outside of the city limits.
Two of you will back up
the other, got that?
All right, ma’am, but I think Shinji
ought to take point.
Well, this is a job for the highest rated,
bravest, Number One synchro-ratio
holder, right?
Or don’t you feel up to it, Shinji?
No, I can do it.
I’ll show you how it ought
to be done, Asuka.
Wh...what was that?
Hey, you two cut it out.
Isn’t that what you said, Misato?
“You are Number One!”
Well, that was...
And combat is a man’s job, after all.
Talk about out of date!
Unit 02 will back him up.
Unit 00 will back him up as well.
I can’t believe those kids are doing
this without my orders.
Shinji’s getting more manly, isn’t he?
No, I’m going to have to chew him
out when he gets back.
You might just be a good teacher.
Ayanami, Asuka, are you in position yet?
Not yet.
You know an Eva can’t move that fast.
Not there yet?
I’ll have to stop it myself.
It disappeared!
What?!
Pattern Blue!!  Angel confirmed!
Directly beneath Unit 01!
A... a shadow?!
What is this?!  I can’t believe it!!
Shinji, get out of there!  Shinji?!
Ikari?
You idiot!  What are you doing?!
Misato, what’s going on?!
Misato?  Asuka!  Ayanami!  Help me!
Misato?!  Can you hear me, Misato?!
Misato!!
Eject the plug!  Send the signal!
Misato?!  Can you hear me, Misato?!
Misato!!
No response!  It’s not working!
Misato!  Misato!
Shinji!
Asuka!  Rei!  Rescue Unit 01!  Hurry!
That idiot.  He can get an A on a test
but not in the real world.
It disappeared again!
Asuka, be careful.
A shadow?
The city is sinking!
Asuka!  Rei!  Pull back!
B...
Wait!
Unit 01 and Ikari are still in there.
This is an order.  Retreat.
Major Katsuragi must feel awful.
They reeled the umbilical cable back in,
but the other end was missing.
Without power...
There’s not much energy
in the internal batteries.
If Shinji doesn’t waste it groping
blindly in the dark...
...if he stays in the most minimal
life-support mode...
...then he can survive for 16 hours.
Second Tank Battalion deployed.
Roger.  Hold your current
positions and stand by.
Sub laser circuit has been opened.
Transmitting data now.
Confirmed.  New line transmitting data.
The UN forces have completely
surrounded it.
Shadow status?
It hasn’t moved.  It stopped
spreading once it reached a diameter
just over 600 meters.
By the way, is there a use for
those ground troops?
They’re supposed to allow us
to apply pressure.
Oh, well...
Taking matters into his own hands,
defying Operations.  He got what
he was asking for.
Just because he got a little better score
than mine, he had to go and show me
how it ought to be done.
What a dummkopf!
What?  Are my comments about
Shinji pissing you off?
Do you pilot Eva just for
the praise of others?
No!  I don’t need anybody’s
approval but my own!
Cut it out, you two!
Yes, he acted arbitrarily and
without consultation.
So...  I’ll just have to punish him
when he comes back.
I never thought sleeping could
be this exhausting.
Still nothing but white noise...
No radar or sonar reflections at all.
This space must be too big.
It’s been 12 hours since I switched
to life-support mode.
My life will end in four or five hours.
I’m hungry.
So, that shadow is actually
the Angel’s body?
Correct.  It’s 680 meters in diameter with
a thickness of three nanometers.
Sustained within that ultra-thin space
is an inverted AT Field.
Inside that field is a region of space
that can only be defined by abstract
mathematics, a Sea of Dirac.
It could be connected
to another universe.
What about the sphere?
It disappears when the imaginary
circuit of the body closes.
The object in the sky is only a shadow.
So the black shadow that swallowed
Unit 01 is the real target.
Then there’s no way that we can fight it.
The water is getting cloudy!
The purification system is breaking down.
It smells in here...
Blood!  This place smells like blood!
No!  I hate this place!
Why can’t I open this lock?
Open up!  Let me out!
Misato, tell me what’s going on!
Misato!  Asuka!  Ayanami!
Dr. Ritsuko!
Father...
Please...  someone help me.
A forced Eva salvage?
It’s the only possibility that might work.
We would drop all 992 existing
N2 mines into its center...
...while simultaneously activating the
AT Fields of both remaining Evas...
...in such a way as to disrupt the
hypothetical circuit that encloses the
Angel’s pocket interior.
If we concentrate enough explosive
power into the same microsecond...
...we might destroy the Angel along with
the Dirac Sea that makes up its body.
But the damage to the Eva would be...
Shinji wouldn’t...
What kind of rescue operation is this?
This operation’s priority is to
recover the Eva itself.
That the body may be severely damaged
or destroyed in the process
has no bearing.
Now wait a second!
The pilot’s life is not our concern.
If Shinji’s lost, it’s your fault!
Just remember that!
Why are you and Commander Ikari
so worried about Unit 01?
What in the hell is an Eva?
I’ve given you all the information.
You’re lying!
Misato, trust me.
I’m taking command of
this entire operation.
Forward all flights to Kansai International
Airport.  Contact Air Traffic Control and
the air transport divisions of the JADF.
The Second Impact,
the Instrumentality Project, Adam...
There are so many secrets that
I’m in the dark about.
Who’s that?
Who?
Shinji Ikari.
That’s me.
I am you.
This self incorporates another self.
The self has always been composed
of two selves.
Two?
Yes, the self which is observed and the
self which observes itself.
To expound, the Shinji Ikari that exists in
your mind is only one Shinji Ikari...
...there’s also the Shinji Ikari in
Misato Katsuragi’s mind...
...the Shinji Ikari in
Asuka Soryu’s mind...
...the Shinji Ikari in Rei Ayanami’s mind...
...and the Shinji Ikari in
Gendo Ikari’s mind.
All are different Shinji Ikaris...
...but each of them is a true Shinji Ikari.
What you fear are the Shinji Ikaris who
exist in the minds of others.
I’m just afraid of being hated.
You’re afraid of being hurt.
Who is bad?
Father is.
The father who deserted us.
No, I’m the one who’s bad.
You’re always apologizing!  Do you
always think you’re the one at fault?
I’m worthless.
No, you just believe that
you’re worthless.
Don’t you trust your father?
I thought I hated my father,
but now I’m not sure...
Good work, Shinji.
My father called me by my name.
I was praised by my father!
Will you spend your life regurgitating
and re-digesting those few
pleasant memories?
If I trust their words,
it’s enough to keep me alive.
Even though you know you’re
deceiving yourself?
Everybody does it!
That’s how everyone survives!
If you will not believe that you can change
yourself, you will be unable to continue.
This world is filled with too much pain
and suffering to keep going on.
For example, you can’t swim.
Humans aren’t made to float.
That is self-deception.
I don’t care what you want to call it.
You have been shutting your eyes and
ears to that which you wished to avoid.
His sister was injured during the incident.
Who cares what the others say?!
Go away!
No!  I don’t want to hear this!!
See?  You’re running from reality again.
No one can justify their existence
by linking their happiest moments into
a kind of rosary.
In particular, I cannot.
I’ve found something I can do to feel
good.  Something I want to do!
What’s wrong with that?!
In theory, the entry plug’s energy reserves
should be reaching their expiration point.
The plug suit’s life support system will
be getting close to redline.
Advance the schedule by 12 minutes.
Let’s do it while there’s a possibility
that Shinji’s still alive.
Father, am I unwanted?
Father!
It was really yourself that
you ran away from.
That’s right!  He may be guilty
of killing his own wife.
He killed his own wife.
No!  Mother was...
...smiling.
You did a good job.
Shinji, you must not run away.
Do your best.
I hate this place!
I hate this loneliness.
No...
The heating and the oxygen circulation
are already out.
I’m cold.
It’s useless, the suit is giving out, too.
This is the end...
...tired of...
...everything.
Mother?
Is this enough?
Well, that’s good for you.
Evas are in position and standing by.
AT Fields are ready to generate.
Roger.
T-minus 60 seconds to mine drop.
What’s going on?
Status report!
Unknown!
All meters and gauges are
going off the scale!
But we haven’t done anything yet!
No way!  Shinji?
It’s impossible!
Unit 01’s power level has to be at zero!
I...  am I piloting a thing like that?
My God, what kind of monster
have we copied from?
I know that the Evas aren’t just
copies of the First Angel.
But what is NERV going to do with them
once all the Angels have been destroyed?
Shinji?!  Shinji?!  Shinji?!
Shinji?!  Are you all right, Shinji?!
I just wanted to see them again.
Didn’t you say you were going
to punish him?
I’ve never seen the Eva looking as
horrible as it did today.
Are the Evas really on our side?
They may hate us.
I think Major Katsuragi
noticed something.
I see.  Let her be for now.
If Rei or Shinji were to find out the Evas’
secrets, they’d never forgive us.
You can just rest today.
We’ll take care of everything.
But I’m fine now.
Well, that’s good for you.
It still smells like blood.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Eva Unit 04, which was being built in
America, vanishes with NERV’s Second
Branch during its activation experiment.
Commander Ikari remains silent in the
face of this unexpected incident.
SEELE’s old men try to adjust the script...
...and the Fourth Child is selected
on the basis of a vague feeling.
It’s the next episode, “The Fourth Child.”
I’ll give you more fan service, too!
Next Episode:
The 4th Child