Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
Katsuragi, it’s me.  You’re probably
listening to this after I caused
you a lot of trouble.
I’m sorry.
Please tell Ritsuko I’m sorry, too.
There’s one more thing I’d like
to trouble you with.  There are
some melons I was raising.
I’d be happy if you’d take care of
them.  Shinji knows where they are.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Go for it.
If I ever see you again, I’ll say the
words I didn’t eight years ago.
Bye.
Another phone that will never ring...
Misato is shutting herself up...
Asuka’s not coming back, is she?
She doesn’t go to school,
doesn’t go home.
She does nothing but
play video games.
Hikari?
Wh...what is it?
I want to go to bed.
I’m sorry.  I’m causing
you a lot of trouble.
No, not at all.
I lost.  Now, it’s not worth living.
I hate this.  I hate everything.
Most of all, I hate myself.
I don’t find value in
my life anymore.
I think, you can choose to do
anything you want, and I
wouldn’t say anything.
You did your best, Asuka.
So, you haven’t seen her?
Yeah, I think so, too.
The cat has come to the end of her life.
Don’t cry, Grandma.
Yes, I’ll come home as soon as I can.
It’s been three years since I visited
my mom’s grave.
I’ll call you.
Well, I’ll talk to you later.
So, the cat died.
Episode 23:
Tear
Now it’s impossible to recover the
Lance of Longinus.
Why did you use it?
Are you aware that we do not have
enough of the Eva series yet?
Destroying Angels is our top
priority.  This is the fact
we have to face.
Is that it?  You should come up
with a better excuse.
You’re disrespectful to the
committee these days.
Fuyutsuki, we’re in the middle
of deliberations.
I understand.
There is an Angel approaching.
Let us adjourn for now.
Your seat will be waiting for you.
Will Ikari betray SEELE?
I’ll be there in 15 minutes.
Sortie Unit 00 through the 32nd.
Deploy Unit 02 as backup.
Yes, the Commander will direct
Unit 01.  I don’t have the
authority to release it.  Later.
The Angel is sighted...
Unit 00 launched.  Deploying
to interception point.
Hold Unit 02 at its current position.
No, launch it.
Commander?!
Go ahead.  It can be used as a decoy.
Yes, sir.
Eva Unit 02, preparing for launch.
I’m in this thing again.
How irresolute I am.
Send Unit 02 to Gate Eight.  As soon
as a location is designated,
we’ll launch.
I’m just a deadweight for you, right?
Target is approaching and has passed
the Gora Final Interception Line.
Whatever, doesn’t matter.
Target is rotating in the
air over Owakudani.
Target’s AT Field is active.
What were you doing?
I’m sorry.
Status report!
We’re at a stalemate.
The pattern is periodically changing
from blue to orange.
What does that mean?
The MAGI are still working
on the answer.
There is insufficient information for
them to derive an answer.
The only thing we’re sure of is that
this shape is not its only form.
We’ll have to wait and see.
Rei, you have to stay ready.
No, it’s coming.
Rei, fight back!
No, it’s too late!
Target has made physical
contact with Unit 00!
What about Unit 00’s AT Field?
It’s active, but it’s being eroded!
Is the Angel trying to make
first contact with Unit 00?
This is deadly!  Unit 00’s biological
parts are corroding.
Eva Unit 02 launch!
Back Rei up and save her!
Target is eroding Unit 00.
This could be fatal.  The biological
components are already more
than 5% fused.
Asuka, advance 300 meters, spread
your AT Field to maximum, and fire
the Palette Gun into the target’s rear.
You got it?  Eva Unit 02, lift off!
Go ahead!  Asuka, what
are you doing?
Status?!
It’s no good.  Synch ratio is under 10.
Asuka!
It won’t go.  It just won’t go.
She’ll just be destroyed.
Retrieve!  Hurry!
Who is this?
This is you.
Myself in Eva?
No, I sense someone
other than myself.
Who are you?
Angel?  A man who we
call an Angel?
Why don’t we become one?
No, I am me.  Not you.
Okay, but it’s too late.
Let me share my heart with you.
Let me share this feeling with you.
Doesn’t this hurt?
Doesn’t your heart hurt?
Pain?  No, not pain.
Loneliness?
Yes, I’m lonely.
Loneliness?  I don’t understand it.
You don’t want to be by
yourself, correct?
We are many, but you are alone.
You hate it, don’t you?
That is loneliness.
That is your soul.
That is your soul filled with sorrow.
Is this a tear?
Am I the one who is crying?
Rei!
Remove the restraints from Unit 01
and sortie it immediately.
Sortie it.
Yes, sir!
Am I so worthless to you?
You didn’t do this for me.
Spread your AT Field.
Rescue Rei immediately.
Yes!
Ikari?!
Does my soul want to
become one with Ikari?
No!
AT Field has been reversed!
It will be corroded immediately.
Is she going to hold the Angel?
Rei, abandon Unit 00!  Evacuate!
No, I can’t do it.  I must stay to keep
the AT Field in effect.
Therefore, I won’t retreat.
Rei, are you going to kill yourself?
The core will be destroyed!
Critical pressure exceeded!
The target is destroyed.
This operation is officially over.
Go to first stage alert.
Roger!  Changing to status
Yellow immediately.
What is Unit 00’s status?
The entry plug was not ejected.
Rescue the pilot as soon as possible.
If she’s still alive.
Doctor Akagi...
Keep this top secret.  Retrieve the
plug and destroy all the parts.
Roger.
Let’s go!  Hurry up!
3rd Angel
Sachiel
We have destroyed the Sixteenth Angel.
4th Angel
Shamshel
5th Angel
Ramiel
6th Angel
Gaghiel
7th Angel
Israfel
8th Angel
Now there is only one left according
to SEELE’s Dead Sea Scrolls.
Sandalphon
9th Angel
Matarael
10th Angel
Sahaquiel
11th Angel
Ireul
12th Angel
Leliel
13th Angel
Bardiel
The promised day is near.
14th Angel
Zeruel
15th Angel
Arael
16th Angel
Armisael
The way has been long and
our losses are significant.
Right, we lost the Lance of
Longinus and now we’ve
lost Unit 00.
This is sufficient to remove Ikari.
I thought he’d be smart enough to
understand our intentions in
releasing Fuyutsuki.
We have to find another pawn
to use against Ikari.
One who knows the facts.
Shinji, can I come in?
Misato, I don’t have any tears.
I feel sadness,
but the tears won’t come.
Shinji...
...this is all I can do
for you right now.
No, don’t!
Cut it out, Misato!
I’m sorry.
I’m sure he’s feeling lonely.
Is he afraid of women?
No, he’s just afraid of
affection in general.
Pen Pen, come on.
Okay, I just want anybody.
I’m the one who’s lonely.
Yes, hello.
What did you say?!  Shinji!
Ayanami!
I’m glad you’re alive, Ayanami.
My dad isn’t here?
Thank you for saving my life.
What?
Well, you sacrificed Unit 00
to save me.
I see, so did I save you?
Don’t you remember?
No, I don’t know the facts.
Probably because I’m the third one.
Is this a tear?  I’m seeing this for the
first time, but it feels familiar.
Am I crying?
Why am I crying?
That’s right.  Status quo for the First
Child.  No restrictions are necessary.
This applies to the Second and Third
as well.  Just watch them.
But the fact that Rei is alive could
cause trouble with Chairman Keel.
I have given an alternative to
SEELE’s old men.  Don’t
worry about it.
We’d like to carry this out calmly.
We do not want to disgrace you.
I feel no disgrace.
What a strong woman.  I can
see why Ikari wants to keep
her next to him.
However, the one who sent you here
is none other than Ikari himself.
He refused to let us question the
pilot of Unit 00 and sent you as
a substitute, Doctor Akagi.
I’m Rei’s substitute, am I?
This is a part of the truth
you wanted to know.
I sent you the same thing thirty-six
different ways, but most of those
probably won’t reach you.
I suspect only this capsule
will reach you.
This is my everything.
Do with it as you will.
The pass code is our first memory.
Bye, take care.
I have quit worrying about the phone
that will never ring...
...because I have accepted
your heart.
Are you sure about releasing
Doctor Akagi?
She isn’t like Fuyutsuki.  It will
be beneficial to release her.
A woman of importance to the Eva project,
let her be of use to us for a while.
Correct, for the future of mankind.
There were to be eight
Evangelions constructed.
So, there are four more to go.
The disappearance of Tokyo-3 is a
good reason to proceed quickly
with the project.
The promised day shall arrive on the
day the Eva series is complete.
Yes, hello.
Listen.  I’ve released your restraint.
You can come out now.
Ritsuko?
It’s no use without my password.
I see.  Did Kaji do this?
I will see the secret with
my own eyes.
Okay, but with him, too.
I agree.
This is just like Ayanami’s room.
This IS Rei Ayanami’s room.
It’s where she grew up.
This is?
Yes, she was born here.
The light and water that define the
depths of her mind come from
impressions of this place.
Doctor Akagi, I didn’t come
just to see this.
I know, Misato.
An Eva?
The very first one.
But it was a failure.  It was
discarded ten years ago.
An Eva graveyard...
It’s just a trash can.
This is also where your
mother disappeared.
You may not remember it...
...but you were watching when your
mother disappeared.
Ritsuko!
Is this the source of
the dummy plug?
Let me show you the truth.
Rei Ayanami?
Impossible!  Eva’s dummy plug is...
Right, this is the production factory
for the core of the dummy plug.
This is?
These are all dummies.
They are also replacement parts for Rei.
Man found God, and they
tried to pick him up.
For that, man was punished!
That happened fifteen years ago,
and the God they found disappeared.
Then man tried to resurrect God
with his own hands and that’s
how Adam was created.
From Adam, man created what
resembles God Himself.
That is Eva!
So...  are they human?
Yes, they are human.
We put supposedly mindless souls in Eva.
All the souls were salvaged souls.
Rei is the only container that
can hold the souls.
The souls are born only in Rei.
The Chamber of Guf is empty.
These are merely empty containers.
They have no souls.
So, I want to destroy them
because I hate them.
Do you know what the
hell you’re doing?!
Yes, I do.  I’m destroying them.
They’re not men.  They are
things with human form.
But I lost to these dolls!
I couldn’t win him!
I could stand any
humiliation for him.
I don’t care how wretched I become!
But...  but he had chosen...  he chose.
I knew this, but...
I’m an idiot!
Both the mother and the
daughter are idiots!
Kill me if you want to.  I’d rather die.
That will not release
you from agony.
The tragedy of the Eva Project
is its people.
But I am one of them, too.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
The city is gone, his friends have left
and a boy smiles at the
heartbroken Shinji.
The boy’s casual, embracing
smile enchants Shinji.
However, their cruel destiny
has been preordained.
Next episode: “The Last Angel.”
Next Episode:
The Last Angel