Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Momma!  Momma!  They chose me!
I’m an elite pilot!  I’ll defend
mankind!  I’m the best in the world!
I have to keep it a secret, so I’ll
tell only you, Momma!
Everybody is being so nice to me
now, I won’t feel so lonely anymore!
I’m okay now, even without Papa.
So, look!  Look at me!!
Momma!
Synch ratio zero.  I can’t be the
Second Child anymore.  I have
no reason left to live.
Nobody cares about me anymore.
My papa, my momma, nobody cares.
I have no reason left to live.
Are you Asuka Langley Soryu?
The Second Intelligence Division
reports that they have taken the
Second Child into custody.
Really?  It isn’t like them to lose her
in the first place and then to take
seven days to find her.
They must have done so intentionally.
They’re trying to make trouble
for us, aren’t they?
They could be.
The Fifth Child arrives to replace
Asuka today.  This whole thing
is just too convenient.
Rei Ayanami...
There’s a feeling about her.
Almost like...  my mother...
Rei Ayanami...  and my mother...
What are you doing with
them, Father?
Commander Ikari...
Did you know my cat died?  The cat
my grandmother was taking care of?
I hadn’t taken care of it for a long
time, but now I know that I’ll
never see it again.
Why did you destroy
the dummy system?
It wasn’t the dummy system that I
destroyed.  It was Rei.
I’ll ask you once more.
Why did you do it?
I’m not happy anymore, not even
when you make love to me.
Go ahead and do whatever you want
with my body, it’s never
stopped you before!
You disappoint me.
Disappoint?!
You had no hopes or expectations
of me to start with!
I was nothing!  I am nothing!!
Nothing!
What can I do now, Mother?
Asuka, where have you
disappeared to?
But what could I talk to her about?
Could I talk about Ayanami
with her?
Toji, Kensuke...  Their homes were
destroyed and now they’ve left.
Friends...  I don’t have anybody left
whom I could call my friend.
Nobody!
I can’t go see Ayanami again.  I don’t
have the courage to face her.
I don’t even know how to talk or
act around her now.
Asuka...  Misato...  Mother...
What do I do?
What can I do?
Singing is good.
Singing brings joy and revitalizes the
soul.  I think that song is the greatest
achievement of Lilim culture.
Don’t you agree...
...Shinji Ikari?
How do you know my name?
Everyone knows your name.
I don’t mean to sound rude,
but you’re rather ignorant
of your own position.
Really?  And you are?
I am Kaoru, Kaoru Nagisa.  I’m like
you, one of the selected children...
...the Fifth Child.
You’re the Fifth Child?!  You...
Mister Nagisa...
Call me Kaoru, Mister Ikari.
Oh no, you can call me Shinji.
The Fifth Child has just arrived.
Kaoru Nagisa, Kaoru of the
Seashore.  And all of his records
have been erased, just like Rei.
But one record remains.
He was born on the day
Second Impact occurred.
The committee sent him directly to
us.  There must be something else.
The Marduk Report’s file on the
Fifth Child was classified...
...so I hacked into the Intelligence
Department’s computer system.
I can’t believe you did that!
It was worth doing.
I found out where Ritsuko is.
What do you want to do about the
Fifth Child’s synch tests?
I don’t have any tricks up my sleeve
this time.  Let’s see what he can do.
Down another 0.3.
Yes, sir.
Are these data readouts correct?
All testing systems are
operating correctly, sir.
The MAGI confirm that there
are no data errors.
It’s incredible that he can synch
with Unit 02 before we’ve even
configured the core.  He’s amazing.
But this isn’t possible!
On this system it can’t happen.
Nevertheless, it is happening.
We must accept that fact and start
an investigation into why
it’s happening.
You’re the First Child, aren’t you?
Rei Ayanami.
You’re the same as I am.
Who are you?
The Fifth Child has made
contact with Rei.
I see.
The MAGI are currently analyzing the
nature of the Fifth and what
his powers may be.
We still don’t know who
or what he is.
Who in the hell is this boy?
Shinji hasn’t come back yet either.
I’m not deserving of his trust.
Central Dogma is now open.
Please use Route 3 to transfer.
Hi, you weren’t waiting here
for me, were you?
No, well, not really waiting anyway.
So what are you doing?
Well, usually when the tests are
over, I’ll just take a shower
and go home.
But I don’t really want to
go home these days.
The fact that you have a place where
you can return, a home, will lead
you to happiness.  That’s good.
You think so?
I’d like to talk some more.
May I come with you?
To the shower.
Aren’t you going now?
Or do you mind?
Oh, no, I don’t mind.
You are extremely afraid
of first contact.
Are you that scared of affection?
If you don’t get close to others,
you won’t be betrayed and
you won’t hurt each other.
However, neither will you
forget what loneliness is.
Man can never make loneliness
disappear because man is alone,
but man can forget.
So, man can find the will to live.
It’s time.
Is this it?
I have to go to bed.
With me?
No, you have your own
room, I think.
Right...
Man always has pain in his heart.
Since his heart feels pain,
he experiences life as pain.
You are delicate like glass.
Am I?
Yes, and that earns my sympathy.
Sympathy?
In other words, I like you.
Episode 24
The Last Angel
NERV was formed as SEELE’s
executive branch.
It was created to carry
out our scenario.
However, it has been taken
over by a selfish man.
Yes, it has.  We must return
it to our control.
Before the promised day.
We must restore NERV and the Eva
series to their original purpose.
Ikari will answer to SEELE
for his malfeasance.
It will not be much longer.
The Lance of Longinus that was
hindering our wish is gone forever.
The last Angel should appear soon
and our wish will be attained upon
destroying that Angel.
Soon, very soon, Yui.
Why am I here?
Why am I still alive?
For what purpose?
For whose purpose?
The Fifth Child...
In what way are he and I alike?
Why?
I am glad this apartment is in the
suburbs.  Thank God you were safe.
But there is no guarantee
this won’t happen again.
So, the Horaki family will take care
of you starting tomorrow.
I won’t be able to see you
for a while, Pen Pen.
I think I should sleep on the floor.
No, I am staying at your place.
I should sleep down here.
What do you want to talk about?
You want me to listen to
you, don’t you?
Many things have happened since
I came here.
I used to live with my teacher.
They were calm and boring days.
I was just living...
But I was fine with that!
There was really nothing I had to do.
Do you hate people?
Not really, I don’t care.
But I hate my dad.
Why did I tell Kaoru that?
I was probably born to meet you.
Did you get his data?
This is it.  I got this from Ibuki
without her knowledge.
I’m sorry that I made you do this.
What is this?
No wonder Maya can’t reveal this.
This is not theoretically possible!
You’re right.  The issue gets
even more mysterious.
How can he fix the synch ratio at
whatever point he wishes?
I have to take another chance.
What a surprise to see you here.
I have a question for you.
Our conversation is monitored here.
I don’t care.
What is the boy, the Fifth Child?
He is probably the last Angel.
Well, let’s go.  Come, Adam’s alter
ego and Lilith’s minion.
Eva Unit 02 is activating!
That’s impossible!  Where’s Asuka?
She’s in room 303!
I’ve just confirmed it!
Then who the hell is piloting it?!
It is unmanned!  There is no entry
plug inserted in Unit 02!
Unmanned?  So, the Fifth
Child is not there?
AT Field detected in
Central Dogma!
Is it Unit 02?
No, the blood pattern is blue!
It’s definitely an Angel!
What the hell?!
That boy?  An Angel?
Target has passed the Fourth Layer
and is still descending.
It’s no good!  We can’t cut the
power to the linear carriage!
Target has passed the Fifth Layer.
Close all Central Dogma shutters!
Buy us some time!
Closing all shutters immediately.
All personnel evacuate.
Unbelievable, SEELE itself
sent an Angel to us.
The old men want to advance
another step with our help.
The last Angel has invaded Central
Dogma.  It is currently descending.
Just as we planned.
Ikari, you were our good friend,
our comrade and conspirator,
but this is your last job.
I expect that you will use Unit 01
to accomplish the mission.
Unit 02 has penetrated
the armored shutters!
Target has passed the second wall.
Pursue it with Unit 01.
Yes, sir!
Use any means to keep it from
invading Terminal Dogma.
But why did the Angel take Unit 02?
Is it going to fuse with Unit 02?
Or is it going to bring destruction?
Lie!  Lie!  It’s a lie!!  I don’t believe
that Kaoru is an Angel!  It’s a lie!
This is a fact, face it.  Sortie.
You got it?
Shinji is late.
Eva Unit 01 is descending via
Route 2.  Pursuing the target.
You betrayed me!
You hurt my feelings!
You betrayed me just like
my father did!!
Unit 01 has reached the Fourth
Layer.  It’s about to confront
the target!
There he is!
I have been waiting for you, Shinji.
Kaoru!
I’m sorry, Asuka!
The Eva series were born from
Adam.  The entire human race
must abhor their existence.
Lilim try to survive even if it
means taking advantage of
the thing they hate.
I do not understand this.
Kaoru, stop this!
Why are you doing this?!
Eva is created from the
same tissue as I am.
I am also born from Adam.
So I can synchronize with it as
easily as if it had no soul.
Unit 02’s soul is now
shutting itself up.
An AT Field?!
Yes, that’s what you
Lilim call this.
This is the light of the soul,
sacred territory where no
one should intrude.
Don’t you Lilim know?
Everybody has an AT Field.
I don’t understand what
you’re talking about!
Both Evas have reached
the deepest layer.
Target is 20 meters away from
Terminal Dogma.
If Unit 01’s signal disappears and
then any change occurs...
I know; self-destruct
the entire complex.
It’s better than letting the
Third Impact occur.
I’m sorry.
I don’t mind it if it’s with you.
Thank you.
It is human fate.  Human hope
is made with sorrow.
What is this?!
The strongest AT Field ever
has been detected!
It’s shutting out everything!  Light,
magnetism, sub-atomic particles!
We can’t monitor anything!!
This is absolutely impossible!
Signals from the target, Unit 02
and Unit 01 are lost!  We’ve lost
communication with the pilot!
Kaoru!
Wait!!
Final safety system released!
Heaven’s Door is opening!
The Angel has finally reached it.
Hyuga...
What is this?
What’s going on?!
Another AT Field!
A field as strong as the first one has
appeared around Terminal Dogma!
It’s invading the other AT Field!
Impossible!  Is it another Angel?!
I don’t know!  I can’t confirm it!
God!  It just disappeared!
Disappeared?  The Angel has?
Adam...
...our mother.  One who is born from
Adam must return to Adam.
Although it could destroy
all humanity?
No!  This is...  Lilith?
I see.  I understand Lilim.
Thank you, Shinji.
I wanted you to stop Unit 02.
Otherwise I would survive with her.
Kaoru, why?
Because it is my destiny to live
although it would bring
destruction to humanity.
I would prefer to die here.  Life
and death are equal to me.
Death of the self, that is the
only absolute freedom.
What are you?
I don’t understand what
you’re talking about!
That is my will.
Now, destroy me.
Otherwise you will be destroyed.
Only one life form can be chosen to
evade the destruction and
inherit the future.
And you are not the existence
that should die.
You need the future.
Thank you, my life was meaningful
because of you.
Kaoru said he liked me.
I have never...  never had
such kind words.
He was like me, and like Ayanami.
I liked him, too.
Kaoru should have survived.
He was much better than I am.
No, the one who survives is the one
who has the will to survive.
He wished for death.  He neglected
his will to survive and chose
a false hope.
You are not wrong.
How can you be so cruel?
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
The last Angel is gone,
but Shinji is anguished.
Misato and Asuka, too, reveal their
mind and they ask people for hope...
...while accepting facts as
a kind of end.
Next episode: “The Ending World.”
Next Episode:
The Ending World