Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
Apotheosis for the three Evas will be
performed as soon as the MAGI
system is reactivated.
Operation confirmed.
Steps 450–670 are omitted.
Command has granted approval.
You’re fast, Maya, that’s what
makes you you!
Of course, I am.  You trained me.
Wait a second, A-8 would be faster there.
Let me do that.
Well, she was my teacher...
Hey, how’s it going?  Are you finished
giving the MAGI their checkup?
Almost done.  As promised, it’ll be
finished before today’s experiment begins.
You’re something else, Ritsuko.
You’ve got three nearly impossible
tasks to handle, and you still manage to
beat the schedule.
That one’s cold.
All three MAGI systems have entered
self-diagnostic mode.
The 127th routine maintenance
has been completed.
Confirmed.  Well done, guys.
Take a break until the test begins.
Everything checked out.
As usual, Mother’s in good shape, but...
Is it just me getting older?
Episode 13:
Angel Invasion
What?!  You want me to take
off my clothes again?
The next chamber is an
ultra-clean room environment.
Just taking a shower and changing your
undergarments is insufficient.
Why do I have to go through all this
for a simple autopilot test?
With the advance of time, Eva
technology needs to advance as well.
To do so, we need a constant
influx of new data.
What?!
All right, I’m here, just the way you wanted.
Butt naked and run through
the wash cycle 17 times.
Now, I want all three of you to stay that
way as you walk through the room and
board the entry plug.
Whaaaat?!
Don’t worry.  The video recorders
have been shut off.
We do respect your privacy.
That isn’t the point!
This is a very personal thing!
The purpose of this experiment
is to remove the interference from
your plug suits...
...and monitor the harmonics directly
from your bodies.
Asuka, that’s an order.
All right!  But I don’t want
anybody peeking, okay?
All pilots are ready for entry.
Start the test.
Beginning the test.
Initiate autopilot recording.
Inserting simulation plug.
Connecting the simulation
bodies to the systems.
The simulation plugs are now
under the MAGI’s control.
Wow, that was really fast.
The MAGI are magnificent!
It’s hard to believe that the first
experiment took a whole week.
According to the schedule,
the test will end in three hours.
How do you feel?
It feels odd.
Yeah, it’s different from the other times.
Something’s wrong with my senses.
My right arm’s the only thing I can feel
clearly, everything else is fuzzy.
Rei, imagine moving your right hand.
Yes, ma’am.
Data collection is proceeding nicely.
Everything seems good so far.
Return the MAGI to their normal state.
A dilemma...
You can sure feel the creator’s
personality, can’t you?
What are you talking about?  You’re
the one who created them, aren’t you?
You don’t know anything, do you?
That’s because you never talk about
yourself like I do, Ritsuko!
That’s true.  I just created
the system uplinks.
The person who developed the basic
theorems and the mainframe...
...was my mother.
Are you double-checking this?
Yes, I am.
These are the parts that were
brought in three days ago.
These are the parts that are showing
signs of deterioration.
The 87th protein wall.
With magnification,
you can see some spots.
Can you tell me what it is?
It’s got to be corrosion.
There are slight variations
in the temperature and conduction
rates of the spots.
Deterioration of sterilized rooms
happens a lot, an awful lot, as of late.
The construction schedule was
cut by about 60 days.
It’s possible that some air bubbles
may have gotten inside.
There are a lot of flaws in the
construction of Wing B.
This building was constructed after the
Angels appeared, remember?
You can’t really put the blame
on anyone; everybody was
so exhausted back then.
Take care of it by tomorrow.
Otherwise, Ikari will be jumping all
over our asses for it.
Understood.
Another water leak?
No, it’s some kind of corrosion in the
protein wall above this floor.
Wonderful.
Could it have any effect on this test?
No, not at the moment.
Then let’s continue.
We can’t abort complex experiments
due to minor technical problems.
Otherwise, Commander Ikari will be
jumping all over our asses for it.
Understood.
Synchronization position is correct.
Connecting the simulation entry plugs to
the Evas via the simulation bodies.
Contact with Eva Unit 00
has been confirmed.
AT Field will be generated on two.
What’s happening?!
We’ve got a contamination alert
in the Sigma Unit on Floor A!
The 87th protein wall is corroding
and releasing heat!
We’ve detected an abnormality
in the 6th pipe as well!
Corrosion of the protein wall is
increasing at an incredible rate!
Abort the experiment!
Shut off the 6th pipe!
Right!
Numbers 60, 38 and 39 are all closed!
Corrosion has occurred in 6-42!
No effect!  Corrosion is spreading
along the walls!
Prepare the polysomes.
Set laser power at maximum!
Shoot the invasive particles!
Corrosion has reached 6-58!  It’s here!
Rei!
Rei’s simulation body is moving!
Impossible!
The corrosion is still spreading!
It’s invading the simulation bodies’
active water system!
How’s Rei?!
She’s all right!
Eject all plugs immediately!
Hurry up with that laser!
An AT Field?!
Impossible!
What?
The pattern analysis is blue!
There’s no question, it’s an Angel!
An Angel?!
You let an Angel get inside?
I’m sorry, sir.
This isn’t the time for excuses!
I want a physical shutdown of Central
Dogma!  Isolate it from Sigma Unit!
Initiating physical shutdown of Central
Dogma.  Isolating from Sigma Unit.
Abandon unit!  Evacuate immediately!
Initiating physical shutdown of Central
Dogma.  Isolating from Sigma Unit.
Abandon unit!  Evacuate immediately!
What the hell are you doing?  Hurry!
Isolating Sigma Unit from Floor B.
Closing all partitions.
All personnel in the area must evacuate.
I know.  Please take care of it.
Stop the alert.
S...stopping the alarm, sir.
This is a malfunction.
An error in the alarm system.
Report that to both the Japanese
government and the committee.
Y...yes, sir!
The contaminated area is
still descending.
It’s spreading all over Sigma Unit
from the Pribnow Box!
That’s a critical area.
Yes, it’s too close to Adam.
Stop the corrosion within Sigma Unit!
If necessary, sacrifice the Geo-Front.
What’s the Evas’ status?
Ready in the 7th cage.
We can launch them as soon as the
pilots are recovered.
There’s no need to wait for the pilots.
Launch them immediately!
Launch Unit 01 first.
Sacrifice the other two if necessary.
Unit 01 has top priority?
But sir, we can’t destroy the
Angel without the Evas.
If the Evas are contaminated first,
we’ll be finished!  Hurry!
Roger!
All of Central Dogma under Sigma Unit
will be shut down in 60 seconds.
So, that’s the Angel.
All of Central Dogma under Sigma Unit
will be shut down in 60 seconds.
So, that’s the Angel.
Thirty seconds until activation
of vacuum pump.
Time to take a break.
Thirty seconds until activation
of vacuum pump.
Central Dogma has been
completely sealed.
Mega-depth facilities are all
occupied by the intruder!
Well now, how will we mount an
offensive against an Angel
without an Eva?
Look, this is the border between
the normal and heavy water.
There’s a higher level of oxygen here.
Their preference is pretty obvious.
The place where ozone is vented in
to maintain aseptic conditions
isn’t contaminated.
So, does that mean ozone is its weakness?
It would seem so.
Injecting ozone.
Ozone concentration is increasing.
It’s working, all right.
Will this work?
Zero A and Zero B seem
to be recovering.
The area around the pipes is
getting back to normal.
The center portion is proving
a little more difficult.
All right, inject more ozone.
This isn’t right.
What?  It’s increasing?
Something is wrong.
Heat levels are increasing!
The contaminated area is
spreading again!
The ozone is no longer
having any effect.
Now it’s absorbing the ozone!
Stop the ozone injection!!
Amazing...
It’s evolving.
What’s wrong?
Something’s hacking into the
sub-computer.  The intruder hasn’t
been identified.
Not now!  Dealing with C-Mode!
Unfreeze the barrier.  Open a decoy entry.
Decoy entry has been avoided.
T-minus 18 seconds to
completion of trace.
Spreading barrier!
Barrier has been penetrated!
Open another false entry!
No human being could do this.
The trace is complete.
The hacker is inside this facility!
It’s in Wing B, in the Pribnow Box!
Optical pattern is changing!
Those glowing lines look like electronic
circuits!  This is just like a computer!
Opening decoy entry!
It failed!  There’s interference!
Cut off the main cable!
Negative, it refuses to accept
the command!
Fire the laser!!
It’s generating an AT Field!  No effect!
It’s accessing the main security bank!
It’s cracking the pass code.
12th digit...  16th digit...
D-Word has been cleared!
It’s broken into the main banks!
It’s reading the main bank!
We can’t stop it!
What does it want?
Scanning the main directories.
This code is...  my God!
It’s going after the MAGI!
Shut down the I/O system!
Countdown!
3...
2...
One!
We can’t shut it down!
The Angel is intruding further
into the computers!
It’s made contact with Melchior!
It’s no good!
The Angel is taking over Melchior!
Melchior is being re-programmed
by the Angel!
Melchior’s self-destruct
has been initiated.
Overruled.  Overruled.  Overruled.
Overruled.
Melchior is hacking into Balthasar!
Overruled.  Overruled.  Overruled.
Overruled.
Melchior is hacking into Balthasar!
Damn, it’s too fast!!
What calculation speed!
Change the logic mode!
Change synchronization code to
every 15 seconds!
Roger!
How much time did we buy?
At least two hours, I think.
The MAGI have become our enemy.
This Angel must be composed of
a group of micromachines,
each the size of a virus.
These micromachines group
together to form colonies.
In a very short period of time,
they have exponentially evolved to form
a sophisticated intelligence circuit.
Evolved...
Yes...
They’re continuously changing...
...to form the best system to cope
with any environment.
That’s their survival mechanism
as a life form.
Against an enemy that constantly
evolves to overcome its weaknesses...
...the only effective countermeasure
is to eliminate the host and let
the parasite die with it.
The only option is to order the
MAGI to commit suicide.
I propose the physical elimination
of the MAGI.
That’s impossible.
Destroying the MAGI means destroying
headquarters itself.
Then, I’m officially requesting it on
behalf of the Operations Division.
I reject it.
This is a matter for the
Technology Department.
Why are you being so mule-headed?!
This situation is a result of
my carelessness.
Why do you always have
to be like this?
You’re always taking all the
responsibility on your own shoulders...
...and avoiding depending on anyone.
As long as this Angel keeps evolving,
we have a chance.
Expedite its evolution?
Yes...
The end of evolution is self-destruction...
death itself.
Thus, we just need to accelerate
its evolution.
If the Angel considers it the only
practical means of survival...
...it may choose to coexist with
the MAGI system.
But how?
If the Angel is a computer itself...
...we can reverse-hack by connecting
Casper to the Angel...
...and uploading a self-destruct
program, but...
...at the same time, we’ll be turning off
the barrier to the Angel.
So, either Casper or the Angel,
whichever is faster, will win.
Yes...
Will the program be ready in time?
If Casper is taken over first,
it’ll all be over.
I keep my promises.
Red alert!  Red alert!
An emergency has occurred
in NERV Headquarters.
All D-class personnel must evacuate.
Wh...what are those?
These are notes by the developer.
My gosh!  These are access codes!
MAGI’s access codes!
It’s like a special map to all of the
MAGI’s back doors!
Ikari, you idiot!
Am I allowed to see these?
I can’t believe it!  These are in INT-C!
With these we can program much
faster than we thought!
Thank you, Mom.  We can make it.
Give me the wrench.
Doesn’t this remind you of
our college days?
Now, board number 25.
Hey, why don’t you tell me something
about the MAGI?  Just a little?
It’s a long story.
A long, boring story.
Do you know about the
personality transplant OS?
It’s for implanting an individual’s
personality into a seventh generation
computer so it can think for itself.
The same technology is used for
operating the Evas.
I’ve heard that the MAGI’s
programming used one of the
first test subjects.
My mother developed the technology...
So, it was her personality that
was transplanted?
Right!
In a very real sense,
these brains are my mother.
Is that why you wanted to
protect the MAGI?
I don’t think so.
I didn’t really like my mom.
This was a decision as a scientist.
It’s starting!
Balthasar is being taken over!
The self-destruct sequence has been
initiated by the computer.
Has it begun yet?!
Self-destruct will be triggered 20
seconds after all three AI consent.
The area of destruction will be geoid
depth -280, -140 and Floor 0.
Special Command 582 requires the consent
of two computers to cancel the action.
Balthasar is now invading Casper!
Special Command 582 requires the consent
of two computers to cancel the action.
It’s faster than us!
Special Command 582 requires the consent
of two computers to cancel the action.
What speed!
T-minus 20 to self-destruct.
My God!
Casper will be taken over
in 18 seconds!
T-minus 15 to self-destruct.
Ritsuko, hurry!
No problem.  I’ve got almost one
whole second to spare.
T-minus 10 to self-destruct.
Only one?!
9...
At least it’s not a zero or a minus.
8...
7...
6...
Maya!
We can do it!!
5...
4...
3...
2...
Hit it!
1...
Zero.
Self-destruct has been canceled
by the computer.
All right!
Special Command 582
is also canceled.
The MAGI are returning to
normal mode.
The red alert has been canceled.
All hands return to first stage alert.
What’s going on outside?
Jesus!  I can’t get out with
no clothes on!
Somebody, help me fast!
Sigma Unit has been released.
T-minus 03 to MAGI reactivation.
I’m getting old.  Staying up for
these all-nighters is rough.
You kept your promise again.
Good job.
Thank you.
This is the first time I’ve ever really
appreciated your coffee.
The night before she died, my mother
told me that the MAGI are three
aspects of herself.
Herself as a scientist...
Herself as a mother...
Herself as a woman...
Those three aspects of her
are struggling for dominance inside
the MAGI.
She intentionally implanted the
dilemmas of the human
experience into them.
Actually, each of the three programs
are slightly different as well.
I don’t think I’ll ever be a mother, and I
don’t really understand her as a mother.
I respected her as a scientist.
However, as a woman, I hated her.
You’re rather talkative today.
Only sometimes.
Casper contains the program
of her as a woman.
She stayed a woman to the last.
How totally like my mother...
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
SEELE is the secret organization that
manipulates both NERV and the
Human Instrumentality Project.
Together, with Ikari, they verify the
events of both the past and present.
Are the Angel attacks and Ikari’s
behavior actually reenactments of the
Dead Sea Scrolls?
Is every phenomenon simply following
a prescribed scenario?
Is human hope even projected?
It’s the next episode,
“SEELE, Throne of Souls.”
And there’ll be more fan
service next time, too!
Next Episode:
SEELE, Throne
of Souls