Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Are you ready, Shinji?
Yes.
Release the final safety lock!
Evangelion Unit 01, lift off!
Shinji, just concentrate on
walking right now.
Walk...
It walked!
Shinji, are you okay?
Hurry!  Get up!
Shinji, calm down!  That’s not your arm!!
What’s going on with the Eva’s
defense system?!
The signal’s not working!
The field’s not unfolding!
Have we failed?
Left arm damaged!!
The circuits have snapped!
Shinji, dodge!
There’s a crack on the front
of the brain case!
The armor won’t last any longer!
The head’s been damaged!  Extent
of damage, unknown!
The control nerves are breaking off!
We’re not getting any readings
on the pilot!
Shinji!!!
This ceiling is unfamiliar.
Episode 2:
Unfamiliar Ceiling
So, the Angels have returned, eh?
It’s so sudden.
It’s the same as it was fifteen years ago.
A disaster comes as it will,
without warning.
On the positive side, our previous
investments will not go to waste.
You can’t be sure about that yet.
If it doesn’t pay off, it’s a waste
all the same.
Correct.  Now that the Angels have
become common knowledge...
...we have to manipulate the
information to avoid trouble.
NERV must take care of
these matters quickly.
It’s already been taken care of.
You may rest assured of that.
In regards to the declaration of the
state of emergency, government
officials have announced...
This incident was...
UN force in Japan...
Public scenario B-22, just
like we thought.
In response to the reporters’ questions...
No, there’s no threat of contamination
from the center of the explosion.
So, we’re hushing up the truth again?
No, there’s no threat of contamination
from the center of the explosion.
But at least our public relations
people are thrilled...
No, there’s no threat of contamination
from the center of the explosion.
But at least our public relations
people are thrilled...
The only Angel samples collected
were adhered to the Eva.
...now that they’ve finally got
something to do.
The only Angel samples collected
were adhered to the Eva.
We’re being pretty casual about it.
The only Angel samples collected
were adhered to the Eva.
We’re being pretty casual about it.
Correct, as in the model simulation,
approximately 99.9% of it evaporated.
I don’t think so.  Actually, I think
we’re all scared to death.
Correct, as in the model simulation,
approximately 99.9% of it evaporated.
Of course we are.
Well, we must acknowledge that.
Speaking of which, Mr. Ikari, isn’t there
a better way to utilize NERV and Eva?
We’re referring to the repair costs for
Unit 01, which when added to the
costs for Unit 00...
...are enough to bankrupt
an entire country.
We also understand that you gave that
particular toy to your son, did you not?
Manpower... time... and money...
How much more will be wasted by you
and your family?
And that is not your only responsibility.
Top Secret
Human Instrumentality Project
United Nations Supreme Council
Seventeenth Interim Report
Human Instrumentality Committee
Project Outline, 2015 AD, Summary
The Human Instrumentality Project...
...that should be your top priority.
Correct.
Under these desperate circumstances,
that project is our only hope.
Do you understand?
In any case, the Angel is no excuse for
delaying that project’s schedule.
However, we will consider
adjusting the budget.
Now, the rest of this meeting
concerns only us.
Your presence here was
appreciated, Mr. Ikari.
Ikari, you do understand there can
be no turning back, don’t you?
I know.
Mankind has no time left.
Danger
Air conditioning has just got to be
mankind’s greatest treasure.  It’s the
triumph of science over nature.
Shinji’s woken up.
And... how is he?
No external injuries.  His memory is a
bit muddled, however.
You don’t think it could
be brain damage?
The doctor said that there was
nothing to worry about.
Really?
I suppose.  He did have a
pretty hectic day.
His cranial nerves must have
taken a lot of strain.
Don’t you mean... his heart?
Notification of Construction
Building: Guided weapon systems building #25.
Location: 4-75-1-90 Ta, Tokyo-3
Site area: 192.68
All area: 261.05
Structure: Steel Frame Construction Foundation
Work: Piling
Story: 8 stories up, 2 under ground
Start Construction: November 2014
Completion: August 2015
Builder: The Tokyo-3 Build Dept, 1st Division.
Designer: The Tokyo-3 Tech. Research Center.
Use: Secret
Building area: 107.41
Height: 22.65m
Actual Constructor:
Classified
Okay, go on.
Yeah, that way.  Stop.
If Eva and this city both operate at
their full potential, maybe we can
make it through this.
Are you going to defeat the Angels?
You’re always such an optimist.
Hey, sometimes you need a little wishful
thinking just to keep on living.
I see your point.  Your attitude makes
me feel a little more at ease.
See ya!
First Cranial Nerve Division
Dr. Ugai, Internal
Department 1...
Dr. Ugai, Internal Department 1, please
call Dr. Azuma of the 1st Surgical
Department immediately.
The medical conference on the B
experiment will be held as scheduled.
All supervisors please proceed to
conference room 2.
Are you sure?
They don’t want to live together?
I think that living apart is natural for
Ikari and his son.
And being together is unnatural?
Residence Registration
6-24 District-F Geo-Front, Tokyo-3
Ikari Shinji 0001-137-2
Alone?
Right.  His room will be in the 6th
block, just beyond this one.
Is that satisfactory?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Shinji...
It’s fine.  Being alone is
okay with me.
I’m alone anyway.
Whaaaat?!
So, I said, I’ll take care of Shinji.
I’ve already got permission
from the brass.
Hey, it’s not like I’m going to
“put the moves” on him.
Of course you’re not!
How could you even think of
such a thing?
You’re always like that.  Shame on you!
She just can’t take a joke.
Well, we’ll have to have a
party tonight, huh?
What for?
What for?  A welcoming party for my
new roommate, of course!
100% Beef, Ramen,
Pork-flavor Super Cup, Lawson
So, you’re going to move after all?
Yes.  I’d never have dreamt that this city
would become a battlefield.
Yeah...
My husband’s saying that our kid and I
should move, at the very least.
Don’t I know it.
This city may be a fortress, but that’s
no guarantee of safety.
Just remembering it gives me the chills.
Really.
I hope you don’t mind if we make
a little stop on the way.
Where?
Someplace really cool.
So desolate.  This city seems so lonely.
It’s time.
Cool!  The buildings are growing!
This city is a fortress, designed
to protect from the Angels.
This is Tokyo-3...
This is our city.
And... it’s the city that you saved.
Your things should have already
been delivered, Shinji.
I just moved into this apartment, too.
Come on in.
Pardon... the intrusion...
Shinji...  this is your home now.
I’m...  I’m home...
Welcome home.
Um, as you can see, the place is a
little bit messy...
Make yourself comfortable.
You call this...
...a “little bit” messy?
Oh!  Sorry!  Could you put
the food in the fridge?
Uh... sure.
Ice...
Snacks...
And tons of beer...
What kind of a life does she lead?
Excuse me... what’s in the other fridge?
Oh, don’t mind that.  He’s
probably still sleeping!
Sleeping?
Let’s eat!
Let’s eat...
Life just doesn’t get any
better than this!
Don’t you want to eat?  It’s good,
even if it is all instant.
I’m sorry, I’m just not used to it.
That’s no excuse!  You can’t
be so finicky.
No... that’s not what I... uh, well...
Isn’t this nice?
Having two for dinner instead of
eating alone!
Uh... yeah.
Here we go.
Let’s go for the next one.
Paper, stone and scissors...
Pon!  Pon!  Pon!  Pon!
Sorry, Shinji.
Okay!  That was a pretty fair way of
splitting our daily chores, right?
Our Chore Schedule
Breakfast
Dinner
Yeah...
This is your home now, so make yourself
comfortable and take advantage of
everything here... except me.
Y... yes.
Man... “Yes, yes, yes”... is that all you
say?  It’s getting on my nerves.
You’re a boy, aren’t you?
Act like a man!  Okay?
Y... yes.
Okay, that’s just the way you are.
Well, why don’t you go take a bath and
scrub away those bad memories.
Bathing cleanses both the
mind and soul.
M... M... Miss Misato!!
What?
A p... p... p...
Oh, him?  He’s one of those new
warm water penguins.
Th... th... that was a what?
His name is Pen Pen.  He’s your
other roommate.
Why don’t you cover that up?
I guess I’m not being as nice
as I ought to...
Of course, he’s probably already made
up his mind about me.
Misato Katsuragi.
She’s not a bad person.
Bathing cleanses both the
mind and soul.
But bad memories always seem to
find me when I’m in the bath.
Like my father...
...and Rei Ayanami.
So, how was Rei today?
You did see her at the hospital this
afternoon, didn’t you?
She’ll be ready to work again
in twenty days.
By then, we’ll be ready to reactivate
Unit 00 from cryostasis.
It’s so hard on these poor children.
There is no one else who
can pilot the Evas.
As long as they survive, that is
what I’ll have them do.
With no regard to what they may want?
Shinji’s Lovely Suite
City Junior High School #1
Transfer Admission
Shinji Ikari
Yeah, after all the horrible stuff he went
through, I doubt that he’ll pilot it again.
Maintaining him is part of
your job, Misato.
I’m just scared.  I don’t know how
to deal with him.
Grumbling already?  It was your idea
to take him in, you know.
Shut up!!
I was just thinking of Shinji as a tool...
I’m as shameless as Ritsuko.
We destroyed the Angel...
...so why can’t I be happy about it?
Another unfamiliar ceiling.
Of course.  In this whole city, there’s
no place that’s familiar.
This is your home.
Why am I here?
The brain case has been damaged!
Extent of damage unknown!
We’re having problems
maintaining activation!
Status report!
The Synchrograph is reversing!
The pulses are flowing backward!
Break the circuit!  Block it!
We can’t!!
It’s not accepting the signal!
It won’t take it!
What about Shinji?
His monitors aren’t responding.
His condition’s unknown!!
Unit 01’s gone completely silent!!
Misato!!
We’ve got to stop this...
Abort the operation!  Rescuing the
pilot is our first priority!
Eject the entry plug!
We can’t!  It’s completely
out of control!!
No way!
The Eva’s reactivating!
Impossible!  How could this happen?!
Impossible...!
A berserker...?
It looks like we’ve won.
An AT Field!
No!  As long as the Angel has that
AT Field up...
...he can’t get near the Angel!
The left arm has been
regenerated!
Incredible!
Unit 01’s expanding an AT
Field of its own!
It’s neutralizing the phase space!
No, not neutralizing, it’s eroding it!
Unbelievable!  It went through that
AT Field so easily...
No!  It’s going to self-destruct!
Is the Eva...?
That must be the Eva’s...
...true form.
Circuits reconnected.
Systems restored.  Graphs
back to normal.
Pilot life signs, confirmed.
Send out the recovery team.  Hurry!
Preserving the pilot’s life is
our first priority.
Shinji... can I come in?
I forgot to tell you something...
You did a very good thing today.
You should be proud of yourself.
Good night, Mister Shinji.
Hang in there.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Training as an Eva pilot.
A new life with Misato.
Shinji, who passes his life without
having himself, would surely never
have a friend.
But when it’s revealed that he’s a
pilot, he becomes a hero.
Shinji becomes embarrassed and
one boy bullies him.
Next episode:
“The Phone That Never Rings.”
I’ll give you something special again.
Next Episode:
The Phone That
Never Rings