Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
The fiction has become the reality.
How ironic, that the experiment’s
advocate became its victim.
So, you believe that the contact
experiment was the direct cause?
Her mental breakdown was
a result of the contact.
Even so, this is too cruel,
committing suicide and leaving such
a young girl behind.
Perhaps, but I believe that there may have
been some additional causes.
Asuka darling, Mama cooked your
favorite for you.
Oh, no, you have to eat this or
that girl will laugh at you.
She’s like that every day.
She just sits there, talking to that doll
as if it were her real daughter.
I think it’s because of the guilt
she must feel.
She devoted her entire life to her research,
not to taking care of her own daughter.
I sympathize with your grief.
But, it’s like looking at porcelain figures
of a mother and her child.
Perhaps there really isn’t much difference
between humans and dolls.
Man creates dolls in his own image.
If God exists, it’s possible that we’re
all just dolls to him.
Saying things like that doesn’t make you
sound like much of a modern physician.
I may be a doctor, but I’m a human
being and a woman, first.
The Medical Staff conference on the
E Incident will be held as planned.
All senior staff should report to
Conference Room 2.
You’re a strong girl, Asuka,
but it’s all right if you want to cry.
I’m okay.  I won’t cry.
I can think for myself.
Can you hear me, Asuka?  Your synch
ratio has dropped an entire eight points.
Don’t think about anything else,
just concentrate the way you used to.
I’m trying!
Episode 22:
At Least,
Be Humane
Asuka’s synch ratio is getting
lower and lower.
This is extremely troublesome.
We don’t have a spare now.
Maybe we’d better make repairing
Rei’s Unit 00 top priority.
We can’t afford to repair them
both at the same time.
Mitosis process in the left arm of Unit 02
has cleared the numerical requirement.
Necrosis development is
currently under 0.05%.
Apotheosis process is in nominal status.
Unit 00’s regeneration process
currently stable.
Connecting receptors to the
secondary terminals.
The Eva series was born from Adam.
Now we’re using the force which caused
the Second Impact to defeat the Angels.
Attempting to harness the engine
of our own destruction...
...only humans are so foolish.
After all, I myself hate the Evas.
Revenge for my father?!
Major Katsuragi!
They’ve started construction on
Evas up through Unit 13?
At seven different locations
around the world?
This information came via Shanghai.
The source is reliable.
Why are they speeding up the
construction process now?
Well, we’ve lost two Evas recently,
and two more Evas are currently
severely damaged.
So I’d assume that they’re accelerating
to create a reserve force for their
contingency plans.
Perhaps...
...but we’ve been receiving spare parts
from Germany that were originally
intended for Evas Units 05 and 06.
They’ve been spending a lot of cash lately.
They just doubled the budget.  I think the
brass are being driven by something.
Yeah, I can feel
the committee’s impatience.
Well, could they be doing this
in anticipation of intercepting multiple
Angels at once?
Could be...
...except that there’s no reason for them to
do it outside of official channels.
There must be some other reason.
This is the first time all three of us have
gotten together in a while, so what’s with
the gloomy atmosphere?
I’m finished.
Asuka!
I’m not getting it.  After all, it’s probably
Kaji calling for Misato.  You should get it.
Never again...
Oh no, I’m sorry that our mighty invincible
Shinji should have to be bothered
with such a thing.
Yes, hello?
I can’t stand the way he’s so aloof!
It’s a call from Germany for Asuka.
It’s your mother.
For me?  My mama?
Give me that!
Hello, Mother?
When she speaks in a language
I can’t understand...
...Asuka seems to be a different person.
Her mother...
You were on the phone quite a while.
Well, it was just a
routine periodic communication.
I wish I could talk with my family.
Well, it’s just for show.
She’s not my real mother.
But, it’s not like I hate her or anything
like that.  I just feel uncomfortable
talking with her.
Why am I telling you this?!
Sorry.
I know I’ve hit rock bottom when I
get sympathy from you!
Synchrograph, minus 12.8.
It’s barely over the starting indicator.
That’s pathetic.
It’s a worse score than yesterday.
Asuka’s not feeling well,
it’s the second day of her period.
Synch ratio scores aren’t influenced
by physical disorders.
The problem’s in her subconscious.
We may have to replace Unit 02’s pilot.
Asuka, you’re finished now.
Maintenance of Power Grid 8 will begin
this evening at 18:00 hours.
Asuka’s pride has been badly damaged.
Maintenance of Power Grid 8 will begin
this evening at 18:00 hours.
It’s hard to blame her after she
was defeated so badly.
The Primary Command Center team...
It’s hard to blame her after she
was defeated so badly.
...will meet as scheduled.
Even worse, she feels Shinji beat her.
All General Affairs personnel are to
report to Conference Room 2.
Maybe it’s beyond our limits.
All General Affairs personnel are to
report to Conference Room 2.
Maybe the time has come for the three
of us to stop living together.
So you’ve hit your breaking point?
Are you fed up with your nice
imitation family?
I don’t have to take that from someone
who tries to fill the holes in her
own empty life with cats.
I’m sorry.  I’m just a little upset.
Why do I suffer through this
just because I’m a girl?
I don’t want to have children anyway.
Route 7 Loop is currently closed
due to an accident.
Please use Route 12 as a detour...
If you don’t open your mind to her,
your Eva will not move.
Are you saying that I’m
shutting myself out?!
Yes, because your Eva has her own mind.
The robot does?
You’re aware of it, aren’t you?
I don’t know what happened to make you
start talking to me.  It must be an omen
of a disaster or something!
What?!  Are you happy that
I can’t pilot my Eva?!
Don’t worry!  When an Angel comes,
our invincible Shinji will destroy it anyway!
We don’t have to fight!
They only need Shinji!
When a wind-up doll like you starts
being sympathetic to me...
...I’ve really hit rock bottom.
I am not a doll.
Shut up!  You do anything you’re
ordered to, don’t you?!
You’d kill yourself if Commander Ikari
told you to, wouldn’t you?!
Yes, I would.
Then you’re a toy, just like I thought!
You’re an unthinking, emotionless
doll and I hate you!
Everyone!  I hate everyone!
Shinji’s absent again today.
It’s nothing unusual for Ayanami
not to show up, but...
Asuka’s missing, too.
And Suzuhara can’t leave the hospital yet.
I guess the situation’s gotten so serious
they can’t come to school anymore.
Eva Unit 02’s signals all read nominal.
Connection and fusion of VA’s
are within normal limits.
The field of proliferation is within
the expected range.
You’re my doll, so move like I tell
you to and don’t argue!
Why does a weapon need a mind?
It just gives you trouble.
Anyway, you must obey my orders!
This is stupid.
All personnel, go to first stage alert!
Prepare for aerial assault!
An Angel?  They’re still coming?
Visual confirmation of Angel.
This is maximum magnification.
It’s not moving from its orbit.
It’s maintaining a constant distance
from our position.
So, does that mean that it’s looking
for a place to land?
Or that it’s going to destroy us
from up there?
We can’t attack it easily from this position.
Unless it comes into our range,
there’s nothing we can do.
The Evas can’t destroy an enemy
that’s in orbit.
What’s Rei’s status?
She and Unit 00 are both
in good condition.
Understood.
Sortie Unit 00.
Prepare for extreme long range firing.
Unit 02, Asuka, be ready to
sortie as her backup.
Backup?  Me?  For Unit 00?!
That’s right, take the rear guard position.
You can’t be serious...
Eva Unit 02 launch!
Asuka!
It’s okay.  Let her take point
if that’s what she wants.
Major Katsuragi?!
If she fails this time,
Asuka won’t be allowed to pilot anymore.
You mean this is her last chance?
We’d better start making preparations to
replace Unit 02’s pilot, just in case.
Yes, ma’am.
Excuse me, but aren’t you
going to sortie Unit 01?
It’s to remain frozen.
Those are Commander Ikari’s orders.
After what happened, it’s a good idea.
If I fail this time, they’re not going
to let me pilot anymore.
You can’t make any mistakes
this time, Asuka.
The target is still out of the range.
Why in the hell are you so slow?!
Come on down, you lazy Angel!
The Angel has a particle beam weapon?!
No, there are no thermal emissions
being detected.
We’ve got abnormal readings in her
psychograph!  Mental contamination
is about to begin!
The Angel’s making a psychic attack?
The Angels don’t understand
our minds that well!
Goddamn it!!
Positrons dissipated!
It’s not working!  It’s too far out of range!
Unit 02’s rifle is out of ammunition.
What’s the result of the beam analysis?
It’s an energy oscillation pattern
on a visible wavelength.
It’s similar to an AT Field,
but we don’t know much more.
How’s Asuka?
Her situation is critical.
The mental contamination is crossing
her Ego borderline!
Noooo!
Don’t!  Don’t come into me!
Pain!
No!
Get out of my mind!
Please!  Don’t rape my mind!
Asuka!
Psychograph shows she
can’t take anymore!
Yes, her mental circuits are being
destroyed.  This is too dangerous for her.
Asuka!  Retreat!
No!
That was an order!
Asuka, I’m ordering you to retreat!
No!  Never!
I’d rather die than retreat now!!
Asuka!
Accelerator synchronization initiated.
Voltage is increasing.
Approaching pressure zone.
Compulsory focus convergence, activated.
Correction for the Earth’s rotation
and gravity, 0.03.
Pressure in the chamber is at maximum.
Release the final safety lock.
All personnel, prepare for firing.
Negative effect!  There wasn’t
enough energy to penetrate its AT Field
from this distance.
But we’re at maximum power output!
We can’t get any more power!
Unit 02’s psychograph is getting weak!
What about the LCL mind barrier?
Negative!  We can’t even hope
for a buffering effect.
Switch top priority to life support.
Don’t let the Eva feed back.
Yes, ma’am!
Somehow, that ray scanned Asuka’s
mental wavelength and adapted to it.
Impossible!  Is the Angel trying to analyze
what’s inside a human mind?
Why am I crying?
I swore that I wouldn’t cry anymore.
What’s wrong, Asuka?
This is a present from your new mother.
Don’t you like it?
No!
But why not?
Because I’m not a child!
I’ll grow up faster than other people.
I don’t need a stuffed toy.
Please, look at me!  Mama!
I beg you, don’t stop being my mama.
Come to heaven with me.
Mama!  Mama!  Please, don’t kill me!
No!  I’m not Mama’s doll!
I’ll think for myself, and I’ll live for myself!
I don’t need a papa or mama,
I’ll live on my own.
No!  Don’t make me remember that!
I want to forget those things!
Don’t dig them up from my mind!
I don’t want those terrible
memories anymore.
Please, stop this!  Stop this!
My mind’s being contaminated.
Kaji!  My mind’s being raped!
What will I do?  It’s defiling my mind!
Unit 02 has ceased activation!
The life support system has crashed!
Pilot’s mind is entering danger zone.
Target position is constant.
Relative distance has not changed.
Possibility of the target coming into
Unit 00’s range is 0.02%.
Could we airlift Unit 00 and
try shooting from the sky?
No, we can’t do that.
If the Angel attacked during the approach,
we couldn’t protect it.
I’ll go out in Unit 01!
No!  This target has the ability to
attack the pilot’s mind.
We cannot allow an invasion of Unit 01.
But that can’t happen as long as
I’m not defeated, right?
There is no guarantee that
you will succeed.
But if we don’t, Asuka will...
I don’t care.  Rei, go to Dogma
and get the Lance.
The Lance of Longinus?!
You can’t do that, Ikari!
There’s no other way to destroy a
target that remains beyond the reach of
our AT Fields.
Hurry!
But if Adam and the Eva come into
contact, it might cause the Third Impact!
It’s too dangerous!
Commander Ikari, please don’t do this!
So, that story was fraudulent, too?
The Second Impact wasn’t caused
by contact between two Angels.
Opening Central Dogma barriers
10 through 15.
Unit 00 has passed the 6th Malvoisie.
Now opening barriers 16 through 20.
If something like this won’t cause
the Third Impact, then...
...what really happened to cause
the Second Impact?
Ikari, I still think it’s too early to use this.
The committee has
already started to mass produce Evas.
This is our chance, Fuyutsuki.
But...
We cannot make time run backwards...
...but we can spur its course forward
with our own hands.
The old men won’t allow this.
Therefore, we must finish this before
SEELE has time to act.
It is not acceptable to lose
Unit 02 at this time.
But you can’t use the Lance of Longinus
without SEELE’s approval.
The need is the justification.
There are no other factors to consider.
Justification?  No, what you’re
looking for is an excuse.
Unit 02’s pilot’s EKG has
dropped to 0.06.
We’re past the limits of the
life support system.
Unit 00 is passing through Vent 2.
She’s approaching the surface!
That’s the Lance of Longinus?
Unit 00 is in position to throw.
Target sighted.
Error corrections have been made.
Starting countdown.  Going from 10.
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Zero!
Target annihilated.
Eva Unit 02 is free.
What about the Lance of Longinus?
It passed escape velocity.
It’s moving into a lunar orbit.
It’s impossible to recover it now.
Yes, sir.  We have no method to recover
an object of that much mass.
Unit 02’s psychograph is
returning to normal.
Return the Evangelion to the second cage.
Please use Route 67.
How’s Asuka?
We’ve confirmed that the pilot is alive,
and we’ve established quarantine
for the contamination.
I see.
I’m glad you’re okay, Asuka.
Shut up!  Who the hell is “okay”?!
How could it get any worse?
That little bitch rescued me.
That little bitch rescued ME.
I’d rather have died!
I hate you!  I hate you!  I hate everyone!
I hate you!
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Unit 00 is possessed and
corroded by an Angel.
In order to protect Shinji from the Angel...
...Rei wishes herself dead.
She becomes light and heat to
disappear with Tokyo-3.
It’s the next episode, “Tear.”
Next Episode:
Tear