''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
SHIN SEIKI
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui  pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
I'm lucky!
I get to shop with you!
What the...?
This's the swimsuit section.
Hey, how about this?!
Isn't that a bit too much for a middle school student?
You're so far
behind the times.
This kind of suit is
quite common these days.
Is that so?
It's for our school trip,
I want to feel relaxed.
Where are you going?
O
Oki
Okina
Okinawa!
Scuba-diving is on
the schedule, too.
Scuba-diving...
I haven't gone diving
for three years.
Where'd you go
for your school trip?
We didn't have one.
How come?
The Second Impact.
Episode #10
Magma Diver
We can't go on
our school trip?!
Right.
Why not?
You must be on alert.
I hadn't heard that.
I just told you.
Who decided that?
I did, as the
Operations Planning Manager.
Hey, stop drinking tea,
and say something!
You're a man,
aren't you?!
I expected
this to happen.
Already given up...?
Yeah.
How pathetic.
A tame  guy's terrible.
Don't say it that way.
I know how you feel,
but it can't be helped.
An Angel might attack
while you're gone.
We always have to wait.
Wait wait wait.
We always have to wait for the enemy,
even though we don't know when they'll come.
Why don't you find
it first, then attack?
If we could,
we would.
Well, you must think
of this as a good chance.
While the others are gone,
you can study.
Did you think I wasn't
aware of THESE?
You're mistaken if you think
you can hide them from me.
I can easily obtain the information on how well you did on exams.
Ridiculous. What's with
this academic achievement?
I'm not interested in the old fashioned
exams of the demerit system.
In Rome, do as the Romans do.
I hope you get used to Japanese schools.
No way!
Asuka, I'll bring
you a souvenir!
I feel sorry
for you guys.
We'll have fun for you!
Paste the data of Mt. Asama from Balthazar to Melchior smoothly.
School trip?
They're too relaxed
at a time like this.
Because of times like these,
they want to play while they can.
Whatcha doin'?
Studying science.
Oh, you're so obedient.
But I have to.
Ta da!
Since I can't go scuba diving
in Okinawa, I'll dive here.
I see.
Well, what're you doin'?
Let me see.
Can't you even solve an
easy equation like this?
There, it's done.
It's simple.
If you can solve a difficult problem like this,
how come you did bad on the exams?
I couldn't understand what
was written on the exam.
You mean you couldn't
read the questions in Japanese?
That's right. I haven't
mastered all the Kanji yet.
I didn't study
it at college.
College?
Yup.
I graduated last year.
What's this about?
This's a problem
about thermal expansion.
Thermal expansion?
How elementary.
In short, things swell
and get bigger when heated...
...and shrink and get
smaller when cooled, right?
I know that, but...
In my case, do you think my
breasts'll get bigger when heated?
Don't ask me,
I have no idea.
Boring guy.
Look look, Shinji!
Backroll Entry!
These don't give
us a clear image.
But, this spot reported by Asamayama Earthquake Research Institute bothers me.
Of course,
we can't ignore that.
What did Magi say?
Fifty - fifty.
Is someone there?
Capt. Katsuragi's
already there.
That's the limit!
Not yet.
500 more, please.
Depth 1200.
Anti-pressure armor cracked.
Katsuragi!
If it breaks, we'll compensate for it.
200 more, please.
Contact on the monitor.
Start analysis.
Okay.
Probe crushed
and imploded.
How was the analysis?
We barely got it.
Pattern is blue.
No doubt.
That's an Angel.
This lab's now completely closed
and is under Nerv's control.
No one's allowed to enter, and all events for the last 6 hours must remain secret.
Request A-17
from Commander Ikari.
Be careful,
this line's unsecured.
I know, hurry and switch
to the secure line.
A-17?
You mean our
side'll attack first?
Yes.
No, it's too dangerous. Don't tell me you've forgotten what happened 15 years ago?
It's our chance.
We've done nothing but defend; now we can go on the offensive for the first time.
It's too risky.
But, you know how important a living sample of an Angel is.
Failure is unacceptable.
Failure? In that case,
all humanity will be lost.
Are you really sure?
That's an Angel?
Yes. It's something like
a pupa before maturity.
Our primary objective
is to capture the Angel.
Capture it alive and preserve the original form as much as possible.
If we fail...?
Destroy it as
soon as possible. Got it?
Yes.
Who's gonna do this?
Me, me!
I'll dive!
But, it'll probably
be me again.
Asuka.
You'll do it
with Unit 02.
Yes!
It's a piece of cake!
And me?
The special equipment won't fit
on a prototype such as Unit 00.
You're ordered to stay
at HQ with Unit 00.
Alright.
Too bad you can't
go to the hot spring.
Since A-17 was issued, we'll leave as soon as possible. Get ready.
Okay.
Even though you said this is an anti-heat plug suit, there's nothing different.
Push the right switch.
Oh, no!
What is this?!
Unit 02 is ready.
No, what's that?!
Special anti-heat, anti-pressure,
and anti-nuclear suits.
Type-D equipment
for extreme regions.
Is that my Unit 02?
No, I won't go!
I don't want to be
seen in public like this!
Shinji's more suitable
for this kind of job!
That's disappointing. I thought I'd get to see your brave actions.
Oh, no!
I'm not bold enough to
let Kaji see me like this.
It's a problem, isn't it?
It is.
Then, I'll...
I'll go with Unit 02.
Sorry, but I don't want
YOU touching my Unit 02!
If the First has to,
I'd rather go.
It's ugly,
but please be patient.
NEON GENESIS
Eva Unit 01 and
Unit 02 have arrived.
Both units, wait for
orders at present positions.
Prepare the laser shot
and the crane, quickly.
Roger.
Oh, where's Kaji?
That idiot won't come.
He doesn't have a job here.
Darn, I wanted to show
him my excellent work.
A-17's been ordered. That also means seizure of the present assets.
That puts a lot of
people in trouble.
Why didn't
you stop him?
There's no reason to stop.
The order's official.
But, if Nerv fails,
it means the end of the world.
They're not that arrogant.
What's that?
The U.N. Airforce is
on alert above us...
...until the end
of this operation.
Are they gonna help us?
No. They'll take care
of the aftermath.
If we fail...
What do you mean?
They'll burn the Angel with
an N2 bomb, along with us.
How terrible!
Who'd order such a thing?
Commander Ikari.
Laser operation complete.
Course secured.
Type-D equipment, no problem.
Unit 02's ready to go.
Roger.
Asuka, are you ready?
Anytime.
Go!
Wow, it looks hot!
Unit 02's entering the lava.
Look look, Shinji!
Giant Stroke Entry!
Present depth 170, descending speed 20.
Everything's operating normally.
Visibility zero.
I can't see anything.
I'm switching
to the CT monitor.
The range of the scope
is still only 120.
Depth 400.
450.
500.
550.
600.
650.
900.
950.
1000.
1020.
Passed the
safe depth.
Depth 1300. This is
the predicted target point.
Asuka, can you
see anything?
Nothing.
It's not here.
The lava flow is
faster than expected.
There's some error
in target speed.
Recalculate, quickly. Continue the operation. Descend farther.
Depth 1350.
1400...
Second circulation
pipe cracked.
Depth 1480.
Past max depth limit.
It hasn't encountered
the target. Continue.
Asuka, what's your status?
It's still holding. I wanna complete the job soon and take a shower.
I know a nice
hot spring nearby.
We'll go there when it's done,
so hang in there a little more.
Max depth, plus 120
Eva Unit 02 lost
its Prog'knife.
Max depth, plus 200.
Katsuragi, stop!
It's manned this time.
I'm in charge of
the operation. Continue.
She's right.
Don't worry, I can go farther.
Depth 1780. Predicted target
position after recalculation.
There.
Target, visually confirmed.
Prepare for capture.
Since both are driven by the flow, you only have one chance for contact.
I know. Trust me.
30 to target contact.
Relative speed 2.2.
I'm on the line of axis.
Electromagnetic cage expanded.
No problem. Target captured.
Nice, Asuka.
Capture operation complete.
Ascending.
Asuka, are you alright?
Of course!
It's easier to do it than worry about it, you know? It was easy.
But, this is more like
a sauna suit than plug suit.
I wanna go to
a hot spring.
Sounds like her
tension's gone.
Really?
You've also been worried
about today's operation, right?
More or less. If we fail,
there'd be another one.
Yes. Second Impact...
I don't want that again.
What's going on?!
No, it's begun emerging.
It's earlier than calculated.
How about the cage?
It won't hold!
Abort the capture operation.
Drop the cage.
Change the operation!
Angel's destruction is the top priority!
Unit 02, withdraw and
prepare for battle!
That's what I want!
Damn, I dropped the knife!
From the front?!
Release the ballast!
It's fast!
This isn't good.
I lost sight of the target.
In addition, visibility's bad, it's hot,
and the suit is sweaty and disgusting.
This sucks.
Asuka, Unit 01 will
drop its knife. Catch it.
Roger!
Damn, haven't you
dropped it yet, Shinji?
40 to knife's arrival.
The Angel's rapidly approaching.
No, stay away !
Hey, come on, quick!
Damn it! Too slow!
Damn it!
I can't believe it opened
its mouth in that environment.
It has an
incredible structure.
Right leg damaged.
Anti-heat process!
Damn you!
High temperature and high pressure. It can still withstand that kind of critical situation.
The Prog'knife won't work.
What should we do?!
I got it!
That's it!
You bastard!
I see.
It's the thermal expansion!
Redirect all cooling pressure to number three!~~Hurry!
I did it, but...
...is this really the end?
Shinji...?
Dummy. You're pushing
yourself too hard.
Hello, is there
anybody here from Nerv?!
Coming!
Sign here, please.
Thank you very much.
From Kaji?
What is it?
The bath is over
there to the left.
It's heaven, it's heaven.
I never realized bathing
was this relaxing.
Shinji, can you hear me?!
Ah, yes!
Could you throw the
body shampoo to us?
The one that we
brought here ran out.
Okay!
Here it comes!
Okay.
Ouch.
Idiot. Watch where you
throw that, you klutz!
Sorry...
Geez, don't hit
a part like this.
Oh, let me see?
Hey, Asuka's
bubbly skin is funny.
Don't touch it,
it tickles!
How about here?
Or here?
Don't touch it!
It's okay,
you won't lose anything.
It's growing...
How embarrassing.
Oh, this?
This happened because
of the Second Impact...
You know everything
about me, don't you?
Well, sort of.
It's my job.
It happened a long time ago,
so we shouldn't worry, right?
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Kouzou: Genmu Kiyokawa
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Kirl: Mugito~~~~~~
Member A: Kouichi Nagano~~
Initial Translation
Onizuka Kentaro
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Barbara
Brain
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
When Tokyo-3's power supply is cut off,
an Angel arrives at NERV HQ to find it completely locked up,
Can three kids make it to headquarters in time to intercept the Angel?
Next episode:
"In the Still Darkness"
You can expect more fanservice!