Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
NEON GENESIS
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.
Young boy, become a legend.
Good morning, Shinji.
How are you?
I've gotten used to it...
I think nothing's wrong.
That's fine. Exit points,
emergency power source...
...locations of armed buildings and recovery spots.
Can you remember
all of them?
Maybe...
Well, I'll review
the lesson again.
Eva usually works off an
electric power supply cable.
If Eva uses its internal battery in an emergency...
...it'll only function one minute at full strength or five minutes at most, even with Gain.
You understand?
Yes.
Now, let's resume the Induction Mode lesson where we left off yesterday.
Aim at the target in the center of the sights...switch on.
Stay calm. Aim at the
center of the target.
Switch...
Next!
Say, I wonder how Shinji
brought himself to pilot it.
He goes along with what
others say obediently...
...it's how he copes
with his life, isn't it?
Aim at the center of the target, switch...
Aim at the center of the target...
Episode 3:
A Phone
That
Never Rings.
Misato, it's morning already.
I was on night duty
until a little while ago.
I don't have to go to the
office until this evening.
So, please let me sleep.
Then, I...
Is it Thursday?
Burnable garbage, please.
Okay.
Have you gotten
used to school?
Yes.
Good. Take care.
See you later.
Yes, hello.
Oh, it's you, Ritsuko.
How have you been?
Are you getting along with him?
Him? Oh, Shinji. It's been two weeks since he transferred schools.
He's still the same.
He never gets any telephone calls.
Telephone calls?
As it's a necessity, I gave him a portable one a long time ago.
He doesn't seem to have used it or received a phone call from anyone.
I wonder if he
has any friends.
He seems to have a poor personality for making friends, doesn't he?
Have you heard the story of
the "Hedgehog's Dilemma''?
Hedgehogs?
The thorny ones?
Even if they want to warm each other, the closer they get, the more they hurt each other.
Humans are the same.
Shinji must be afraid of getting hurt, so he acts timid.
After he grows up and gets closer to and stays away from someone...
...he'll learn the proper distance to maintain to avoid hurting each other.
What is it, Class Rep?
Did you take care
of yesterday's printout?
Ah, well, there didn't seem to be anybody at Touji's house.
Aida, you're on good terms with Suzuhara, aren't you?
Why aren't you
worried about him?
I'm not sure, but he
may have been hurt.
In that robot incident?
The TV said that nobody was hurt...
No way! You saw the center of the explosion, didn't you?
Not only the units of Iruma and Komatsu but also Misawa and Kyushu were sent out.
I'm sure that there were more than 10 or 20 people injured. Some might've been killed...
Touji!
Suzuhara!
Yo! The number of students seems to have dropped drastically.
Evacuation, evacuation. Many have transferred to other schools.
It's not surprising. There was a real battle within the city.
You're the only guy who's happy to see real battle.
I guess.
How have you been?
You've been absent a long time.
Were you involved in the incident?
My younger sister...
She was buried under
a heap of rubble.
She survived, but has been in the hospital since then.
My father and grandfather work for the research center.
They can't leave work. If I didn't stay with her she'd be all alone.
Anyway, the pilot of
that robot really sucked!
I'm really pissed.
A robot on our side destroyed the city! What was he doing?!
Did you hear the rumor
about the transfer student?
Transfer student?
Him. He transferred to this school while you were gone.
It was just
after the incident.
Don't you think
that's strange?
All rise!
The hardest trials for the human race began then.
In the last year of the 20th century...
...a massive meteor, from deep space, fell on the Antarctic Continent.
It caused the continent's
ice to melt rapidly.
As the result, the water
level of the oceans rose...
...the Earth's axis fluctuated
and abnormal weather...
...which threatened the existence of all living things occurred around the world.
We call this
the Second Impact.
Economic collapse, racial disputes and civil wars. The survivors suffered all kinds of hell.
"Is it true that you're the pilot of that robot? Y/N''
But 15 years later...only 15 years, we have revived the world a great deal.
This result is not only due to the excellence of the human race...
"It's true, isn't it? Y/N''
...but to the blood, sweat, tears and effort of your fathers and mothers.
In those days, I lived in Nebukawa.
It is already...
Hey, everybody! We're still in class, aren't we? Take your seats!
You're always trying
to take control!
It's okay, it's okay.
No, it's not!
How were you selected?
Did you have any examinations?
Were you frightened?
What's the cockpit like?
Well, uh, I have to
keep such things secret...
What's the name
of the robot?
I'm not sure, but they
call it Eva or Unit 01...
Eva?
What's its deadly attack?
It's some knife and the vibrations...
like an ultrasonic wave...
Anyway, that's amazing! He's the pride of our school, isn't he?
Great!
Consequently...
Well, so much for today.
All rise! Bow!
Hey, everybody! At least
do it properly at the end of...
Sorry, transferee. But I had to hit you. I couldn't be satisfied unless I hit you.
Sorry, but his younger sister got hurt in the battle. That's the reason.
Speaking for myself,
I'm not doing it by choice.
An emergency call...
I'll go on ahead...
A special state of
emergency now exists...
...for the Kanto and Chubu districts around the Tokai area.
Please take refuge in designated shelters. I repeat....
NEON GENESIS
The target has been acquired optically.
It has invaded territorial waters.
All hands to
battle stations!
Roger. Prepare
anti-aircraft batteries!
Tokyo-3 is transforming
to battle formation.
House the central block!
The central block and
District 1 to 7 have been housed.
The government and all ministries concerned have been notified.
Present anti-aircraft interception
system effectiveness is 48%.
What's the status of
noncombatants and civilians?
The evacuation has
been reported complete.
Primary and junior high school students,
please stay in your class.
Residents, please stay
in your block.
Again?!
There're only letters
on the screen again.
News blackout. They won't
show us civilians anything at all.
Although this is
such a big event...
The 4th Angel shows up when Commander Ikari is absent. It's sooner than I expected.
The last one came after a 15 year interval. This one after only 3 weeks.
They never think about our circumstances, do they? They're the type women hate.
They're just
wasting taxes.
The committee is requesting that we mobilize Evangelion again.
How annoying. We'd mobilize it even if they didn't ask.
Entry has begun.
Charge LCL.
Release Arrival/Departure Lock.
My father isn't here,
so why am I still piloting it?
I was hit, too...
Hey, I have something
to talk to you about...
What is it?
Yeah, well...you know.
Oh, alright.
Class Rep!
What?
Both of us are
going to the toilet.
Come on! You should
have done that earlier.
Well, what is it?
I want to see it, even
if it's only once before I die.
The battle?
I don't know if the
next enemy will come...
Kensuke, you're something else!
If I miss this chance, I might never...
Say, help me unlock the gate.
If you go out,
you'll be killed.
We don't know if we're safe here,
so I want to go see it.
You moron. What do you
think Nerv is for?
What do you think the fighting machine of Nerv is?
The robot which
the transferee pilots.
Last time, he protected us.
But you hit him. Twice at that.
If he doesn't want to pilot the robot, we'll all be killed.
You have a duty to
watch his battle, don't you?
There's no other choice.
You have a one
track mind, don't you?
Shinji, time
to launch, okay?
Alright.
Alright, neutralize the enemy's AT-field and fire the rifle just like you practiced.
Are you ready?
Yes.
Launch!
Amazing! It was worth the effort.
Wow, this's what I've been waiting for!
There it is.
Aim at the center of the target, switch, aim at the center of the target, switch...
Develop an AT-field according to the plan. OK?
Okay.
Idiot! The enemy is hidden by
the explosion's smoke!
Look, he's already beaten.
He's all right.
I'll send you
a spare rifle!
Take it!
Shinji, Shinji...
Damn!~~I wonder if being punched affected him as badly as I thought.
S...shut up!
Umbilical cable was cut!
Eva has switched over
to internal batteries.
Active time remaining is
4 minutes 53 seconds!
It's coming this way!
Shinji, are you
all right?! Shinji!
Damage report.
No problem.
It's operational!
They're Shinji's classmates!
Why are they there?!
Why doesn't he fight?!
Because we're here...
he can't move freely.
Unit 01, active time remaining,
3 minutes 28 seconds!
Shinji, let them
into the cockpit.
After they're in, retreat.
Then come back later!
Do you think civilians are permitted into the entry plug without authorization?!
I'll permit it.
You're exceeding your authority,
Captain Katsuragi.
Unit 01, active time
remaining, 3 minutes!
Maintain Eva under present orders and extend the entry plug! Hurry up!
You two, get inside!
Quickly!
What? It's water!
My camera.
Oh, my camera!
Trouble in the
nervous system!
It's because foreign
bodies have been inserted.
Noise detected in
the nervous pulses.
Now, retreat!
Recovery route is No. 34.
Go to the east
side of the mountain!
Transferee! She said
"Run away,'' transferee.
Don't run away, don't run away, don't run away...
Progressive Knife drawn!
Shinji, obey my orders!
Retreat!
Shinji!
That idiot!
Unit 01. Active time
remaining, 30 seconds...
Eva Unit 01 has stopped.
The target is silent.
Three days have already passed...
Since we were really
raked over the coals...
Since he's been absent
from school, I mean.
Who's he?
The transferee,
the transferee.
I wonder how he's been?
Are you worried about him?
I'm not especially worried...
For being so tactless,
you're stubborn, aren't you?
Afterwards, if you'd
said to him you're sorry...
...you wouldn't have suffered mental agony for three days.
Here's the transferee's phone number.
If you're worried,
try calling him.
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Teacher: Eiji Maruyama~~
Girl A: Yuko Miyamura~
Initial Translation
Wada Mitsuhito
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Shinji can't overcome the weakness in his mind and even runs away from Misato.
But the organization catches him easily.
There aren't any kind words.
Next time, "Rain, After He Runs Away.''
And, of course, fanservice!