''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
SHIN SEIKI
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui  pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
~YEARS
~AGO
~~
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~A.D. 2000~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Father...
Episode 12
The Value of a Miracle is...
Thanks for letting
us stay, Shinji.
Where's Misato?
She might still be sleeping.
She's had a lot of overnight work lately.
Yeah, her job's
very hard.
Keep quiet,
so we don't wake her up.
Hey, what're you
guys doing here?!
Getting out
of the rain.
Oh, sure. You're after me,
aren't you?
I'm changing clothes.
If you peek, I'll kill you.
You bitch! Who'd want to
see you changing clothes?!
She's too conceited.
I...I...I...
Sorry for disturbing you.
I'm glad to see you.
Welcome home, Shinji. We have a harmonics test tonight. Don't be late.
Okay.
Asuka, you know that,
don't you?
Yeah.
Congratulations
on your promotion.
Co...Congratulations.
Thanks.
Oh, don't mention it.
Well, I'm off.
Take care.
What's wrong?
Did something happen to Misato?
Her badge.
It has two lines.
She must've been
promoted to Major.
I didn't notice.
I wonder when...
Are you serious?
How pathetic.
Don't you guys
have any sympathy?
It's not so easy for a woman her age to take care of two junior high students.
"We'' are the only ones
who have human hearts.
Number 0 and 2 have reached the contamination border, that's the limit.
Number 1 seems to be able to take it.
Decrease the plug depth by 0.3.
It's almost reached
the contamination zone.
But these readings...?
He's incredible.
His harmonics and synchronization
ratios are approaching Asuka's.
It's his talent, isn't it?
He was definitely
born to pilot the Eva.
Although he doesn't wish to be like that.
He wouldn't be happy to know that.
Well done, everyone.
Shinji, good job.
What do you mean?
Your harmonics value has risen 8 points from the previous test. Nice increase.
But it's still 50 points
lower than mine.
An 8 point gain in ten days.
That's great.
Not that great.
How nice it is for
you to be praised.
I'm going home.
You idiot.
Ummm...congratulations
on your promotion.
Thank you.
But, to tell the truth,
I'm not that happy.
I understand.
When I was praised,
I wasn't so happy either.
It only made
Asuka angry.
I wonder why
she got angry?
What made her angry?
Does it bother you?
Yes.
It's because you always
consider what others think.
Congratulations!
Thank you.
Thank you, Suzuhara.
No, no. He's the
one who planned this.
Yes, the planning and scheduling were done by Aida Kensuke, Aida Kensuke!
Thank you, Aida.
Oh, you don't need to thank me for it.
This is what comes naturally.
But, why is the
Class Rep here?
I invited her.
Right?
What about Rei?
I invited her, but she doesn't seem to get along well with others.
Kaji's late.
Is he cool?
He sure is. Kaji's completely different from these lumps of potato, like day and night.
It's an insulting comparison.
What did you say?!
Is it still difficult for you to be in situations like this?
No, but I'm not used to
being around so many people.
Why're we making
such a fuss?
Promotion...It's because your work is recognized by others, right?
Well, probably.
That's why we're celebrating.
But you don't look happy.
No, I don't mean that I'm totally unhappy. I'm a little happy.
But, that's not
why I'm here.
Then, why'd
you join Nerv?
Well, it's been a long time.
I've forgotten.
It must be Kaji!
I came directly from HQ.
I met her on the way.
I doubt that.
Jealous?
Absolutely not.
Anyhow, congratulations, Major Katsuragi.
I have to be polite to you from now on.
What're you talking about,
you idiot?
Well, it's unprecedented that both the Commander and Sub-Commander left Japan.
That means they
trust Katsuragi.
My father's gone?
Commander Ikari is at
the South Pole by now.
No lifeforms may exist in this dead world of Antarctica.
Or rather, we should
call it "Hell.''
Nevertheless, we humans are
standing here as living beings.
Because we're protected
by the power of science.
Science is humanity's power.
That arrogance caused the tragedy 15 years ago. The Second Impact.
And this is the result...
This punishment is too great,
considering our crime.
It's like
the Dead Sea.
Yet, this is a pure world without the impurity of the original sin.
I prefer a world where people live,
no matter how smeared with sin it is.
Message received.
Nerv reports that they detected an Angel in orbit above the Indian Ocean.
It suddenly appeared
two minutes ago.
Move the 6th reconnaissance
satellite to its orbit.
Two minutes to contact.
Target in sight.
Incredible.
That's ridiculous.
The 6th satellite's going
to contact the target.
Start scanning.
Start transmitting data.
Transmission confirmed.
AT-field?
That's a new
way to use it.
What massive power of destruction.
That's definitely an AT-field.
It's using momentum.
That Angel itself is
something like a bomber.
Anyway, the first shot hit the
Pacific Ocean far from its target.
The second shot hit that
point two hours later.
After that, it's steadily correcting the trajectory errors.
That means
it's learning.
N2 anti-air missiles
didn't have any effect.
The Angel disappeared
after that.
It'll come.
Next time, it might drop
itself right here.
Could that be the birth
of the 3rd Ashinoko Lake?
Fuji's five lakes will merge and become part of the Pacific Ocean, including HQ.
What about Commander Ikari?
Communications are impossible due to the Angel's strong jamming.
What's Magi's recommendation?
They ALL
recommended evacuation.
What're you going to do?
You're in charge now.
Report to each ministry.
Issue special declaration
D-17 under Nerv's authority...
...and evacuate all citizens
within a 50km radius.
Recommend the backup
of Magi to Matsushiro.
Are we going to
abandon this place?
No. But we don't
want to risk all of us.
Special declaration D-17
was announced by the government.
All citizens, go to your
designated shelters immediately.
Make Block Six and Seven
first priority...
Follow each Section Chief's instructions,
and evacuate immediately.
All shelters in the
city report complete.
The evacuation of noncombatants and Class D
personnel by "Alarm C'' is complete.
Are you seriously
going to do this?
Yes, I am.
Are you going to abandon the three Eva units because of your selfish decision?
The probability of success is only 0.00001%.
Less than one in ten thousand.
But it's not zero.
Major Katsuragi...!
I'm the one who's
in charge now.
I want to do all that I can.
My job is to destroy the Angel.
Your job?
Don't make me laugh.
It's for you. It's your revenge against the Angels, isn't it?
NEON GENESIS
What?!
Catch it by hand?!
Yes. Position the Evas at
the estimated impact point...
...and stop it with
a full AT-field.
What if the Angel has changed
its course considerably?
Then, it'll be over.
What if the units can't
withstand the shock?
Again, it'll be over.
The probability of success is...?
Only God knows,
so to speak.
If it succeeds,
it'll be a miracle.
Miracles have value only
when we make them happen.
In other words, you're saying that we must manage to do it somehow?
Sorry, but in this operation,
there's no other way.
How can you call
this an operation?!
You're right, I can't. Therefore, if you don't want to, you can refuse.
Are you ready?
You're required to write a will.
What're you going to do?
I don't care.
I'm not going to die.
I won't.
It's unnecessary.
I won't either.
I'm sorry. When the operation is over,
I'll treat you to a steak.
Really?
I promise.
Wow!
Don't forget.
Look forward to it.
Steak means a gorgeous dinner...?
Does she really think that today's kids would be glad to get steak?
How poor some the people of
the Second Impact Generation are.
It can't be helped.
What was that "WOW?''
You pretended to be happy.
It's nicer if we make
her command easier.
Anyway, she's
going to treat us.
Where will we go?
You MUST come this time.
I won't.
Why not?
I hate meat.
The target's been lost
due to the Angel's jamming.
It's impossible to
estimate the exact point...
...but Magi has estimated the impact point from the available data, and...
...this is it.
Is it this wide?!
The radius is huge.
The target's AT-field will completely destroy HQ if it falls anywhere within that radius.
Under these conditions, we'll place an Eva Unit at each of these three points.
What are those
locations based on?
My intuition.
Intuition?
Yes, it's woman's intuition.
How vague. I feel
the miracle fading away.
Misato's never won much.
Ack.
Hey.
What?
Why do you
pilot the Eva?
It's obvious. To show
my talents to the world.
To show you exist?
Something like that.
Why don't you
ask that girl?
I've asked her before.
You two sure
get along well.
It's not like that.
How about you, Shinji?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Are you stupid?
I might be.
You're really stupid.
120 minutes to
estimated impact.
Everyone, take shelter.
I can handle the rest from here.
No, this is
my job too.
I can't let the children be the only ones in danger.
They'll be okay.
Even if the Evas are damaged,
the AT-field will protect them.
The Eva is
the safest place.
Shinji, you asked why
I joined Nerv yesterday.
My father threw himself into his research... his only dream.
I couldn't forgive him,
rather I hated him.
Just like my father.
He didn't care about me,
my mother or our family.
People said that
he was sensitive...
...but he was so weak that he was always trying to escape from reality, such as family.
He was like a kid.
I agreed with my mother when she divorced him, since she was always in tears.
My father seemed shocked...
...but he laughed at himself,
saying it was his fault.
He saved me in exchange
for his life...
...because of the Second Impact.
I'm confused as to
whether I loved or hated him.
But I'm sure that I have to defeat the Angels that caused the Second Impact.
I joined Nerv
to accomplish that.
It might be that I was
trying to avenge my father...
...in order to be free from my father's binding spell.
Don't run away. Don't run away.
Don't run away.
That's right,
I shouldn't run away.
Target in sight.
Maximum magnification.
Distance, approximately 25000.
Here it comes.
All Eva Units, proceed
to the start position.
The target's trajectory can only be calculated using optical observation.
So, Magi will guide you
until a distance of 1000.
After that, you're on your own.
I trust you all.
The Angel's approaching.
Distance, approximately 20000.
Then, begin the operation.
Let's go.
Start!
Distance, 12000!
Maximum field!
Unit 02, maximum field!
I'm doing it!
Now!
Bastard!
Communications restored. There's an incoming message from Commander Ikari in Antarctica.
Put it through.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm very sorry. Due to my actions, Unit 01 was damaged.
I take full responsibility.
It's alright. The Evas' mission is the annihilation of the Angels.
It was fortunate that
the damage was light.
Yes.
Well done, Major Katsuragi.
Thank you very much.
By the way, is the
pilot of Unit 01 there?
Y...yes.
I've heard the story.
Well done, Shinji.
Eh? Y...yes.
Major Katsuragi,
I leave the rest to you.
Yes, sir.
Next station is Shin-Miyanoshita,
Shin-Miyanoshita.
At the next station
the exit is on the left side.
You must fulfill
your promise.
Okay, okay.
I've withdrawn big bucks.
I can pay for a full-course dinner.
...it's before
payday though.
Relax, I know what's
inside your wallet.
Miss Honor Student said
that she'd come if it's ramen.
I'll have garlic flavor
without baked pork.
I'd like shark fin
with baked pork. A large.
Here you go.
Shark fin with baked pork.
Say, Misato...
What?
When I heard my father's words, I found for the first time that it's nice to be praised.
And I also found out that I pilot Eva to hear those words from my father.
THAT'S why you pilot it?
You really are stupid.
To be continued
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Operator: Kouichi Nagano~~
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
After a simulated plug activation
trouble occurs, and Central Dogma is invaded.
NERV is forced to accept a course of self-destruction.
Next Episode:
"Angel Invades.''
Next time, fan service!