I guess we'll be in Japan by tomorrow.
Misato said she'd pick us up around noon.
Misato is the person who was
with me in Germany before you.
I don't really like her that much,
she seems too contrived.
Tsk, I guess that means a temporary
parting between us.  Boooring!
You'll have plenty of boyfriends
when we get to Japan.
I hear the Third Children is a boy.
I'm not interested in some stupid kid!
I'm only interested in Kaji-san.
I'm honored.
I'm ready anytime for you!
Be it kissing and beyond!
You're still a child.  Those things
are for when you get older.
What?!  Boooring!
I'm old enough already!
I'm an adult!  An adult!
An adult!!  So look at me!!
Fiction becomes reality.
What a fate.  The experimenter
herself was the guinea pig.
So, you think that the contact
experiment was the immediate cause?
The mental breakdown...
Was that a result of the contact?
It's too cruel.  She committed suicide,
leaving behind such a young girl.
Hmm, perhaps.  I don't think
that it was the only cause.
Asuka-chan, Mama
cooked your favorite for you.
If you complain about what you like
and dislike, that girl will laugh at you.
Everyday, she's like that.
She talks to the doll, thinking
that it's her beloved daughter.
She might feel responsible,
in her own way.
She devoted her whole life to research,
and did not spend the time to take
care of her own daughter.
I sympathize with your grief.
But, they are like a doll
mother and a doll daughter.
Maybe there is very little difference
between humans and dolls.
Dolls are made by humans in their own image.
If God really exists, we
might just be dolls for him.
Hearing such things, I can hardly believe
you're a doctor of modern medicine.
Yes, I'm a doctor, but I'm
still a human, and a woman first.
You're so good, Asuka-chan.
You may cry if you wish.
It's OK.  I won't cry.
I can think for myself.
Can you hear me, Asuka?  Your synchro
ratio decreased by 8 whole points.
Don't think about extraneous things.
Just the same as usual.
I'm trying!
Don't Be
Recently, Asuka's synchro ratio has
been getting lower and lower.
This is very troubling.
We don't have a spare.
Maybe we should work on Rei's Unit 00 first.
We can't repair both of them at the same time.
The mitosis process in the left arm of
Unit 02 has cleared the numerical goal.
The necrosis process is presently under 0.05%.
No problems in the apotheosis process.
Maintain the current status of the
self formation system of Unit 00.
Connect each receptor to
the second signal terminal.
What was born from Adam, the Eva series.
We have no other way to defeat
the Angels, besides utilizing the
very cause of Second Impact.
In other words, those who utilize even
the thing that tried to destroy them,
those are human beings.
After all, I probably hate Eva.  Probably,
I'm trying to avenge my father.
Katsuragi-san!
They have begun construction
of Evas up to Unit 13?
In seven places all over the world?
This information came via Shanghai.
The source is reliable.
Why are they speeding up construction now?
We've lost two Eva units recently, and
now another two units are severely damaged.
I suppose they're speeding the creation
of a spare force for backup plans.
Who knows?  We've even received
parts from Germany which were originally
made for Units 05 and 06.
Nowadays they're spending
a great deal of money.
The budget was recently doubled.
From that, we might guess that the
executives were driven into a corner.
I feel the committee's impatience.
So, do you think they are doing it because they
anticipate cases of several Angels attacking at
once, and not just one like we've seen so far?
Maybe...  But there's no reason for them
to do that outside of the normal channels.
There might be another reason.
The number you have just
dialed is no longer in service.
Strange...  It won't connect.
I wonder if he's gone off somewhere again?
A train will be arriving soon on track number 2.
Please stay inside the white line until
the train has come to a complete stop.
He spent an entire month dissolved inside
Eva and he's already back to his old ways.
After all, I lost...  and to the likes of you.
It's been a long time since we were all together,
so what's with this unsociable atmosphere?
I'm finished.
Asuka!
I'm not going to get it!  After all, maybe
it's a call from Kaji-san to Misato.
You should get it.
It can't be...
Oh, I'm so sorry that I forced the unrivaled
Shinji to do such a trivial job.
Yes, hello...
Hmph!  I can't stand the way he's so formal.
An international call from Germany for Asuka.
It's your mother.
For me?  From Mama?
Give me that!
Hallo, Mutter!
Wir haben uns lange nicht gehoert.
Danke schoen... ch...
Listening to her speaking an unfamiliar
language, I feel as if Asuka were a stranger.
Ach, ha, niemals!
Er ist ein sauberer Mensch.
Ja.  Ja.  Wirklich?
Das ist aber toll.  Fantastisch!
Mother...
Auch, wenn ich gehts keine lerne. go.
Auch, wenn ich...
Ich werde jetzt ins Bett gehen.
Aufwiederhoeren.  Gute Nacht!
That was a very long call.
It's only a sort of periodic communication.
I'm envious.  Family talk...
Oh, it looks...  It's only superficial.
She isn't my real mother.
But, it doesn't mean I dislike her.
It's just that I feel a little uncomfortable with her.
Why the hell am I telling you such a thing?!
Sorry.
It's the end for me, when
I get sympathy from you!
I feel sick...
Who wants to bathe in the same water that
Misato and stupid Shinji have bathed in?
Who wants to use a washing
machine that Misato and stupid Shinji
have washed their underwear in?
Who wants to sit on a toilet that
Misato and stupid Shinji have used?
Who wants to breathe the same
air as Misato and stupid Shinji?
I hate Misato!  I hate Shinji!
I hate First even more!
I hate Papa!  I hate Mama!
But most of all I hate myself!!
I can't take it anymore!!
Why me?!  Why me?!!
Synchro graph, minus 12.8.  It's on
the borderline of the starting indicator.
What a terrible state!  Her
results are worse than yesterday.
Asuka is feeling bad today.  She's
in the second day of her period.
Synchro ratio is not affected
by external bodily disorders.
The problem's in her subconscious.
We may have to change the Unit 02 pilot.
Asuka, you're all done.
Maintenance of power system number 8
is going to start at 18:00 this evening.
Asuka's pride was badly damaged.
It's natural, after being beaten that way.
The regular meeting on the first Command
Center project will be held on time.
More ever, it's much worse that she
feels that she was beaten by Shinji.
Personnel of the General Affairs department
report to meeting room number 2.
Maybe it's our limitations.  I'm afraid
the three of us couldn't live together.
You broke through the critical point?
Is this the end of your nice family game?
I won't listen to this from someone who
conceals her loneliness with pet cats.
Sorry, I'm just a little upset.
Why do I have to go through such
an awful time just because I'm a girl?
I don't even want to have children.
Circular route number 7 is now
closed because of an accident.
Please use route number 12 instead.
If you don't open your mind
to her, Eva will not move.
You mean I'm closing myself off?  Me?
Yes.  Eva has her own mind.
That doll?
You must be aware of that.
Today is a special day, since even you talked
to me.  Tomorrow maybe we'll have snow.
Damn!  Are you that happy
that I can't pilot Eva?
Don't worry.  When an Angel comes,
the invincible Shinji will defeat it.
We don't have to do anything.
They only need Shinji!  If Shinji is
there, everything will be OK!
Not only Shinji, but a doll like you is sympathizing
with me.  It must be the end for me.
I'm not a doll.
Shut up!  You do anything you're ordered to.
You'll kill yourself if Commander
Ikari orders you to do so.
Yes, I will.
You're a doll, just like I thought!
You've always looked like a doll, and
I've hated you for a long, long time.
Everyone!  I hate everyone!
Shinji is absent today, too.
Ayanami's absent, as usual, but...
Asuka too.
Suzuhara is still in the hospital.
I guess that the situation is very
serious, and they can't come to school.
All Eva Unit 02's signals are normal.
Connection and fusion of VA is within normal limits.
The field of proliferation is within the expected range.
So you're finally back together...
after losing like that.
You're just my doll.  So move like
I tell you to, and don't say 'no'.
Why does a weapon have a mind?
What a hassle!
Anyway, you must only say 'yes' to my orders.
This is stupid.
All personnel, level one combat
readiness.  Prepare for aerial assault.
An Angel!  They're still coming?
Visual confirmation of the Angel.
This is at maximum zoom.
It's not moving from orbit.
It's maintaining a constant distance from us.
That means it's waiting for a chance
to come down.  Or is it going to
destroy us without approaching?
We can't get at it easily.
Anyway, we can't do anything unless
it moves to within our firing range.
Eva can't defeat an enemy in orbit.
How's Rei?
She and Unit 00 are in good condition.
They'll be OK.
Roger.  Unit 00, move out!  Prepare
for extreme long distance firing.
Unit 02, Asuka, be ready for a sortie as backup.
Backup?  Me?  For Unit 00?
That's right.  Take the rear guard.
You must be kidding?  Eva Unit 02, move out.
Asuka!
It's OK.  Allow her in the front if she wishes.
Major Kasturagi!
You mean, if Asuka fails
here, she'll be dismissed.
That means, it's her last chance?
We must prepare in case the
Unit 02 pilot has to be changed.
Yes, ma'am.
By the way, aren't you sending out Unit 01?
It's been frozen by strict
orders from Commander Ikari.
We have to accept it after an accident like that...
If I fail this mission, I might lose
my position as pilot of Unit 02.
You must not make any mistakes, Asuka.
Target is still out of the firing range.
Oh, hurry up and come here, you lazy Angel!
You're laziness is getting on my nerves.
Alert
The enemy's directional weapon?
No, no thermal energy reaction detected.
Abnormal patterns in the psycho graph.
Mental contamination will start soon.
An Angel's psychic attack?  Can they
understand the minds of human beings?
God damn it!
Positrons diminished.
No effect.  It's out of range.
Unit 02 has no ammunition in its rifle.
What's the result of the ray analysis?
Energy wave of visible wavelength.
It's similar to an AT Field, but
the details are still unknown.
How's Asuka?
Situation dangerous.  Mental
contamination has broken the borderline.
Nnnooo!  I...  Don't enter into me!
No
Pain
Strangled
No
Don't touch me!
Hatred
No
Stop!
Menarche
No
Keep out!
Shame
No
No!
Commit
double
suicide
No!
No
Death Sex
Invader
No!
No
Mama
How comfortable
No!
Don't peep into my mind!
Please!  Don't invade my mind anymore!
Asuka!
Her psycho graph is at the critical point!
Her mental circuit is now
being severely damaged.
Further overload will be too dangerous.
Asuka, retreat!
No!
This is an order!  Asuka, I order you to retreat.
No, never!  I'd rather die here than retreat!
Asuka...
Accelerator, start synchronization.
Voltage increasing.  Approaching the pressure range.
Compulsory focusing start.
Correct the error from the rotation
and gravity of the Earth, 0.03.
Pressure in the barrel is at maximum.
Release the final safety lock.
All personnel, prepare for firing!
No effect!  There's not enough energy to break
through the AT Field from this great a distance.
But, output power is at maximum.
We can't get more power!
Unit 02's psycho graph signal is very weak.
How about the mind barrier from the LCL?
No effect.  We can't even
expect the buffering effect.
Give first priority to life support.
Don't allow feedback from Eva.
Yes, ma'am.
That ray seems to scan Asuka's
mental wavelength pattern.
Oh, no...  Does that mean the Angel
is trying to search the human mind?
Why am I crying?
I decided that I wouldn't cry anymore.
What is it, Asuka?
It's a present from your new mama.
Don't you like it?
No.
So, what do you want?
I'm not a baby.  I'll become an
adult earlier than other people.
I don't need a teddy bear.
Painful
Look at me.
Stepmother
The loss
Painful
Insanity
Mama, please don't stop being my mama.
No
Sex
Death
No
Sex
Death
No
Sex
Death
Please, come to heaven with me.
No
Sex
Mama, Mama, please, don't kill me!
Death
Sex
No
Death
Sex
No!  I'm not Mama's doll.
No
Sex
Death
No
I'll think for myself, and I'll live on my own.
Sex
Death
No
I don't need Papa or Mama.
I will live on my own.
No!  Don't make me remember such things!
I want to forget, so don't dig into my memories!
I don't want to remember such terrible things.
Stop!  Stop!!
My dear Asuka-chan...
Die with me.
OK, I'll die with you Mama.
So don't stop being my mama!
Please, Mama!!
Mama?
I don't know you.
Who are you?
My name's Soryu Asuka Langley.
Pleased to meet you.
Are you stupid?
Chance.
So look at me!
No!  This isn't me!
My name's Soryu Asuka Langley.
Pleased to meet you.
Are you stupid?
Chance.
So look at me!
No!  This isn't me!
My name's Soryu Asuka Langley.
Pleased to meet you.
Are you stupid?
Chance.
So look at me!
No!  This isn't me!
My name's Soryu Asuka Langley.
Pleased to meet you.
Are you stupid?
Chance.
So look at me!
No!  This isn't me!
My name's Soryu Asuka Langley.
Pleased to meet you.
Are you stupid?
Chance.
So look at me!
No!  This isn't me!
Help me!  Help me Kaji-san!!
You're still a child, Asuka.
What are you doing there?!
You won't do anything!  You won't help me!
You won't even hold me!
Nobody.  Nobody!  Nobody!!
So look at me!
Are you lonely?
No!  Don't come near me!
I can live by myself!
Are you stupid?
Do you like me?
I don't need anyone!
Do you really like me?
I can live by myself!
Liar.
Rejection
NNOOOOO!!!
Father
Mother
Lack
Anxiety
Separation
Evasion
Contact
Obsession
Attachment behavior
Dependence
Emptiness
Mental Collapse
Pity
I am not a doll!
Mental contamination
Don't violate me!
Stop!
Die with me!
No!!
It hurts!!
I hate you!!
Presumptuousness
Latency
Masculine protest
Don't be
Manifest
Reaction formation
Shadow
Opposing will
Compensation
Don't be
Primary identification
Rationalization
Oblivion
Deception
Raison d'etre
Self-confidence
Infantile experience
Sense of loss
Compensation
Symbiosis
Hostility
Repression
Death
I hate you!!
My mind has been sullied.
Kaji-san, it's polluted.
What should I do?  My mind has been polluted.
All activity has ceased in Unit 02.
A problem has arisen
in the life support system.
The pilot will enter the danger zone.
No change in the target.  Relative
distance still shows no change.
The possibility that the target will move
into the firing range of Unit 00 is 0.02%.
Can we transport Unit 00 by air?
Shoot the target from the sky?
No, we can't do that.  If the Angel shoots
during the approach, we can't protect it.
I'll go out in Unit 01.
No.  This target is one which
invades the minds of the pilots.
We must avoid a situation
where Unit 01 is invaded now.
So, you mean it's OK as
long as I'm not defeated?
That can't be guaranteed.
But, if this goes on, Asuka will...
I don't care.  Rei, descend to
Dogma and use the Lance.
Lance of Longinus?  Ikari, that's...
We have no other choice to destroy
a target in orbit, where an AT Field
from here can't reach.  Hurry!
But, there's the possibility that the
contact between Adam and Eva
will cause Third Impact.
It's too dangerous.
Commander Ikari, please don't do it!
It's a lie?  Second Impact wasn't
caused by contact with an Angel.
Open area numbers 10 to 15 of Central Dogma.
Unit 00 has passed the 6th Malebolge.
Next, open area numbers 16 to 20.
You say Third Impact will not be
aroused by such a small thing.
So, what was the real
cause of Second Impact?
Ikari, I think it's too early to use that.
The committee has started the
mass production of the Eva series.
This is our chance, Fuyutsuki.
But, I can't...
We can't make the clock move backwards.
But, we can make it move
forward with our own hands.
The old men will not allow it.
We must put an end to everything
before Seele takes action.
It's not a good idea to lose Unit 02 right now.
But, if we use the Lance of Longinus
without the permission of Seele,
that will cause many problems.
If a reason exists, that is enough.
I don't see anything else to consider.
Reason?  What you really want is an excuse.
The amplitude of the EEG of
Unit 02's pilot has decreased to 0.06.
It's the critical point for life support.
Unit 00 has passed area number 2.
She'll be coming up above ground.
That's the Lange of Longinus.
Unit 00, take position for throwing.
Confirm the target.  Correct for error, OK.
Start the countdown.
10 seconds left...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
0...
Target annihilated.
Eva Unit 02 is free.
How about the Lance of Longinus?
It surpassed escape velocity.
It's now moving into a Lunar orbit.
It'll be almost impossible to recover it.
Yes.  There is currently no way
to retrieve that much mass.
Unit 02 is all right.  Graphs
are within normal limits.
Send the unit to cage number 2.
Use route number 67.
How's Asuka?
Confirmed.  The pilot is alive.
Quarantine for contamination complete.
I see...
I'm glad you're OK, Asuka.
Shut up!  Who are you calling OK?!
It's the worst.  I was rescued by that girl!
Rescued by that damn girl!
I would rather die than that!
I hate, hate, everyone, everything!!
Neon Genesis Evangelion
Episode 22'
Created by: GAiNAX
Subtitled by: deus X anime
http://www.deusxanime.com/
Script version: 1.12
Source:  DVD [KIBA-6]
Translations:
TV scenes - Kentaro Onizuka
(Literal Translation Series Edited by Matthew Opel)
Revised scenes - Bochan_bird
Editing:  deus
Timing:  deus
Special Thanks to Kotus for Sub Station Alpha
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi~
~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
~~~~~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kyokawa
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki
~~~~~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Preview
Unit 00 is possessed and corroded by an Angel.
In order to protect Shinji from the Angel,
Rei wishes herself dead.
She becomes light and heat to disappear with Tokyo-3.
It's the next episode: "Tears"