Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
NEON GENESIS
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.  Young boy, become a legend.
Yeah!
I hit it, I hit it!
Coin Cleaning
Hour
Cleaning doesn't come cheap.
Thank you very much. Thank you very much.
I wish I had time to
do them at home, don't you?
You're lucky, at least
you had time to go home.
Oh, Sub-Commander.
Good morning.
Good morning, sir.
Morning.
You're early today.
I went to the
upper town for Ikari.
I see. It's the committee's regular meeting today, I suppose.
Boring job. Ikari always
forces trivial duties on me.
If not for Magi,
I wouldn't know what to do.
A city council election will
take place above soon.
The city council is just a puppet.
Magi is truly in charge of the city.
Magi. Those three
super computers are...?
Those three computers decide
everything by majority rule.
The system follows the
fundamentals of democracy.
Does the council only
follow Magi's decisions?
It's an effective government
which minimizes waste.
It's indeed the city of science.
It's an era when science is omnipotent.
What an old-fashioned phrase.
Come to think, you have an experiment involving Unit 00, don't you?
Yes, starting
at 10:30 today...
...the second experiment for improving the activation time is scheduled.
I'm expecting good news.
Abort the experiment.
Cut the circuits.
The circuits
are switched.
Power supply recovering.
This is a
problem after all.
Yes. I'm worried that the conversion efficiency is lower than the theoretical value by 0.008.
It's within the maximum error measurement. What should we do?
Lower the interconversion by 0.01 and try it again with the same setting.
Roger.
Start reactivation experiment.
Episode 11
In the Still Dark
Hey!
Just a moment!
Man, I ran and ran.
You seem to be in
a bad mood today.
It's because I saw YOU
just after I arrived.
Yes. Hold a
moment, please.
What?
Um...umm...
Well, Father...
What's the matter?
Be quick!
Umm, well...
Today...at school...
...I was told to tell my parent that a career guidance interview will take place.
I've entrusted Katsuragi
with those things.
Don't call me for such trivial things.
Don't make phone calls like this.
What the...?
A blackout?
No way,
that can't happen.
Something's wrong.
An accident...?
Did Akagi screw
up an experiment?
Main power supply down.
Voltage zero.
It...it wasn't me.
I wonder...
But the auxiliary power
supply should come on soon.
It's no use. The auxiliary
circuit isn't operating.
Impossible. How many
circuits are operational?
1.2 percent in all!
Only 9 circuits from No. 2567!
Use all operating power supplies
to maintain Magi and Central Dogma.
But that will affect the life support systems in every building.
That's alright!
They're top priority.
Remember Takahasi Nozomu, Takahashi Nozomu. Thank you for your support.
She's really lazy.
I think Katsuragi should
get her own laundry.
Wha...?
It was because
Commander Ikari's too busy.
I wonder. It was like I failed or something rather than his hanging up.
Geez. You're a man, why don't you stop worrying about the small stuff?
What?
What're you doing?
Hey, let me do it!
Damn it!
It must be broken!
Anyway, we've got to get
to the control center.
The power's been out
for seven minutes.
Something's very wrong.
How's this
place powered?
Three systems:
Main, sub and auxiliary.
I can't believe that all
three failed simultaneously.
That means...
...we'd better assume that someone's tripped the breakers instead of a system failure.
No matter what caused this, we'll be in big trouble if an Angel appears.
An unidentified object's been
detected by search radar.
Expected landing location...
former Atami area.
It may be
the eighth one.
Yes.
It must be an Angel.
What should we do?
Take an alert position.
That's standard procedure.
Its destination is Tokyo-3.
Right, but we
can't do anything.
The Angel has landed.
It's still coming.
And Tokyo-3?
It's still silent.
What on earth are those
Nerv guys doing?
I thought that a ladder was
just an old-fashioned ornament.
I never imagined
that I'd use one.
They say,
preparation is prevention.
This doesn't
work either.
None of the facilities work.
It's strange.
You mean something's
happened below?
It's a natural conclusion.
Anyway, let's contact
Nerv Headquarters.
No use. Even the emergency
phone doesn't work.
No use. Line 77
isn't operating either.
No, I can't
make contact.
I can't either.
Even the emergency line is out.
What should we do?
What're you doing?
Are you stupid?!
There's an emergency manual!
Anyway, let's go
to Headquarters.
Okay, let's choose the leader of our group before we go into action.
And of course,
I'll be the leader.
Any objections?
Let's go!
We can go down through
Route-07 over there.
But the doors
don't work, right?
Oh, a manual door...
Alright, Shinji.
It's your turn.
You only rely on me
in situations like this.
That damn Joint Staff Council only relies on us frontliners in situations like this.
What's the
government saying?
The guys in Tokyo-2?
I heard they're preparing to escape.
The Angel is
still advancing.
Anyway, we have to
contact Nerv.
But how?
Go yourself.
This's the Third District
Japan Air Self-Defense Force.
An unidentified object is currently approaching this area.
Residents, please go to your designated shelters as soon as possible.
Oh, no! I have
to report to HQ...
...but how?
Remember Takahashi, Takahashi Nozomu,
who is unperturbed even in an emergency.
Lucky!
It's really hot.
The air conditioners
aren't working.
Katsuragi, if you can't stand the heat,
you could at least take off your shirt.
There's no reason
to be shy, is there?
Even if the situation comes up,
don't get any weird ideas.
Okay, okay.
This's bad.
The air's stagnating.
These facilities are supposed to be the pinnacle of modern science.
But, that's just like the
Commander and Sub-Commander.
They aren't bothered
by this much heat.
It's lukewarm.
Yeah.
NEON GENESIS
Due to this district's special state of emergency, an emergency vehicle is going...
It's a dead end,
you know?!
It's okay! Go in,
it's an emergency!
Alright!
No, please stop!
The Geo-front was designed
to be self-sufficient...
...even if it's isolated
from the outside.
Theoretically, it's impossible for all the power supplies fail.
Which means somebody
did it deliberately.
I guess their purpose is
to investigate this place.
They want to examine the structure of HQ
through its recovery procedures.
Annoying guys.
I'll run a dummy program on Magi to make it difficult for them to grasp the whole.
I'll leave it to you.
Yes, sir.
The first damage to Headquarters was done by humans rather than an Angel...
I can't bear
the thought.
After all, humanity's
enemy is a human.
It usually takes two minutes to get there. Is this the right passage?
If we reach it, I'm sure
we can enter the Geo-front.
I've heard the same
phrase four times already.
You're always thinking too
much about the small stuff.
Be quiet.
What is it,
Miss Honor Student?!
I hear a voice.
It's Hyuga!
Hey! Hey!
An Angel's approaching!
Repeat; an Angel's approaching!
An Angel's
approaching...?!
We mustn't waste time.
Let's take a shortcut.
I'm the leader. Don't take
control without my permission.
So, where's the shortcut?
Damn, even though this
is a shortcut, I look so bad.
Say, what do you
think the Angels are?
What're you
talking about?
Angels, messengers of God.
Our enemies with the name of Angels.
Why're we
fighting them?
Are you stupid?
Unknown enemies are attacking us.
It's natural that we have to
``get rid of sparks raining down on us.''{<- an analogy)
I say right.
To the left,
in my opinion.
Don't bother me!
What do you think, Shinji?!
Well...
...I don't know.
Geez, I'm the leader,
so you should follow me!
As I expected, something seems strange.
This passage leads up.
What do you mean,"As I expected?''
You always say too much.
See! I'm sure
I'm right this time.
We visually verified there's an Angel. Now we're sure that we have to hurry, right?
An Angel's approaching. I suggest that Eva should be readied for combat.
Oh, no.
Fuyutsuki, I leave
the rest to you.
Ikari...
I'm going to the cage to
prepare the Evas for combat.
You mean you're going
to do it manually?
We have a diesel
for emergencies.
But...
...we have no pilots.
Again.
This way.
You're Commander Ikari's
favorite, aren't you?
You see, the beloved honor
student is different from us.
Stop saying such things
at a time like this.
You always stay calm.
Hey, don't screw with me just because you're the favorite!
I'm not screwing with you...
...nor am I the favorite.
I know it
all too well.
Roger. Termination signal
plug has been extracted.
OK. Prepare to insert the
entry plugs into all three Evas.
But, we don't have
any pilots yet.
Don't worry.
I'm sure they'll come.
We can't open
this door by hand.
It can't be helped. We'll force
open the duct and go through it.
The"First'' is scary.
She's the kind of person who stops at nothing to achieve her objectives.
She's a self-righteous one.
We've completed
placing the plugs.
All we need now
are those children.
Don't look ahead no matter what.
If you do, I'll kill you.
You Idiot!
Idiot, idiot!
I told you not to look!
What could I do?
If I don't look ahead...
You guys...
All units,
prepare for entry.
Roger. Open the
hatches manually.
How're the Evas?
They're ready.
Nothing's working though...
We did it by human hands.
It was the Commander's idea.
Father's...
Commander Ikari's been preparing,
believing that you'd come.
Plugs inserted.
All units were activated
with auxiliary power sources.
Remove the first lock bolt.
Release hydraulic
locks 2 thru 32.
Pressure zero.
They're free.
OK. Everyone, remove the
bindings by force, and move out.
The target's staying
directly above us.
Hurry up.
Emergency batteries attached.
Good. They're ready.
Move out!
Geez, I look so uncool!
We're nearing
the pit.
Oh man, I look
so uncool again!
Oh, no.
Dodge it!
No!
The target's trying to invade HQ directly using a strong solvent liquid.
What should we do?
We'll defeat it,
of course!
But how? I dropped my rifle and the batteries on our backs are empty.
We can only move
for three more minutes.
I have a plan.
The defense stays here...
...neutralizing the AT-field and shielding the offense from the Angel's solvent liquid.
The backup goes down, picks up the rifle and gives it to the offense.
Then the offense destroys the target with a salvo from the rifle. How's that?
Okay.
I'll be the defense.
Sorry, but...
...I'll do it.
It's so dangerous.
That's why. I'd feel bad if I left my debt unpaid from the last battle.
Shinji's the offense.
Miss Honor Student is the backup.
Alright?
Okay.
Alright, let's go!
Ayanami!
Asuka, get out
of the way!
I've paid off my debt.
Damn, why won't this open?!
It's an emergency!
I can't stand this...!
Hey, I told you
not to look up!
Okay, okay.
Dirty...
It's ironic that the stars look so beautiful without artificial lights.
But, I don't feel like people live there without the lights.
See? That makes
me feel better.
Mankind fears the darkness and scrapes it away with fire to survive.
So philosophical!
I wonder if man is a special creature because of that.
Is that why the
Angels are attacking us?
Are you stupid?
How're we
supposed to know?
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~~~~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~
~~~~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
~~~Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
~SoldierA: Tomomichi Nishimura
SoldierB: Hidenari Ugaki~~~~
Driver: Kouichi Nagano~~
AnnounceGirl: Akiko Yajima~~~~~~~~~ {C...Crayon Shin-chan!!! )
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Misato's career has been a crusade to exterminate the Angels.
Shinji finds a similar sentiment within himself.
The largest Angel yet comes flying through the stratosphere,
making many people abandon all hope.
Next time:
``The Value of a Miracle is...''
Watch it with everyone together.