''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
SHIN SEIKI
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui  pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
Yes, I've already made arrangements with the Committee about that problem.
The cargo left Sasebo yesterday, and is now in the Pacific.
Mil-55D transport helicopter!
I never thought I'd get a chance to be on one!
It's great to have friends,
isn't it, Shinji?
I thought it was stuffy staying in the mountain every day, so I invited all of you on my date.
Then, is this a real
date with Misato?
I bought this cap
just for today, Misato.
So, where are we going?
We're going to be cruising the
Pacific on some gorgeous ships!
Five carriers and
four battleships!
It's a large fleet.
It's definitely good to have friends.
That's "gorgeous?''
You bet it's gorgeous!
That's the carrier, "Over the Rainbow,''
the pride of the U.N. Forces.
It's huge.
I wonder how such an
obsolete ship can stay afloat.
No, no, it's
pre-Second Impact vintage.
How nice,
they brought a toy socket.
They're on an
errand for the kid.
Great...
...great...
Too great! If you're a man,
you weep at such a sight!
Great...!
...great...
Hey, wait! Wait!
Damn it!
Stop! Stop!
Hello, Misato.
How've you been?
As well as ever.
You look taller.
Yeah! And the rest of
my body has grown too.
Let me introduce you...
She's the exclusive pilot of Evangelion Unit 02,
the Second Child, Souryu Asuka Langley.
Episode 8
Asuka
Arrives at Japan
What'd you hit me for?!
Payment for the view.
Cheap, wasn't it?
Say what?
Then I'll show you mine, too.
What're you doing?!
So, which is the
much-discussed Third Child?
Don't tell me it's...
No, he's the one.
He seems rather dull...
I thought you were accompanying kids from the Boy Scouts, but it seems that I was wrong.
Thank you for your
understanding, Captain.
Don't mention it. I'm rather happy to have kids to take care of after such a long time.
We appreciate your assistance with the transport of Eva Unit 02.
Here's the specifications
for the emergency power socket.
I haven't heard any requests to mobilize "that'' doll at sea.
Just think of it as
back-up in case of emergency.
To guard against such emergencies,
we, the Pacific Fleet, are escorting it.
When did the U.N.
become a delivery service?
I believe it was just after a certain organization was established.
This is a massive escort
for guarding a mere toy.
The entire
Pacific Fleet is mobilized.
Considering Eva's importance,
it seems too small.
Well, please sign these forms.
Not yet.
At the request of the
3rd Branch in Germany...
...both Unit 02 and its pilot are under this fleet's command.
I won't allow you
to just do as you please!
Then, when will
you transfer command?
After unloading the
cargo at Shin-Yokosuka.
We're still in charge at sea.
Follow our orders without question.
I understand. In an emergency, however,
please don't forget that Nerv has authority.
She's cool!
She's almost like Ritsuko...
You're as
courteous as ever...
Kaji-senpai!
Hi.
Kaji, I didn't invite
you to the bridge.
Sorry about that.
Well, excuse us.
On the way to Shin-Yokosuka...
Is this a date?
Awesome,
too awesome.
Shit! Those kids
will save the Earth?
Times change. I heard that Congress has put its hopes in that robot.
In that toy? Idiots!
If they have the money for things like that, they should be paying US more!
What're you doing here?!
I'm accompanying her.
I'm on a business trip from Germany.
I was careless... I should have expected this to happen...
Hey, don't touch me!
What can we do?!
The 3rd Squadron has
taken off as scheduled...
Are you seeing anyone?
It's none of
your business, is it?
Oh, you're so cold.
You're living with
Katsuragi, aren't you?
Y...yes.
Tell me, does she still
toss about in her sleep?
Wh...wh...
What're you
talking about?!
So, she hasn't changed,
has she, Ikari Shinji?
N...no. How do
you know my name?
It's no surprise, you're
famous in our society...
...the Third Child, who piloted
Eva in combat without any training.
Not really.
It was luck.
That luck is part of your destiny.
It's your talent.
See you later, then.
Okay.
This has to be a bad joke.
No, a nightmare...
What do you think
of Ikari Shinji?
He's dull!~~I'm disappointed that a boy like him has been chosen as the Third Child.
When confronted by sudden combat,
his synchro-ratio exceeded 40%.
No way.
That captain was
completely arrogant!
He's a proud man.
He couldn't help saying some ironies.
He seems to be
rather lively...Kaji, I mean.
He's always been
like that. The idiot!
Third Child!
Come with me.
I didn't know
Unit 02 was red.
That's not the
only difference.
After all, Units 00 and 01 are prototypes.
They're just test models.
That's why it synchronized with someone who hasn't had any training.
However, Unit 02
is different.
This is a true Evangelion, the first on Earth to be built for actual combat. The final model.
What's happening?
Shock wave in the water...!
Something's exploded nearby.
That's....
Is that... an Angel?
Is that a real one...?
What should I do?
I have to get back to where Misato is.
Chance.
NEON GENESIS
All ships, check distance between ships and take evasive maneuvers.
Report the situation.
"Cinbli'' is sinking. "Titus Andronicus'' hasn't confirmed the target.
Damn it!
What's going on?!
Hello, Nerv service.
Do you need data and countermeasures against that invisible enemy?
We're engaged in battle! Unauthorized personnel are not allowed here!
From what I can tell,
this must be an Angel attack.
All ships,
fire at will.
That's useless.
That kind of attack
won't penetrate its AT-field.
Why is the Angel here?
Is it for Unit 02?
Hey, where're we going?
Wait here a second!
What's she doing...?
Don't peep, you jerk!
Why are boys
such perverted idiots?!
Asuka, let's go.
Why won't it sink?
Only Eva can defeat it,
after all.
Hey, let's go!
You're coming with me!
Hey, why're we
changing into plug suits?
Are you stupid? It's obvious.
We're gonna defeat it with Unit 02.
That's going too far.
Shouldn't we ask Misato?
I'll ask after I win.
Here I go. I'll show
you how skillful I am.
Just don't disturb me.
Strange. It seems to be
looking for something.
I never expected an Angel attack here.
This isn't like what you said.
That's what Unit 02 is for,
and another pilot's there as a reserve.
If the worst happens,
escape by yourself.
I understand.
LCL Fullung, Anfang der Bewegung...
...Anfang des Nerven anschlusses...
...Ausloses von links-Kleidung...
Synchro-Start.
Error?
What happened?
Mental noise!
I told you not to disturb me!
What do you mean?
You're thinking in Japanese, aren't you? Think in German!
A...all right...
Ba...baumkuuhen...
Idiot!
Oh, fine! Switch base
thought language to Japanese.
Evangelion Unit 02, activate!
Message from "Othello:''
Evangelion Unit 02 has activated.
What?!
Nice, Asuka!
No, halt the activation sequence.
Put it back.
I don't care!
Asuka, launch!
What!?
Both Eva and its pilot are under our command.
I won't let you do as you like!
What're you talking about?! Who cares about procedure at a time like this?
Hey...!
Is she serious? Unit 02's
still configured with B-equipment.
If we fall
into the sea, it's over.
If we don't,
we'll be okay.
Shinji, you're also on board?
Yes.
Two kids...
Can I test it...?
Asuka, go for it!
It's coming.
Here we go.
Which way?
Over there.
Only 58 seconds left.
I know! Misato, prepare the emergency external power supply on deck!
I understand.
What are you
going to do?
Okay, I'm gonna jump!
Jump?
Run!
Spare socket ready.
Reactor connection complete.
Clear the flight deck.
Eva, cleared to land.
All personnel,
prepare for impact.
Nonsense!
Eva Unit 02, landiiiiing!
What a waste!
Target is rapidly
approaching the ship!
It's coming
from 9 o'clock!
Switching to
external power source.
Switching complete.
But, we don't
have a gun.
One Prog'knife is enough.
That thing's really big.
That's what I thought.
What're they going to do?
Close range combat's the
best way to defeat Angels.
Alright, Asuka,
you stopped it!
This isn't a joke!
The flight deck's messed up...
It's fallen.
Asuka, underwater battle is
impossible with B-equipment.
We won't know
until we try, right?
What a waste...
What about the
length of the cable?
One thousand
two hundred remaining.
What're you going to do?
We can deal with it.
We have to do something.
The cable's running out.
Prepare for shock.
Damn!
Eva lost the target.
Change disks...
Yak-38bis!
Hey, Katsuragi!
Kaji!
I have something to deliver,
so I'm leaving now...
Go ahead.
So, if you'll excuse me,
Captain Katsuragi...
He ran away.
Target approaching Eva again!
It's coming again!
I'll kill it this time!
What?!
It's not working!
With B-equipment...
What can we do?
What can we...?
How pathetic!
You're the Third Child, aren't you?
Here it comes!
Mouth?
Because it's an Angel...
Eva Unit 02's
entered target's body.
Does that mean
Eva was eaten?!
It's like fishing...
Fishing...?
Yes, fishing!
We're in trouble again.
Shut up...
Hey, get off me,
you pervert!
But we have
to free ourselves!
Asuka, can you hear me?
Don't release it!
Captain.
What?
I beg your cooperation.
Point blank fire by the
two remaining battleships?
Yes. We sink two unmanned battleships on the axial line of the umbilical cable to set a trap.
Meanwhile, Eva Unit 02 will
open the target's mouth.
The ships will then
rush into the opening.
After firing, self-destruct
them to destroy the target.
That's insane!
Insane, but
not impossible.
I understand.
All hands, abandon ship.
Repeat, all hands abandon ship.
All frigates, pick up those people in the lifeboats, quickly!
But what about Eva?
Don't worry,
those two'll be alright.
Hey, don't operate my Unit 02
without my permission!
Do both of you
understand the operation?
I'll do my best.
I'm counting on you.
Open the Kingston valves.
Start sinking to Z-point.
Roger.
Reverse the cable.
Eva has started surfacing.
70 to contact.
Hey, you're still
touching me. Move over!
But if we can't open the mouth soon, we'll also be destroyed.
60 to contact.
Status of Angel's mouth?
Still closed.
Both battleships are
sinking to the target.
Eva's surfacing!
50 to contact!
It's no use!
We don't have
much time left...
Target has passed
under the "Tempest.''
Hurry or you'll
be too late!
Don't think strange things!
Like what?
Never mind,
just concentrate.
I know.
20 to contact.
15 to contact.
Open, open, open, open!
Fire!
Shin Yokosuka (Formerly Odawara)
You did it again.
I should have prepared
for underwater combat.
How rare.
Second-guessing yourself?
Don't say it.
We've obtained precious data.
You're right.
Misato...
It's truly precious.
P...pair-look!
That's sick!
They set a new
synchro-ratio record, didn't they?
For only 7 seconds.
It was probably because of the danger...
Hey, where's Kaji?
He escaped earlier. He must've arrived at HQ! That bastard!
Well, that was an
eventful journey.
Was it because of this?
It has already been
restored to this stage.
It's held within hard Bakelite,
though I'm certain it's still alive.
It's the key to the Complement of Humanity Project, isn't it?
Yes. This is the
first human being...
...ADAM.
Really, she was a disgusting girl,
despite her lovely appearance.
Well, we'll never
see her again.
But, sir, you can't avoid meeting her because of your job. I really sympathize with you.
I'm Souryu Asuka Langley.
Nice to meet you.
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Touji: Tomokazu Seki~~
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga~~
Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
~~~~Captain: Tomomichi Nishimura
1st Officer: Jin Yamanoi~~~~~~~~
Initial Translation
Shouichi Takeuchi
Craig Green
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
PREVIEW
It's the first combination
attack with two Evas...
...but Shinji and Asuka's
minds are out of phase...
Misato brings a plan to them
to form their perfect unison.
Next time:
"Momentarily Unite the Minds.''
And, of course, fanservice!