Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
NEON GENESIS
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.  Young boy, become a legend.
Apotheosis procedure
for three Eva units...
...will begin as planned as soon as the Magi System's on line.
Confirmed.
Omit from 450 to 670.
Order received.
You're fast as usual, Maya.
That's because you
personally taught me.
Hold it.
A8 is faster.
Let me do it.
This is just like you.
How're things going? Have you finished the diagnosis on the Magi System?
Almost. I made it in time for today's test, just like I promised.
You're indeed Ritsuko, even though you have to deal with the three of them.
It's already cold.
All three Magi System computers have shifted to self-analysis mode.
127th periodic check,
passed without any problems.
Confirmed. Well done. Everyone,
take a break until the test begins.
No problem...?
Mom's healthy as ever,
but I'm just aging, aren't I?
Episode 13
Angel Invades
"shito shinnyuu''
What?!
Undress again?!
It's a super clean room from there.
Just taking a shower and changing your underwear isn't enough.
Why do we have to do this for testing the auto pilot?
Time isn't simply passing. The technology for the Evas must keep improving.
We always need fresh data.
See?
I did what you said.
Cleaned seventeen times!
Then, all three of you, go through this room and enter the entry plug.
Don't worry. The visual monitor's turned off. Your privacy's protected.
That's not the point!
I'm not comfortable with it!
This is a direct harmonics test without the support of the plug suit.
Asuka, that's an order.
Geez, just don't watch, okay?
Each pilot's ready for entry.
Start the test.
Auto pilot, start recording.
Insert the simulation plugs.
Connect the system
to the dummy bodies.
Simulation program has
handed over control to Magi.
Oh, it's pretty quick.
It's truly Magi.
It's hard to believe that the
first experiment took a week.
The test is expected to
be completed in three hours.
How do you feel?
Something's different.
Yeah, it's different from usual.
It's a different sensation. The right arm is clear, and all the rest is dull.
Rei, imagine that you're
moving the right arm.
Okay.
Data collection's
going well.
There seem to be no problems.
Change Magi back to normal.
Dilemma...?
You can guess the personality of the person who made it, can't you?
What are you saying?
You made it, didn't you?
You don't know anything.
Well, unlike me, you don't
talk about yourself.
True.
I upgraded the system.
My mother created the
logic base and architecture.
Have you confirmed it?
Yes, I have.
This is the part that was
delivered three days ago.
This part is deteriorating.
That's the 87th protein wall,
isn't it?
When I zoom in, I can see something like a stain. I wonder what it is.
It's corrosion, right? Temperature and conductivity's been slightly changed.
Degradation in the sterilized
room happens often these days.
The deadline was pushed up sixty days,
so it had some air bubbles.
The job on complex B
was very sloppy.
That part was finished
after the Angel appeared.
That couldn't be helped
because everyone was tired.
Fix it by tomorrow.
Ikari's very picky.
Yes, sir.
Water leak again?
No, it's corrosion on the
protein wall above us.
That's bad.
Will it affect our test?
At this moment, no.
Then, continue.
I can't stop this test easily.
Commander Ikari's so picky.
Alright.
Synchronization point, normal.
Connecting the simulation plugs to the Eva units via the simulation bodies.
Eva Unit 00, contact confirmed.
Generating AT-field
at normal output.
What happened?
Contamination alert has been
issued in Sigma Unit, floor A.
87th protein wall has degraded.
It's heating up.
There's a problem
in No.6 pipe.
The corroded area's
expanding rapidly!
Abort the experiment!
Disconnect No.6 pipe!
Yes, ma'am.
60, 38 and 39 are isolated.
More corrosion in 6-38.
It's not working.
Corrosion's spreading from wall to wall.
Prepare the Polysome.
Set the laser at max. power.
Fire as soon as it reaches there.
Corrosion's reached 6-58.
It's coming!
Rei?!
Rei's simulation body's moving.
Impossible.
Corrosion still expanding.
It's destroying the water circulation system of the simulation body.
What about Rei?!
She's alive.
Eject all plugs!
Fire the laser quickly!
AT-field!
Impossible.
What's that?
Analysis pattern blue,
that's definitely an Angel!
Angel...?!
You let it get in?!
I'm sorry.
No need for excuses. Isolate Central Dogma and separate it from the Sigma Unit!
Isolating Central Dogma and separating it from the Sigma Unit.
We'll isolate the box!
All personnel, evacuate!
What're you doing?!
Move it!
Isolating the
Sigma Unit from floor E.
Close all shutters. All personnel in the corresponding sections, evacuate.
I know.
I'll leave it to you.
Stop the alarm.
S...stop the alarm.
It was a false alarm.
The sensor malfunctioned.
Tell that to Japan's
government and the Committee.
Roger.
The polluted area's
still growing.
It's expanding from the Pribnow Box to the entire area of the Sigma Unit.
That's a bad location.
Yes, it's too
close to Adam.
Contain the pollution within the Sigma Unit.
You can sacrifice the Geo-Front.
Evas' status?
They're standing by
in the 7th cage.
As soon as the pilots
are recovered, they can go.
You don't have to wait for the pilots.
Launch to the surface immediately.
Unit 01 has to be the first. You can sacrifice the rest if you have to.
Unit 01...?
But, without Eva, we can't
physically destroy the Angel.
If Eva's contaminated before that,
everything will be over.
Hurry!
Roger!
Central Dogma below the Sigma Unit will be completely isolated in 60 seconds.
So, that's the Angel.
This isn't time for working.
The vacuum pump will be
activated in 30 seconds.
Central Dogma's been completed isolated. The deep facilities were taken over by the invader.
Well, how will you deal with
the Angel without Eva?
NEON GENESIS
See? That's the border of heavy water that contains more oxygen.
It seems that
it's quite particular.
The part where ozone's coming in to keep it sterilized isn't polluted.
That means it
hates oxygen, right?
Looks like it.
Ozone's being released.
The density's increasing.
It's working, it's working.
Did we do it?
Zero-A and zero-B seem
to be recovering.
The exterior of the
pipe's returned to normal.
The central part is strong.
Alright, increase ozone.
Strange...
It's expanding.
Something's wrong.
It's heating up.
The polluted area's
expanding again.
No good,
it's totally ineffective.
It's absorbing
ozone this time.
Stop the ozone.
Amazing. It's evolving.
What's wrong?!
The sub-computer's been hacked.
Intruder, unknown.
At a time like this...?
Damn, I'll handle it in mode C.
I'm gonna open the defensive
wall and run a dummy entrance.
It evaded the
dummy entrance.
Eighteen seconds to
trace the invasion.
Develop a defensive wall.
It broke through
the defensive wall.
I'm opening more
dummy entrances.
This isn't
a human's doing.
Trace, successful.
It's from our facilities.
It's from the underground of the complex B.
It's from the Pribnow Box!
Its optical
pattern's changing.
The bright lines are
like an electronic circuit.
It's pretty much
like a computer.
I'm opening
a dummy entrance.
Failed.
It was interrupted.
Cut the main cable.
Didn't work.
It doesn't accept the command.
Shoot the laser.
The AT-field was developed,
no effect.
It's accessing the main bank
of the security section.
It's scanning
the password.
Twelfth digit...sixteenth digit...
"D'' word, cleared.
It's entered the main bank
of the security section!
It's scanning in the main bank!
I can't stop it!
What's its purpose?
It's searching for the main bus.
This code is...damn...
It's trying to invade Magi!
Shut down the
input/output system.
Go ahead and count!
Three...two...one...
I can't shut
the power off!
The Angel's still invading.
It's reached Melchior.
No, it's been taken
over by the Angel.
Melchior was reprogrammed
by the Angel.
Self destruction was proposed by
the artificial intelligence, Melchior.
Rejected...rejected...rejected...
N...now, Melchior's
hacking Balthasar!
Damn, it's fast!
What amazing calculation speed!
Change the logic mode.
Set the synchro code to 15 second cycle.
Roger!
How long can we hold out?
Guessing from that speed,
we have about two hours.
I didn't expect Magi
to become our enemy.
They're micro machines
the size of bacteria.
The group of machines rapidly evolved until they acquired intelligence.
Evolved...?
Yes.
They're always changing, trying to become a system that can counter any situation.
That's very much like the cycle of life, seeking survival.
The most effective attack
against an enemy...
...that can overcome its own disadvantage and keep evolving...
...is to have
them "learn'' death.
They have to die
along with Magi.
I suggest destruction
of the Magi System.
Impossible. To destroy Magi
means abandoning headquarters.
Then, I officially request
it from the tactical section.
I refuse. This problem should
be handled by the technical section.
Why're you so obstinate?!
This began from my mistake.
You're always like this, trying to handle everything by yourself.
You never ask others
for help, do you?
If the Angel keeps evolving,
I have a winning strategy.
To promote the evolution?
Yes.
The end of evolution is self destruction,
and that means death.
So, we just promote
its evolution, right?
If the Angel considers an effective way to avoid death, it might choose to live with Magi.
But, how?
Because the object is a computer, by connecting Casper to the Angel directly...
...we can hack and send a self destruct promotion program, but...
...at the same time, we have to drop the guard against the Angel.
Whether Casper's faster or the Angel's faster...it's a gamble.
Yes.
Can you prepare the program in time?
If Casper's infected, it's all over.
You have my word.
R alert announced,
R alert announced.
An emergency has occurred in NERV headquarters. Class D workers, evacuate.
What are those?
These are developer's notes.
Unbelievable. It's a hidden code...a hidden code for Magi.
It's a collection of
secret techniques, isn't it?
I feel guilty even looking at these.
Amazing, this is int-C...
We can program faster
than expected with these.
Thanks, Mom.
We can definitely make it.
Give me a wrench.
This reminds me of
our college days.
Board No.25.
Why don't you tell
me a little about Magi?
It's a long story,
and it's not very interesting.
Do you know about the transcribed personality operating system?
Yeah, it's a system to transcribe an individual's personality...
...to the 7th generation organic computer, and make it self aware.
It's a technology used for controlling the Eva also, right?
Magi seems to be the
first of that kind.
It's a technology which
was developed by my mother.
So, your mother's
personality was transcribed?
Yes.
This is my mother's
brain, so to speak.
Is that why you
wanted to protect Magi?
No. I didn't like
her very much.
So, I made that
decision as a scientist.
Here it comes!
It took over Balthasar!
The artificial intelligence
approved of self destruction.
It's begun?!
Self destruction will be commenced
in 02 seconds by an unanimous vote.
Effective depth, minus 280,
minus 140, floor zero.
Because of the current situation,
special order 582...
Balthasar has entered Casper.
It's getting ahead of us.
What speed...?!
Twenty seconds to
self destruct.
No!
Casper'll be taken
over in 18 seconds!
Fifteen seconds to activation
of the self destruct devices.
Ritsuko, hurry!
It'll be okay. I have about
a one second margin.
Ten seconds to self-destruct.
One second...?
Nine seconds...
Eight seconds...
It's not zero or minus.
Seven seconds...
Six seconds...
Maya?!
Five seconds...
Four seconds...
...three seconds...
...two seconds...
Push!
...one second...
Self-destruct was cancelled
by the artificial intelligence.
Alright!
Special order 582 was also cancelled. Magi system's returning to the normal mode.
R alert was cancelled,
R alert was cancelled.
All personnel, go to first alert.
What's really going on?
Geez, I can't go anywhere
'cause I'm naked!
Someone help me now!
Sigma Unit's open. Minus 03 to
resumption of the Magi system.
Am I already old?
Overnight work is so hard.
You kept your promise again.
Good work.
Thanks.
This's the first time I think
your coffee is delicious.
The night before my mother died, she said that Magi has three of her characteristics.
A scientist,
a mother and a woman.
Those three are in constant conflict with each other within Magi.
She purposefully
left human dilemma.
Actually the program
was modified a little.
I don't think I'll become a mother, so I don't understand that part of my mother.
I admired her
as a scientist...
...but I hated
her as a woman.
You're talking a lot today.
Sometimes.
Casper has the
pattern of a woman.
She kept her womanhood until the end.
It was just like her.
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
~~~~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Operators: Kouichi Nagano
~~~~~~~~~~~~Fujiko Takimoto
Translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
NERV and Seele manage the Human Complement Project behind the scenes.
They will revise the present
and the future of NERV.
Are all the incidents simply just a realization of a given scenario?
Next time:
"Seele, Throne of the Soul.''
And of course, service, service.