''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
SHIN SEIKI
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no these
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui  pathos
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
It was in 2015 A.D.
The Third Angel
Sachiel, attacks.
Ordinary weapons were ineffective against the Angel.
The UN aborted
the mission.
All authority transferred directly to the Special Institute, NERV.
Midnight, the same day, the Angel arrived above NERV headquarters.
The same day, they acquired...
...the Third Child.
Ikari Shinji
He agreed to be the pilot.
Evangelion Unit 01 launched for the first time.
NERV experienced its
first actual battle.
The first battle in Tokyo-3.
Eva Unit 01,
head damaged,
out of control.
Complete silence.
Then...
IT WENT BERSERK!
Interim report on the
"Battle in Tokyo-3.''
The person in charge: Planning Manager Captain Katsuragi Misato
As a result, we suffered
major damage, but...
...the challenge of an unexperienced boy in the first battle against the unknown target...
The Third Angel as well as Unit 01...
...developed an AT-Field.
...and the fact that he carried out the mission, were indeed admirable deeds by Ikari Shinji.
Unit 01 eroded the
target's AT-Field.
However, for the planning section...
...it was a hard battle that revealed further problems and many points to improve.
Angel, destroyed.
Intercept installation, slightly damaged.
Eva Unit 01, medium damage.
The victims in this
incident were not publicized.
My sister's in the second grade.
She was injured in that incident.
Excerpt from Suzuhara Touji's composition:
The injury wasn't due to the enemy, but to that wild robot on our side.
I can't forgive such a
ridiculous story, man!
I wanna make those adults, who made the robot, know my sister's pain and my anger.
The Fourth Angel
Shamusiel, attacks.
At that time, the performance of the surface-to-air intercept system was down to 48.2%.
The operational ratio of Tokyo-3's
battle formation was 96.8%.
Excerpt from Horaki Hikari's composition:
Since I'd practiced the evacuation training many times with classmates...
...it was just an everyday occurance.
I didn't actually realize the situation.
The boys were making noise as
if they were on a field trip.
We girls weren't
afraid of anything.
Angel arrives
above Tokyo-3.
The second battle in Tokyo-3.
Despite accidental cutoff
of power supply...
Angel, destroyed.
NERV obtained a sample of an Angel in its original condition.
However, the final analysis report is not being released.
The Fifth Angel
Ramiel, attacks.
Against the seemingly invincible target...
Captain Katsuragi's proposed
Operation Yashima was approved.
The First Child
The Exclusive Pilot of Eva Unit 00.
Ayanami Rei
Launched in the unfrozen Eva Unit 00 for the first time.
Midnight, the same day,
part of the Angel
penetrated the Geo-Front.
NERV executed Operation Yashima.
Excerpt from Aida Kensuke's personal diary:
Ikari didn't say anything.
But I think, at that time...
...Unit 00 protected Unit 01 with her life from the enemy's particle-cannon.
No, I am sure about that.
It's because of only one reason.
It's Ayanami.
It seems that she regards herself as being insignificant.
Operation Yashima successful.
Different from pessimism...
Eva Unit 00 heavily damaged.
But she already has
something like that.
However, the pilot survived.
She seems to be more mature than rest of us at the age of 14.
The Sixth Angel
Gagiel, encountered.
That incident was slightly
different from our scenario.
But the result was within the predicted margins. It's possible to correct.
The Second Child.
The Exclusive Pilot of Eva Unit 02.
Souryu Asuka Langley
Launches in Eva Unit 02 for the first time.
A close-range battle at sea...
And...
...the first underwater battle occured.
The battle was around the former Ito area.
Angel, destroyed.
During the battle, the UN navy
lost one third of its ships.
The ships lost were your country's.
That's negligible.
Right. It was fortunate that
damage was so light.
The Seventh Angel
Israfel, attacks.
It demonstrated the ability to separate and unite.
However, with the simultaneous double attacks by the two Eva units...
Angel, destroyed.
The Eighth Angel
Sandalfon was found in the Asamayama crater.
NERV issued order A-17.
A capture operation was carried out for the first time as a top priority.
It was briefly contained in
the electromagnetic cage, but...
...the cage was destroyed,
and the operation was aborted.
The objective was immediately changed to the destruction of the Angel.
Eva unit 02 carried
out the operation.
Angel, destroyed.
The repairs and modifications to Eva Unit 00 were completed, and...
...it returned to service.
The Ninth Angel
Matriel, attacks.
In the first joint operation of all three Eva units...
Angel, destroyed.
The Tenth Angel
Sahquiel, attacks.
Against the object that fell from the stratosphere...
...the three Eva units used a direct snare attack...
Angel, destroyed.
The Eleventh Angel
Currently, its invasion
remains unconfirmed.
Leaked information says that it directly invaded NERV headquarters.
This isn't going right.
It's too early.
Human complement committee special conference.
Right. We didn't expect an
Angel to invade NERV HQ.
This allowed the Angel to advance into Central Dogma.
If it had made contact, the whole project could have been jeopardized.
The report to the committee was false. There's no proof that an Angel invaded HQ.
Then, Ikari, you deny the
invasion of the 11th Angel.
Yes.
Be careful what you say at this conference. False testimony means death.
You can check Magi's recorder. It didn't record anything to support such a conclusion.
Don't make me laugh.
Coverups are your specialty.
The time schedule is proceeding as described in the Dead Sea Scrolls.
It's alright. We won't refer to your crime and responsibility this time.
But don't create
a new scenario.
I know. Everything will
follow Seele's scenario.
Episode 14
Seele, Throne of the Soul "Seele, tamashii no za''
Mountain. Heavy mountain.
It changes over a long period.
The sky. Blue sky. Invisible objects. Visible objects.
The sun. There's only one.
Water. Something comfortable.
Commander Ikari.
Flowers. There're many of the same ones.
There're many unnecessary ones also.
The sky.
Red, red sky.
The color red.
I don't like red.
Flowing water.
Blood.
The smell of blood.
A girl who never bleeds.
A human created from red clay.
A human created by a man and woman.
City. It's built by humans.
Eva. It's built by humans.
What is a human?
It's created by God.
Humans were created by humans.
I have a life...heart. A casing for the heart, the entry plug.
It's the throne of the soul.
Who is this?
It's me.
Who am I?
What am I?
I am myself. This object is myself. It's a shape of myself, a visible self.
But I don't feel
like I'm myself.
It's very strange.
I feel like I'm going to dissolve. I can't recognize myself. My figure's disappearing.
I feel someone else.
Is there anyone beyond here?
Ikari.
I know her.
She's Major Katsuragi.
Doctor Akagi.
Everyone. Classmate.
The pilot of Unit 02.
Commander Ikari.
Who are you?
What is your impression of being inside of the Unit 01 for the first time?
It smells like Ikari.
1st unit mutual compatibility experiment. Subject: Ayanami Rei
Synchro ratio is almost
the same as Unit 00.
Because the personal patterns of
Unit 00 and Unit 01 are similar.
That's why she
can synchronize.
Error is plus minus 0.03.
Harmonics, normal.
I can't find any problems in the compatibility between Rei and Unit 01.
The test is complete.
Rei, you can come back.
Okay.
87th harmonics experiment.
Subject: Souryu Asuka Langley.
The data bank of
Unit 02 is complete.
Harmonics, normal.
The pilot has no problem.
Of course not.
Unit 00 natural compatibility experiment. Subject: Ikari Shinji
What about the personal
data of Unit 00?
It's already rewritten.
Currently double-checking it.
What about the subject?
He's a little nervous, but there's no problem in his nerve pattern.
It's natural because this is his first time in Unit 00.
How stupid. He should forget
about it and relax.
Shinji's a boy who
can't do that.
I know.
That's why he's stupid.
By the way, this compatibility test...
I don't have to join in?
You have no intention of
piloting the other Eva, right?
Well, that's true.
Surely Unit 02
is incompatible.
The entry's begun.
LCL charged.
Start the first contact.
How do you feel about
Unit 00's entry plug?
I feel strange.
Are you uncomfortable?
No, it just
smells like Ayanami...
Smell...?
Is he perverted or what?
Data reception, confirmed.
Pattern, green.
Main power's connected.
Each binder has no problem.
Alright. Then, shift the compatibility test to the second stage.
Second contact
begun with Unit 00.
How is it?
As expected, he doesn't show as high a synchro ratio as with Unit 01.
Harmonics are all normal.
It's an acceptable figure.
We can start the project.
You mean the dummy system...?
Honestly speaking,
I'm not really...
I know you're not in favor, but we have to be prepared in order to survive.
I respect you, and I'll do my job,
but I don't understand.
It's difficult to live with
people if you're fastidious.
You'll understand that once you discover that you're ruined.
Start the third contact.
Self psychology graph's stable.
What do you think of mommy's breasts?
Or is that the womb?
Asuka, that creates noise,
don't bother him.
Okay, okay.
Why do they
only pamper Shinji?
Start connecting
the A10 nerve system.
Harmonics level, plus 20.
What's this?
It's coming into my head.
Directly...something...
Ayanami...?
Ayanami Rei.
This is the feeling
of Ayanami Rei.
Ayanami.
Or maybe not?
What happened?!
There's a problem in
the pilot's nerve pulse.
Psychological contamination
is in progress.
That can't be.
It's impossible at this plug depth.
It's not from the plug.
It's from the Eva.
Unit 00 is out of control.
Shut down all circuits,
and cut the power.
Eva's switched
to backup power.
It's still moving.
How's Shinji?
The circuit's cut off.
I can't monitor him.
Unit 00 rejected Shinji...?!
It's no use, the auto
ejection isn't working!
Is this going to be the same?
Is it going to absorb Shinji?
Rei, get out of there!
Unit 00 will be immobilized
in ten seconds...
Rei!
...nine...
...eight...
...seven...
...six...
...five...
...four...
...three...
...two...
...one...
...zero.
Unit 00's immobilized.
Hurry and rescue the pilot!
It wasn't trying
to kill Rei, was it?
Is this incident relevant to the previous accident with Rei?
I can't say at this moment...
...but we have to put Rei's data back and do a synchro test immediately.
As tactical chief, I request you do it immediately so it won't affect our operations.
I know, Major Katsuragi.
Unit 00 wanted to hit me.
I'm sure of it.
The next contestant is
a dog that can do math.
That's amazing.
She's the genius dog,
Kana, from Niigata.
Nice voice.
Do you understand what I say?
Oh, really?
Then, answer the question, okay?
325 minus 324 equals...?
Incredible. She's right.
The answer is one.
No, not this ceiling again.
Shinji's regained consciousness. There were no aftereffects of the contamination.
They say he doesn't
remember anything.
I see.
Neither Misato nor
Kaji will tell me.
Shinji doesn't know either.
What kind of
girl is the First?
Unexpected invasion of the Angel...
The Human Complement Committee knew
about it and accused us, huh?
They're boring people
who can only complain.
We have all the trump cards.
They can't do anything.
But you don't have to irritate them. It'll cause many problems if Seele comes forward now.
Everything's following our scenario.
There's no problem.
What about the accident with Unit 00?
It wasn't written in my scenario.
Unimportant. The resynchronization of Rei and Unit 00 was successful.
You're too concerned
with Rei, Ikari.
What about the
ADAM Project?
It's going fine. It's behind schedule by no more than 2 percent.
What about the
Longinus Lance then?
It's going as planned.
Rei's carrying it out.
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~
~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Committee: Takashi Nagasumi~
~~~~~~~~Katsumi Suzuki
~~~~~~~~~Takehito Koyasu
Translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Barbara
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Misato feels pressure while many of her friends get married.
In this f@#$%^g situation, the days of her twenties are almost over.
Is a reunion with
Kaji her last chance?
Next time:
"A Lie and Silence.''