Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
NEON GENESIS
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.  Young boy, become a legend.
I owe you again.
But you won't
make up for it, right?
As for the material which they demanded under the Freedom of Information Act...
...I dealt with them
using dummy information.
The administration's been preparing to amend the law, but that won't be possible.
Do I have to do something
for that plan as well?
No. Judging from your material,
that shouldn't be a problem.
Then, I'll proceed
according to the script.
Episode: 7
A Human Work
Good morning.
'morning.
My morning begins with THIS!
Not with coffee?
Traditionally, a Japanese style morning begins with rice, miso soup and sake, you know?
But "that'' is
your way, right?
What do you mean?
Do you remember who's on duty for breakfast this morning?
I can understand why you're
still single at your age.
Sorry that
I'm so uncouth.
And a slob, right?
Shut up.
I'm done.
Are you really
coming to school today?
Of course. It's a parent teacher conference about your future plans.
But, aren't you busy?
Don't worry.
It's part of my job.
Your job?
Hi, thanks for coming.
Wait a minute.
Misato, don't come out looking
like that. It's embarrassing.
Okay, okay.
Good morning, Ikari!
Hi Misato, we're off!
Take care.
Let's go!
Ironic, huh?
Well, it's a good sign that he's started to behave more cheerfully.
Hello.
He just left the house.
Guard him well.
Wow, she's here!
Groovy woman!
Who is that?
Ikari's guardian.
You mean, that beauty
takes care of him?
Idiots.
Oh, man!
Misato's really fine!
Oh, really?
Moreover, she's the planning
manager of Nerv! That's great!
Oh, really?
Aren't we lucky, Kensuke...?
It's because Shinji's such a baby.
Well, I'm sure
he's no match for us.
Touji and the guys don't know anything about her uncouthness.
If I had a
girlfriend like her...
...you'd have a hard life.
You don't
understand anything, "sir.''
Alright, YOU take care
of peace on Earth.
Let US take care
of Misato, alright?
Unit 01 has cooled down.
Move on to the second stage.
Peace on Earth.
That's what Eva is for.
What's Eva? The entry plug smells like blood, but I feel relaxed for some reason.
After all,
I don't know anything.
What about Unit 00's
biochest parts?
They're severely damaged.
We'll make it from scratch, but our supplemental budget's reaching its limit.
I wonder if we can relax a little
once Unit 02 arrives from Germany.
It might be the other way around.
The disposal of the Angels isn't cheap, right?
Really, they're so
stingy with the budget.
This place is supposed to be responsible for the future of humanity, right?
It can't be helped. Eva isn't the only one we have to deal with.
In order for the survivors to live,
they need more money.
Budget...? Then, is the
Commander at a conference again?
Yes.
He's up in the air.
His absence makes this
place quiet. Isn't that nice?
Excuse me. Would you
mind if I sit here?
The spending amendment for
recovering a sample passed easily.
The Committee takes their
survival as top priority.
They'll spare no expense.
They thought the Angels
would never appear again.
Oh, I have more good news.
All members of the Security Council, except the U.S., have approved the budget for Unit 06.
It's just a matter of time until the U.S. approves it.
That country has an
unemployment allergy, doesn't it?
What about your country?
We'll join in the production of Unit 08. The second installation plan is still valid.
The problem is, the pilot
hasn't been found yet.
Angels have appeared again.
There's no other way, but that,
to defeat them.
We don't want anything
like the Second Impact.
So, the Second Impact that evaporated Antarctica was...
Well, the history books explain it as a disaster caused by a massive meteor impact...
...but the truth
tends to be concealed.
15 years ago, mankind found the first humanoid creature called "Angel'' in Antarctica.
During the investigation,
it exploded for unknown reasons.
That's what we called
the Second Impact.
Then, what we're doing is...
In order to avoid a possible third impact,
Nerv and the Evangelions exist.
By the way, the event will
be held tomorrow as planned.
Alright.
Good morning.
G...good morning.
I'm going to
Old Tokyo on business.
I'll be late, so you'd
better order out.
Later.
O...okay.
NEON GENESIS
ABANDONED AREA #28 (FORMER TOKYO METROPOLIS)
It's hard to imagine that this was once a flourishing metropolis.
We've arrived.
There's no reason to do
this in a place like that.
Then, is the SSDF
involved in the project?
The Strategic Self Defense Force?
No, they weren't allowed.
That may be why they
can do what they want.
Thank you for coming to our exhibition of Nippon Heavy Industry Solidarity.
You will observe the official demonstration from the control room.
Do you have any
questions before that?
Yes.
Oh, you're the famous Dr. Akagi Ritsuko.
I'm very glad to see you here.
May I ask a question?
Yes, absolutely.
According to the earlier explanation,
it's equipped with an internal engine.
Yes. That's a major feature of the unit.
150 days of continuous operation is assured.
However, for safety reasons,
I think it's too risky...
...to install a reactor in weapons for close range ground combat.
I think it's much more useful than a weapon that doesn't work more than 5 minutes.
Remote control may cause a problem under emergency situations.
It's more humane than putting
a heavy workload on the pilot...
...which might result
in mental illness.
Stop.
It's childish.
Control by multiple personnel
might cause some problems.
It's safer than a dangerous
weapon that goes out of control.
A weapon without
control is nonsense.
It's just like a hysterical woman.
No one can deal with one.
That's what our technology
and pilots are for.
Do you really think that science and the human mind can control that monster?
Are you serious?
Yes.
Absolutely.
Because you believe in unreliable things, like human minds...
...Nerv allowed that uncontrolled incident to happen.
As a result, the U.N. had to pass a big supplemental budget...
...although there's a country where 20,000 people are suffering from starvation.
Despite the seriousness of that incident, the cause is still unknown.
I want you to be
a little more responsible.
You're lucky. Nerv is exclusively protected by law, and you aren't held accountable.
No matter what you say, only our main weapon can defeat the enemy.
You mean the AT-field?
It's only a matter of time.
Nerv's epoch won't last forever.
Damn, those low-lifes...
That must be the revenge of those who failed to acquire concessions from Nerv!
I'm so pissed...
Stop.
It's childish.
He wants to show off and wants to be praised. He's a small guy.
But how did they
know about the AT-field?
Top secret information
seems to be leaking.
What's the intelligence
section doing?
Now, we'll begin
the demonstration of JA.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Please watch from
the window there.
Ready to start.
Start the test.
Start all engines.
Pressure, nominal.
Cooling system circulation,
nominal.
Extend the
control rods fully.
Engines have reached
the critical point.
Power, nominal.
Start walking.
Walk ahead slowly.
Move right foot ahead.
Roger. Walk ahead slowly.
Balance, normal.
Engines, nominal.
Roger. Next stage.
Move left foot ahead.
Check.
It's walking normally. It looks like it's worth being proud of.
What's happening?
Something's wrong. The reactor's
internal pressure is increasing.
The temperature of the primary coolant is also coming up.
Release the valves!
Inject reactor coolant!
No good!
Pumping power won't come up!
No. Stop the engine.
Command an emergency stop.
Transmission of the
abort signal confirmed.
It's not accepting!
The communication
system's not working!
It's out of control!
Impossible.
That robot's as rude
as the guy who made it.
There's a problem
in the compressor.
The control rods
aren't working.
At this rate, there's
a danger of meltdown.
I...can't believe this...
JA was programmed to react to
all possible emergency situations.
This shouldn't be happening.
But right now, we're facing
the danger of a meltdown.
Under the present conditions, there's nothing to do but wait until it stops by itself.
How likely is
it to stop?
0.00002%.
It'll take a miracle.
We'd better do something other than wait for a miracle. Tell me how to stop it.
We've tried everything.
No. There must be a
way to reset everything.
Tell me the
password to do it.
The deletion program is confidential.
It's not my decision.
I don't have
the authority.
Then get
the authority...
...right now!
It's me. Connect me to Mr. Manda at Tokyo-2.
Yes, the Minister of Home Affairs.
Oh, concerning that matter,
Mr. Yasugi will deal with it. Ask him.
That's too serious to allow with a verbal order.
You need written authority.
Then, we have to ask Mr. Yoshizawa
for permission, is that right?
Yes, I've received permission from Mr. Witz.
Yes. Alright. Later then.
No one wants to
make the decision.
The order will be given soon.
The operation will be official.
We can't wait for that!
It'll be too late once it explodes!
The "Jet Alone'' is
heading towards Atsugi.
There's no time. I'll do it on my own authority. Excuse me.
Hey, Hyuuga? I've already talked to the people in Atsugi...
...so send Shinji and
Unit 01 in F configuration.
Yes, it's an emergency.
It's impossible.
Stop this, Capt. Katsuragi.
How are you
going to stop it?
With human hands, directly.
Are you serious?
Yes.
But, the interior will be full of radiation. It's too dangerous.
If I succeed,
everyone'll be safe.
When the control signal from here is off,
you can open the hatch manually.
You can enter
through the backpack.
"Hope...''
It's the password
to delete the program.
Thank you.
The target is JA. There's a danger of meltdown in 5 minutes.
So, we can't allow it to get
close to the residential area.
Hyuuga?!
Yes?
After launching Eva, get out of here.
Climb to a safe altitude.
Roger!
Shinji.
Yes?
Run with the target,
and put me on its back.
After that, do your
best to stop the target.
Are you going to
get inside it?
Yep.
That's crazy!
I know it's crazy.
But there's no other way.
It's too dangerous.
No problem. Eva can withstand a possible explosion.
I didn't mean that!
I mean you...
Well, I have to do what I can.
Otherwise, I'll regret it.
Target sighted.
Let's go.
Eva in dropping position.
Docking out!
Roger!
I caught up!
Less than 4 minutes left.
Put me on it!
It's alright. Do it!
Misato!
Be careful.
Man, it's hot!
This's bad.
Stop, damn you!
Misato, hurry!
Here it is.
"Hope''
Error?
How come?
No doubt.
The program has been altered.
Power reactor,
0.2 to the critical point!
Control rods
are malfunctioning!
It's sink or swim...
Misato, escape!
Move! You bastard!
Misato!
0.1 to the critical point!
It's no use,
it's gonna explode!
Is this the end...?
MISATO!
She did it!
Internal pressure, down!
All normal!
We're saved!
She did it!
She did it! She did it!
That idiot.
Misato, are you alright?
Misato?
Yeah, but this really sucks...
I'm glad that you're safe.
I'm so glad!
It's great. I underestimated you!
The miracle happened!
Yes.
That "miracle'' was already
prepared by somebody.
Recovery of Unit 01 completed.
There's no danger of radiation.
Except for the act of Capt. Katsuragi,
everything went according to the script.
Well done.
`morning...
Now, it's shower time...
Where are my
bra and panties?
Good morning, Ikari!
Good morning. I am off!
Take care.
Misato is really nice.
I thought so before, but she's so embarrassing at home.
She's uncouth, bad-looking, and a slob.
It's embarrassing
to see her.
I envy you.
How come?
Ikari is really a baby.
Really.
How come?
You get to see the true side of her that she doesn't allow us to see.
That's very much
like a family.
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~~
~Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi
~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~~~
~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Shirou: Yoshitada Ohtsuka
~~Man: Kouichi Yamadera
Boy: Kouichi Nagano
Announce: Megumi Hayashibara~
Initial Translation
Kentaro Onizuka
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
EVA 02 and its pilot embarked from Wilhelmshaven, Germany for Japan.
Shinji gets confused because
of a strong-minded girl.
Next episode:
"Asuka Arrives in Japan.''