Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
NEON GENESIS
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.
Young boy, become a legend.
Did you see her ?
Yes! Yes!
What?
Don't you know
that foreigner?
Foreigner?
Yeah, that transferee to
2nd year, Class A, last week.
She's really good.
I heard her name's
Souryu Asuka Langley.
She's truly cute.
She has returned from abroad.
I wonder if she's more mature.
Don't be silly.
I guess she had a difficult separation in Germany.
And she can't recover from her wounded heart in an unfamiliar country.
Everyone keeps saying,
"Asuka,'' "Asuka.''
Everyone looks relaxed.
Thanks again.
The pictures don't show
her true personality.
Hello, Shinji.
Guten Morgen.
Guu...guuten morugen.
You even look gloomy
in the morning.
It is "I'' who's talking to you.
Why don't you look more pleased?
And the other
one's here too, right?
Who?
Are you stupid?
Who else, but
the First Child?
Oh, Ayanami...
Hello!
You're Ayanami Rei,
the pilot of the prototype.
I'm Asuka. Souryu Asuka Langley,
the pilot of Eva Unit 02.
Be my good friend.
Why?
Because it's convenient
in many ways.
If I'm ordered to,
I will.
You're strange.
That's true. I guess only the eccentric ones're selected as Eva pilots.
You lost weight,
didn't you?
Have I?
You're in a sad love.
How do you know that?
Because those who have a mole in the path of tears are destined to weep all the time.
Are you going to seduce me?
But it won't work, because
a SCARY lady's watching us.
Long time no see, Kaji.
Well, it's been a while.
You're a little more
careless than I remember.
He was stupid,
and he still is.
Since Unit 02's transfer is finished,
why don't you go home?
I was officially notified of my transfer this morning. So, I'll be staying here.
We can hang out together,
like we used to do.
Who'd want to...?
Enemy attack?
Report from the
on station cruiser, "Haruna.''
"We detected a gigantic object near Kii peninsula. We're sending data.''
Received data analyzed.
Wavelength pattern, blue,
it's a confirmed Angel.
All personnel,
first class battle stations.
Episode #9
Momentarily
Unite the Minds.
Tokyo-3's intercept system was heavily damaged in the previous battle.
Currently, only 26%
has been repaired.
Our operational equipment for this battle is almost zero.
So, we'll defeat the target before it reaches land.
Unit 01 and Unit 02 will
continuously attack in turns.
It'll be a
close range battle.
Roger.
This's my combat debut in Japan,
why aren't I allowed to fight alone?
It can't be helped.
That's the plan.
Let me remind you. Don't do anything that disturbs me.
Why was a boy like him
selected as a pilot?
It's unfair to attack together.
I don't like it.
We don't have any other choice,
if we want to survive.
It's coming!
Commence the attack.
OK, I'll go first.
Cover me.
Cover you...?
Ladies first!
Damn, newcomers
shouldn't take control.
I can do it!
Good job.
How about that, Third Child?
Battle must always be
elegant and without waste.
That's cheating!
At 10:58:15 a.m. today...
...Unit 01, attacked by Target "A,''
which separated from the original...
...and was sunk two kilometers
from Suruga Bay.
Twenty seconds later, Unit 02, attacked by Target B, was also immobilized.
Here's a comment from the person in charge of Operation E.
"They look bad.''
Geez. My combat debut was
messed up because of you!
What are you talking about?!
It's because you did something moronic!
Moronic?!
How can a slow boy like
YOU say that?!~~Of all the nerve!
Say what?! Because you were in such a hurry to win, it turned into a big mess!
Look at that!~~It's like a corpse in the sea!~~It's so uncool!
Nerv aborted the operation at 11:03 a.m...
How can YOU say that?!
...and gave command to
the U.N.'s Second Force.
It's so humiliating.
At 11:05, they attacked the target with an N-2 bomb.
We have to
redraw the map again.
They succeeded in incinerating
28% of its components.
They got it?
That only retarded its motion.
The next attack is only a matter of time.
Well, it's fortunate that we gained some time to prepare another plan.
Listen, you two, do you
understand what your job is?
To pilot Eva.
No!
To defeat the Angels.
Nerv doesn't exist to
commit such dishonorable actions.
Therefore, you must
cooperate with each other...
With someone
like him?!
like her?!
Oh, forget it.
Why do people
get angry so easily?
Adults don't like
being humiliated.
Excuse me,
where's Misato?
Cleaning up
the aftermath.
There's someone in charge who
exists to take responsibility.
These are complaints and the damage reports from the ministries involved.
And, here's an
invoice from the U.N.
There are complaints from
the publicity section.
You need to
look them over.
I already know
what they say.
They say, "If you're
going to fight, do it there.''
Good guess.
Without being told, they'll fight once the Angels are defeated.
I'll defeat that Angel.
The Sub-commander is very angry.
If you humiliate him again,
you'll doubtlessly be transferred.
It was good luck within bad luck
that Commander Ikari was absent.
And before you saw these,
you'd have been fired.
Then, you brought some good ideas so I won't be fired, right?
Just one.
Great, Dr. Akagi Ritsuko!
A kind old friend is all I need.
You're wrong. It's not me
who's saving an old friend.
Kaji came up
with this one.
Kaji did?
I'm back....
...but no one's here...
What the hell're these?
How rude.
That's my stuff.
W...why're you here, Souryu?
Why're YOU still here?
Still here?
You're unnecessary.
Misato is going
to live with me.
Well, that'd be the right choice,
considering who's better.
To tell the truth,
I wanna live with Kaji.
Anyway, why're Japanese
rooms so small?
Half of it wouldn't
even fit in here.
And, why do Japanese
people lack precautions?
How can you live in
a room without a lock?
Unbelievable.
Because the Japanese believe in understanding and kindness.
Misato.
Welcome home.
You two seem to be doing well.
Doing what?
Preparation for
the next operation.
What do
you mean?
The seventh Angel has
only one weak point.
A simultaneous concentrated attack on both cores is the only way.
In other words, that's an attack by two completely synchronized Evas.
In order to do so, you have to cooperate for a perfect unison.
So, you're going to
live together from now on.
What?!
No, I won't!~~They say men and women should live separately after age 7!
The Angel
is regenerating.
The second attack is predicted in 6 days.
We don't have time.
That's impossible.
Well, to make
the impossible possible...
...you have to memorize the attack pattern, harmonized with this music...
...as soon as possible,
within six days.
NEON GENESIS
I wonder what
happened to Shinji.
He's been absent from school for the last three days.
Oh, Class Rep.
Two of the idiot trio.
How come you're here?
I've come to see Souryu.
Why are you here?
To see Ikari.
Why'd you
stop here?
Coming!
You've betrayed us.
You're in that
pair-look again. That's sick.
This is because Misato said, ''Japanese should begin things with appearance.''
You two are so indecent!
It's a misunderstanding!
It's nothing like a
misunderstanding or overstatement....
Oh, welcome.
Please tell us what
this is all about.
You should have
told us first.
So, is their
unison going well?
See for yourself...
It's so obvious! I can't adjust
"down'' to Shinji's level!
It was impossible
in the first place!
Then, you're giving up?
There's no
one else, right?
Rei.
Yes.
Give it a try.
Okay.
Maybe it would be better to change the plan,
and have Shinji team up with Rei.
No, I can't stand
this any more!
A...Asuka!
That's called,
"Tears in the devil's eyes.''
Ikari!
Follow her!
You made her cry!
You should take responsibility!
Um...
Don't say anything.
I know.
I must pilot Eva.
I'll do it.
We must triumph
over Rei and Misato.
Wha...triumph over...?
How could you be so naive?
You are a man, aren't you?!
I must have revenge
for my hurt pride!
Where's Misato?
Working. It's gonna be an all nighter.
She said so on the phone.
Then, we're
alone tonight.
This's the indestructible
wall of Jericho.
If you cross this wall,
you'll be executed!
Children shouldn't
stay up late.
How can the Japanese
sleep on the floor?
Unbelievable.
Mama...
You're a child, too.
No, someone'll see us.
Who will?
Who?
Geez. You're no longer my boyfriend.
Don't do this again.
But, your lips
didn't say, "stop.''
Your lips or your words...
which should I trust?
Here.
Thank you.
It's rare to see you sober.
For some reason...
Work, or a man?
Many things.
Still in love...?
Don't be ridiculous!~~Who could
love that kind of guy?!
Even though I was young, it was my biggest disgrace that I hung around with him.
Well, I was
talking about Kaji.
Did I upset you?
You are...
Your anger proves
that I hit the mark.
You should be more frank.
Things are different from 8 years ago.
Nothing's changed.
He's still immature.
Oh well, I've got work to do.
The final battle is tomorrow.
Target's passed our final defense line at Goura.
Here it comes.
We won't fail this time.
When the music starts,
expand an AT-field.
Then, proceed as planned.
Okay you two?
Got it.
Target's entered
the mountain region.
Listen, we'll begin the full performance at full speed, okay?
I know. We'll finish
it in 62 seconds.
Target's arriving
at point zero.
Purge the external
power supply.
Launch.
Both Evas confirmed.
Ouch.
Looks bad.
Hey, look what you've
done to MY Unit 02?!
It's not my fault!
You hit me first!
It was "you'' who
missed the timing first!
It's because
you're always slow!
Besides, why were you awake so late last night?
I was doing image training
for today's battle.
Liar! You tried to kiss me while I was sleeping, didn't you?
It's not fair to
pretend to be sleeping!
That's terrible!
I was only joking!
So, you really did it!~~You kissed me!
No, I didn't!
I stopped!
Lech, molester, pervert!
I can't believe this!
It was your fault for
sleeping in the wrong bed!
They're humiliating us again.
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~~
Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi~
~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
Asuka: Yuko Miyamura~~
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kiyokawa~~
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki~~~
~~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
~Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
~~~Ryouji: Kouichi Yamadera
Touji: Tomokazu Seki
Kensuke: Tetsuya Iwanaga
Hikari: Junko Iwao~~~~
Initial Translation
Onizuka Kentaro
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
In the crater of Mount Asama lies an unhatched Angel.
NERV personnel attempt the first capture of an Angel
An Eva with special equipment challenges the fires of Hell!
Next episode: "Magma Diver.''
Next time, service, service.