Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
Neon Genesis
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.
Young boy, become a legend.
A.D. 2015
Today at 12:30, a special state
of emergency has been declared...
...throughout the Kanto and Chubu
districts around the Tokai Area.
Please take refuge in
your designated shelter.
I repeat: Today at 12:30,
a special state of emergency...
How could I miss him now, of all times?!
What am I gonna do?
All normal lines are down due to the special state of emergency.
No good.
I knew I shouldn't
have come.
Look here!!
I may not be
able to meet her.
Oh, well. Guess I'll
go to the shelter.
The unidentified object
is still approaching.
We've got a visual image of the target.
I'll transfer it to the main screen.
It's been 15 years.
Yes, it has.
Angels....
EPISODE 1:
ANGEL ATTACK
All missiles hit the target!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
The target is still intact.
As before, it's moving toward Tokyo-3.
Our airforce
can't stop it.
Total war! Mobilize all divisions at Atsugi and Iruma bases!
Don't hold back!
Smash the target at all costs!
How?! It must've
been a direct hit!
The tank battalion was totally destroyed. Guided missiles and artillery have no effect...
It's hopeless! We'll get nowhere with such poor firepower!
It's protected by an
AT-field, as we expected.
Yes, normal weapons have
no effect on Angels.
Understood. I'll employ that,
as previously arranged.
Whoa, it can't be!
They're gonna
use an N2-mine?!
Get down!
We did it!
Sorry, but there's
nothing left for you to do.
Incoming shock wave!
Are you all right?
Yes, but something in
my mouth is crunchy.
That's fine.
Are you ready?
Here goes!
Thanks for your help!
Er, it was my pleasure,
Miss Katsuragi...
You can call me Misato.
Nice to meet you,
Ikari Shinji.
Same here.
Target status?
We can't see
it due to EMP effects.
It was such a massive explosion.
It's must've been destroyed.
Sensors on line.
Energy reaction in the
center of the explosion!
WHAAAT?!
Visual image restored.
That was our trump card...
Unbelievable...
Damn monster!
Sure.
Don't worry.
His protection is my top priority. Prepare a car train for us; a linear one, please.
Yes, I'll take full responsibility for him, since it was my idea to meet him. Bye.
But this sucks!~~I just had this car restored, and now it's a wreck.
33 loan repayments to go...
and the repair costs....
Um, Misato....
Even worse, my only good clothes have been ruined....
Eh, what?
Is it okay that
you did that?
Ah, it's okay, no problem.
It's an emergency.
We can't do anything
if the car doesn't run.
In addition, even if I don't look like it, I'm an international officer. So it's okay.
That doesn't seem like
a very good excuse.
Boring boy! You look so calm, despite your pretty face.
You think so...?
Hmm, are you angry?
Sorry, sorry.
It's natural because you're a boy.
You're childish for
your age, aren't you?
It's regenerating,
as we expected.
Otherwise, it would be useless
as an independent weapon.
Oh, impressive. It can also
enhance its own functions.
In addition, it has
acquired intelligence.
It's only a matter of
time until the next attack.
The gate is closing. Attention, please. The train is about to depart.
The special agency, Nerv?
Yes, a special organization directly attached to the United Nations.
It's the one my
father belongs to, isn't it?
Well, yeah...do you
know what he does?
My teacher told me it's an important job to protect the human race.
You're now the commander of this operation. We'll see how you deal with it.
Yes, sir.
Ikari, considering our
available weapons...
...I have to admit we have no effective way to deal with the target.
Are you confident
you can defeat it?
That is why
Nerv exists.
We expect much from you.
The target remains unchanged.
The present effective rate
of interception is 7.5%.
The U.N. troops can't help it.
What are you going to do?
I'll activate Unit 01.
Unit 01?
But we don't have a pilot.
No problem. A back-up
pilot will arrive shortly.
Are we going to
where my father is?
Well, yeah...we are.
Father....
By the way, were you given
an I.D. by your father?
Oh, yes.
Here it is.
Thanks!
Then, read this.
"Welcome to
Nerv...
It's about my father's work.
Is there anything for me to do?
I can't say I'm surprised. He never writes me, unless he wants me to do something.
I see. You consider
him a tough customer.
I feel the same.
Awesome!
A real Geo-Front!
That's right. This is
Nerv's secret headquarters.
It's also the foundation for rebuilding the world for the human race.
NEON GENESIS
This's strange. I'm sure
this was the right way....
I'd really rather not
wear a skirt in this place!
Anyway, where has Ritsuko gone? Sorry, but I'm not familiar with this place.
We passed here
some time ago.
But it'll be okay!
All systems exist to be used.
Chief of Project E, Section 1
of the Technical Department...
...Dr. Akagi Ritsuko,
Dr. Akagi Ritsuko.
Please contact Capt Katsuragi Misato at Section 1 of the Operations Dept. immediately.
I don't believe it!
She must've gotten lost again.
Umm...Hi, Ritsuko...
What are you doing, Captain Katsuragi?
We're short of hands and time!
Sorry.
Is he the one?
Yes, according to Marduk's report, he's the "Third Child.''
Nice to meet you.
Ah, the same.
He's very much like his father...
neither one is lovable.
Well, I'll leave
the rest to you.
This will be their first
meeting in three years.
Sub-Commander, the target has begun to move again.
Okay!
All hands to battle stations!
Repeat: All hands to battle stations.
Prepare to intercept the enemy on the ground.
Hear that?
That's serious.
By the way,
how is Unit 01?
It's configured with Type-B equipment.
It's being cooled.
Does it really work?
I heard that it hasn't worked yet.
The possibility of it working is 0.000000001%.
O9-system seems like a good name for it.
You mean it
won't work, don't you?
How rude!
It isn't zero.
It's only a number. Anyway, to say "it doesn't work at all'' will be no excuse.
It's pitch black.
A face...
A gigantic robot...
You won't find
this in the manual.
This is humanity's Multi-Purpose Humanoid Fighting Machine, EVANGELION.
This is Unit 01. It was built in secrecy. This is mankind's last chance.
Is this also Father's work?
That's right!
Been a while, hasn't it?
Father....
Move out.
Move out?!
Unit 00 is frozen.
You don't mean that
you're activating Unit 01?
We have no choice.
Hey! We can't
have Rei pilot it!
We have no pilots!
One has just arrived.
Are you serious?
Ikari Shinji...
Yes?
...you will pilot it.
But it took Ayanami Rei seven months to synchronize with Eva!
He just arrived.
It's impossible.
Just take a seat. We don't expect you to do any more than that.
But....
At present, intercepting the Angel's attack is our top priority.
Even if there is little potential of synchronizing with Eva.
We have no choice.
Do you understand, Captain Katsuragi?
You may be right....
Father, why did
you call me?
For exactly the
reason you think.
Do you mean that I should pilot this, and fight against that thing I saw?
Of course.
No way! Why're you saying this now?!
I thought you didn't want me!
I only called you
because I need you now.
Why me...?
Because others can't....
I can't do it! I've neither seen
nor heard of it!~~How can I do it?
Listen to her explanation.
No...I can't!
It's impossible!
If you're getting in, stop wasting time. Otherwise, go home!
That bastard has found us.
Shinji, there's no time.
Please get in.
No way! After coming
all this way, it's ridiculous.
Shinji...Why did
you come here?
Don't run away from your father,
or above that, from yourself.
I know.
But I don't think I can do it!!
Fuyutsuki.
Wake up Rei.
Is she available?
Well, she isn't dead.
I understand.
Rei.
Yes.
The back-up turned out to be useless. Try again.
Reconfigure Unit 01's
systems for Rei! Restart!
Yes, ma'am. I'll stop the current process and restart it.
As I thought,
I'm unnecessary.
Watch out!
Eva moved!
What happened?!
It tore off the binding
attached to its right arm!
Impossible! The entry plug hasn't even been inserted yet! It can't move!
It reacted without
the interface...
Or rather,
did it protect him?
He can do it!
Don't run away. Don't run away. Don't run away. Don't run away. Don't run away....
I'll do it!
I'll pilot it!
Cooling process complete.
The binding of the
right arm has been fixed.
Position setting for
docking in the cage is okay.
The stop signal plug
has been discharged.
Roger.
Insert the entry plug.
Plug, locked in place.
Begin the first connection.
Inject LCL
into entry plug.
What's this stuff?!
Don't worry. After your lungs fill with LCL, it'll directly supply you with oxygen.
You'll get used
to it soon.
I feel sick.
Live with it!
You're a boy, aren't you?!
Connect the
main power supply.
Transmit power
to all circuits.
Yes, sir.
The second contact
is beginning.
The connection of the
A10-nerve is operational.
Set Japanese as
command interface.
All initial contacts
are all right.
Connect the mutual lines.
Rate of synchronization is 41.3%.
Incredible!
All harmonic values are normal.
Everything is under control.
It'll work!
PREPARE FOR LAUNCH!
Prepare for launch!
Release the
first lock bolt!
Released.
Move the umbilical bridge!
Release the
second lock bolt!
Remove the first binding,
and then the second.
Cancel first through
fifteenth safety locks.
Internal battery charged.
Socket for external
power supply is operational.
Roger. Eva Unit 01
to the launch pad.
The course is clear.
All green!
It's ready to launch.
Roger. Are you
sure about this?
Of course. We have no future
unless we defeat the Angels.
Ikari, are you
really sure about this?
Launch!
Shinji... Don't die.
TO BE CONTINUED
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi~
~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
~~~~~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kyokawa
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki
~~~~~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Initial Translation
Wada Mitsuhito
Additional Translation
and song translation
Hiroaki Fukuda
Editing
Todd Perkins
Hiroaki Fukuda
Dave
Brain
Timing
Todd Perkins
Subtitled by
Central Anime(Kansas)
NOT
FOR SALE
OR RENT
Preview
Eva defeats the Angel,
but that's only the beginning.
Shinji runs away from his father and insists on staying alone...
...and Misato tries to help him.
Next time: "Unknown Ceilings''
Oh yeah, and I'll have fanservice for you as well!