''zankoku na tenshi no youni''
''shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
SHIN SEIKI
''aoi kaze ga ima mune no DOOR wo tataitemo''
''watashidake wo tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata''
''sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuude''
''unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi''
''dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou sono senaka niwa''
''haruka mirai mezasu tame no hane ga aru koto''
''zankoku na tenshi no THESE
~ madobe kara yagate tobitatsu''
''hotobashiru atsui PATHOS
~ de omoide wo uragiru nara''
''kono sora wo daite kagayaku shoonen yo shinwa ni nare''
Mama!  Mama!  They selected me!
I'm an elite pilot, about to protect
mankind.  The best in the world.
It's a secret to everybody.
But I'll tell you, Mama!
Everybody is so nice to me,
that I'm not lonely.
I'm OK, even though I don't have a papa.
So, look!  Look at me!
Hey Mama!
Start making sense, you idiot!
How many times do I have to say it?!
Kaji-san's not here anymore!
Oh...
Synchro ratio zero.
I've no capacity to be the Second Children.
I've no reason to exist.
No one looks at me.
Not Papa, Mama, or anybody.
There's no reason for me to live.
You are Soryu Asuka Langley?
The second section of the Intelligence Division
says the Second Children was captured alive.
I see.  They found her 7 days after
they lost her.  That isn't like them.
Maybe it was on purpose, then.
The Planning Division is
trying to make trouble for us.
I see.
And today the Fifth will arrive to replace Asuka.
The scenario is too prearranged.
Ayanami Rei.
It may be correct...  that impression.
My mother...
Ayanami Rei...  and my mother...
What are you doing with them...  Father?!
Commander Ikari...
My cat died...
...which my grandmother
had been taking care of.
I hadn't been taking care of it for a long time.
Suddenly, I can't see it again.
Why did you destroy the Dummy System?
It's not the Dummy System,
but Rei who I destroyed.
I ask you once more.  Why?
Now, I'm not happy even if you hold me.
You can do anything you like
to my body, as you did before.
I was disappointed by you.
Disappointed?!  You have neither
expectations nor hopes for me.
I have nothing...  nothing...  nothing...
What should I do, mother?
Where has Asuka been?
What should I talk to her about?
Tell her about Ayanami?
Toji and Kensuke lost their houses
here and went away somewhere.
No friends...  I have no friends here.
No one.
I don't want to see Ayanami.
I lost the courage to see her.
How should I act with her?
Asuka...
Misato-san...
Mother...
What should I do?  What?!
A song is good.
A song brings us joy.
A song is the highest culture
that Lilims have created.
Don't you think so?
Ikari Shinji-kun.
You know my name?
Everyone knows your name.
Excuse me, but you'd better be
aware of your own position.
Is that so?
Umm, who are you?
I'm Kaoru.  Nagisa Kaoru.
of the Seashore)
Just like you, I'm one of the selected
children.  I'm the Fifth Children.
Fifth Children?!
You...  Nagisa-kun?
Call me 'Kaoru', Ikari-kun.
Alright, call me 'Shinji'.
Reportedly, the Fifth Children has just arrived.
Nagisa Kaoru.  The record of his life
has already been deleted, like Rei.
One thing we know is that his birthday
is the same day as Second Impact.
The committee sent him
directly to us.  He has something.
The information on the Fifth in the Marduk
Report is not permitted for publication.
For this reason, I secretly investigated
the data in the Intelligence Division.
Oh, you risked too much.
The risk was worth it.
I know where Ritsuko-san is.
How are you going to do
the synchro test for the Fifth?
I don't have any plans to cheat
today.  Let's see his ability.
Down 0.3 more.
Yes, sir.
Are there any mistakes in this reading?
The testing system is operating normally.
No data error detected by the Magi.
It's amazing that this boy synchronizes
with Unit 02 before replacing the core.
Yet, I can't believe it.
I mean, it's impossible on this system.
Nevertheless, it's a fact.
We must accept the fact and
then investigate the cause.
So you're the First Children?
Ayanami Rei.
You're the same as me.
We've both taken the Lilim's form
as our body to live on this planet.
Who are you?
I hear that the Fifth boy contacted Rei.
Is that so?
The Magi are doing their best
to scan the data on the Fifth.
Still, we don't know yet what he really is.
What is he, that boy?
Authorized Personnel ONLY
If you enter without my
permission, you shall die!
Entry Forbidden!
Shinji-kun hasn't returned.
I'm disqualified as his guardian.
Central Dogma is now being opened.
Use the 3rd route for the transfer.
Hey, you were waiting for me?
Oh, no I did...  I didn't mean to.
Today is?
Well, the usual test was over and I was
going to take a shower before I went home.
But, I don't want to go home these days.
You have a house, or a home to go to.
That fact makes you happy.  That's nice.
Is that so?
I want to talk with you some more.
May I go with you?
I mean to the shower.
Aren't you going to shower?
Yeah...
You mean 'no'?
Oh, yes.  I don't mean 'no'.
You avoid contact of the first kind at all costs.
Do you fear to feel other people?
Being ignorant of others, you will never
be betrayed or hurt, though you will
never escape from feeling sadness.
A person can't erase sadness
forever.  Everyone is alone.
However, people can forget,
and so they are able to live.
It's time.
It's over?
Yeah, we have to go to bed.
Together?
No, you are provided with
your own, different room.
Well...
People always feel pain in their hearts.
The heart is easy to wound,
that's why living is painful.
In particular, your heart is fragile like glass.
Me?
Yes, worthy of love.
Love?
I mean, I love you.
Episode 24'
The Final Messenger
[  note:  this can also be read as  "The Final Death" or even  (phoenetically)  ' The Final Seashore '  ]
Nerv, the system established to act under Seele.
Founded to play our scenario.
Now, it has been exclusively
taken by one person.
Aye, we must take it back.
Before the promised day.
Let Nerv and the Eva
series be as they should be.
Ikari, you are responsible for betraying Seele.
The time remaining to us is short.
And, now we don't have the Lance of Longinus
that would prevent us from realizing our hopes.
The final Angel will soon appear.  When
we erase that, our hopes will come true.
Wait a little longer, Yui.
Why am I here?
Why am I still alive?
For what?
For whom?
The Fifth Children.
He looks...
...something like me.
Why?
We are lucky because we
live in the suburb of the city.
You weren't involved, I'm glad about that.
Yet, next time I can't guarantee that.
So, you'll be taken care of at
Horaki-san's from tomorrow on.
So long, Pen Pen.
Really, I should be on the floor.
No, it's me who asked you to let me stay here.
It's OK if I sleep here.
What do you want to say?
You have something that you want me to hear.
I've experienced many
things, since I came here.
I was at my sensei's before.
Those were silent and calm days.
I did nothing but exist.
But that was fine with me.
I had nothing to do.
Do you dislike people?
Well, I don't really care.
Except for my father, who I hate.
Why am I talking about this
kind of thing with Kaoru-kun?
I might have been born to meet you.
Humans are unable to create
something out of nothing.
They must have something to start
with, because humans aren't gods.
But there's a man who seeks
to gain power equal to God's.
There's a man besides us who
wants to reopen Pandora's Box.
And who wants to close the
Box, before Hope can appear.
Hope?  That's the Lilim's hope?
There are as many forms of
hope as there are people.
Because hope exists only
in the hearts of people.
But our hopes are materializing...
In Lilith, progenitor of humanity - the
false successors from the Black Moon...
And in Adam, progenitor of Angels - the
true successors from the lost White Moon.
And whose salvaged soul
resides only within you...
But whose revived body is already inside Ikari.
Shinji-kun's father...  Is he like me?
That's why we now entrust our hope to you.
I know...  for that's the reason I'm here now.
It's no good, I can't read his lips from here.
Still, going for a walk at this early
hour just to talk to yourself...  time
for some serious psychiatric work.
Did he notice me?
No, impossible.
Everything is going according
to the Lilim's plans.
Well?  Do you have his data?
Here you go.  I borrowed this from First
Lieutenant Ibuki without her permission.
I'm sorry that I made you
do something like a thief.
What's this?
It's quite natural that Maya-chan can't
publish this.  It's theoretically impossible.
Hmm, yes.  The mystery increases.
He can arrange any Eva synchro
ratio freely, by his own will.
We must do anything we can, without
considering what others think.
You dared to come here?
I have one thing to ask you.
This conversation is being recorded.
I don't care.
What is that boy, the Fifth?
Probably...  the final messenger.
Well, let's go.
Come, Adam's alter ego,
and the servant of the Lilim.
Eva Unit 02 started!
What the hell?!  Where's Asuka?
In hospital room 303.  It's confirmed.
Then who is...?
It's unmanned.  Entry plug hasn't been inserted.
Unmanned?  Isn't it the Fifth?
AT Field generation detected in Central Dogma.
Unit 02?
No, pattern is blue.
No doubt.  It's an Angel!
What?
An Angel?  That boy?
Target passing by the fourth level.  Still descending.
No good.  Can't disconnect the power
supply to the Linear Motor Car.
Target passing by the fifth level.
Close all bulkheads in Central Dogma!
Anything to gain time.
Close all levels up to the Fifth Malebolge.
All personnel, evacuate.  All personnel, evacuate.
Seele dared to send it directly to us.
The old men are trying to
advance the schedule, using us.
People forget their foolishness
and repeat the same mistakes.
People won't change if they
perform their own atonement.
We won't rely on Adam or the Angels.
We must advance into the
future by our own means.
Eva Unit 01, fulfill your duty.
Armored bulkheads broken
through by Eva Unit 02.
Target passing the second level.
Eva Unit 01 will pursue.
Yes, sir.
Use any means.  Don't allow the
target to invade Terminal Dogma.
But why is the Angel using Unit 02?
Is he trying to unite with Unit 02?
Or to lead it to destruction?
No No No!  Kaoru-kun is...  an Angel?!
It must be a lie!!
It's true.  Accept the facts.
Sortie, OK?
Shinji-kun hasn't come yet.
Eva Unit 01, descending through route 2.
Pursuing the target.
You betrayed me!
You betrayed my heart!
You betrayed me like my father!
Unit 01 has reached the fourth layer.
Contacting the target.
You're here.
I've been waiting for you, Shinji-kun.
Kaoru-kun!
Asuka, sorry!
Eva series, created from Adam,
the beings detested by humans.
Still the Lilims are trying
to survive by using them.
I can't understand why.
Kaoru-kun, stop!  I don't see why!
Eva is made of the same body as me.
Because I'm also born of Adam.
When the unit doesn't have
a soul, I can unite with it.
The soul of Unit 02 is shutting itself up now.
AT Field!
Yes, you Lilims call it that.
The holy region that must
not be invaded by anyone.
The light of the soul.
You Lilims are aware of that.
Aware that the AT Field is the
wall of the soul that everyone has.
I don't understand that, Kaoru-kun!
Both Eva units have reached the final level.
20 meters until the target
reaches Terminal Dogma.
If something happens to Unit 01,
after the signal disappears...
I know.  You're going to
self destruct this place.
It's better than letting Third Impact take place.
I'm sorry.
Not at all, if I can die with you.
Thanks.
The destination of people?
The hope of people is the thread of sadness.
What's that?!
The strongest AT Field we've ever seen!
Light waves, electromagnetic
waves and particles are shut out.
We can't monitor anything!
That's a field?
The target, Eva Units 02 and 01, all missing.
Can't connect to the pilot.
Kaoru-kun!
Wait!
Final safety system released.
Heaven's Door is opening.
The Angel has arrived?
Hyuga-kun...
What?!
Status?
It's an AT Field.
Another AT Field, similar to the previous one,
has been generated around Terminal Dogma.
Invading the other field.
Impossible.  Does that mean another Angel?
I don't know!  I can't confirm it!
I mean, it vanished.
Vanished?  An Angel?
Adam, our mother being.
Those born from Adam must return to Adam,
even if it means annihilating humanity?
No!  It's different.
Lilith!
I see.  I understand, Lilim.
Thank you, Shinji-kun.
I wished you'd beat Unit 02.
Otherwise, I might have lived with her.
Kaoru-kun, why?
I've been destined to live forever, even
if humanity is annihilated as a result.
However, I'm able to die.
To be or not to be.
It makes no difference to me.
My death is the only absolute liberty.
What are you talking about?
Kaoru-kun, I don't understand
what you're talking about!
Kaoru-kun...
My last words.
Now, please erase me.
Otherwise, you'll be erased.
The life that escapes the time of annihilation,
and that obtains the future, is only one.
And you aren't the one who must die.
All of you need the future.
Thank you.  I'm glad...  to have met you.
Kaoru-kun...
...said, 'I love you'.
To me!
For the first time...  For the
first time I heard those words.
He looked like me.
And Ayanami.
I loved him.
Kaoru-kun should have
been the one to survive.
He was much better than I am.
He should have survived.
No.
A survivor only needs the will to survive.
He wished to die.
He abandoned the will to live,
and depended on false hope.
You weren't wrong, Shinji-kun.
You're cold, Misato-san.
Neon Genesis Evangelion
Episode 24'
Created by: GAiNAX
Subtitled by: deus X anime
http://www.deusxanime.com/
Script version: 1.12
Source:  DVD [KIBA-6]
Translations:
TV scenes - Kentaro Onizuka
(Literal Translation Series Edited by Matthew Opel)
Revised scenes - Bochan_bird
Editing:  deus
Timing:  deus
Special Thanks to Kotus for Sub Station Alpha
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi~
~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
~~~~~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kyokawa
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki
~~~~~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Preview
Next episode: "Air"