In the year AD 2000
The Super Solenoid theory
proposed by Professor Katsuragi?
It's just too far-fetched!
It's still just a theory...
Even so, the S2 theory is the only way to
explain the source of that giant's power.
I heard that Ikari's team is leaving
on the 11th of next month.
I wish they'd locate the smoking sections closer.
And it's already been proven,
even if it was by accident.
There was talk about making the entire facility
non-smoking, so just be happy with what you've got.
The fact that it exists means
that it must be accepted.
Scientists...
they believe too much in their own ideas.
I'd have to leave here if that happened -
I can't work without my cigarettes.
I'll accept it when and only when
all the data has been verified.
It's cold, the food is bad...truly a god-forsaken
place at the end of the world.
What about the Lance of Longinus?
Self-flattery.
It's still where it was brought ashore after
arriving from the Dead Sea last week.
And they argue too much...
Endless criticism and speculation.
Isn't some processing necessary
before taking the Lance underground?
And people like that are given charge
of the truth...  How ironic.
What?  Not "A" lunch again?!
Will it be okay?
Damn, I could kill for some Osaka sushi!
The physical contact experiment is
scheduled for the 13th of next month.
'God' is not that lofty of an issue...
There's plenty of time for any adjustments.
Discovery is fine and well,
but they'll never understand it.
All they seek is
their own exaltation.
It's surpassing calculated predictions!
Block out surface lights!
Emergency...  Emergency...
The DNA that dived into
Adam is physically uniting!
All personnel put on your protective clothing.
Workers below level two please evacuate
to upper area of Central Dogma.
Fields have gone down.
The Lance!  Pull back the Lance!
up!
We can't!  The floor isn't holding up!
It's sinking!
We have to prevent further
damage as much as possible!
Break down the atomic structure, but
keep it within the quark range!  Hurry!
When the Gauf doors open, start the cooling!
Amazing!  It's starting to walk!
Even if only for a half a second, we have to
put an anti-AT Field around him!  Get enough
energy to generate an anti-AT Field!
The conversion system is already set!
Countdown has been activated!
The S2 engine and the explosive system
are being linked!  We can't stop it!
The wings are spreading!  It's going to surface!
Like a cruel angel...
...young boy, become a legend.
Neon Genesis
Even though the blue wind knocked at the door of your heart...
...you kept looking and smiling only at me.
Lost while searching for something soft...
...your honest eyes show that you haven't realized your fate.
But someday, you'll recognize that on your back...
...you have the wings to fly to the distant future.
A cruel revelation from the angels will fly out from a window soon.
When you deny your memory with your spurting and burning pathos...
Shine and hold up the sky.
Young boy, become a legend.
Hello, I'm away right now.
Please leave your message after the beep.
My last job...
It's red, just like blood.
~~ Nerv, the Birth ~~
Kidnapped?  Our vice commander?
It was two hours ago.
He has been missing since he
entered the 8th district in the west.
That's inside of this installation.
You guys in the Division of Intelligence
did nothing to stop it?
An insider was spying on us
and lead the operation.
We were outwitted by that person.
Someone who can baffle the Second
Division of Intelligence.  It can't be...
Kaji Ryoji is suspected to be
the leader of this plot.
That's why you came to see me.
You can help us a great deal,
because you think quickly.
As your colleagues, we truly regret
having to suspect the Chief of Operations.
However, this is our job.
Considering our past,
it's the only natural reaction.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Take her away.
It's been a long time, Chairman Kihl.
This is a very crude way of welcoming me.
There is no need for the
Commander to be called here.
We need to have a long discussion
with you, and this is the best way.
You never change.  You don't take
my situation into account.
The problem we are addressing now has already
emerged.  The consequences are inevitable.
Please understand that.
Not the committee, but Seele
itself has finally appeared.
We have no intention of
creating a new god.
We hope for your cooperation,
Fuyutsuki-sensei.
Fuyutsuki-sensei...
Sensei!  Fuyutsuki-sensei!
AD 1999
Kyoto
Oh, it's you guys.
How about having a beer
by the Kamo River?
Again?
Ryoko and the rest say
they'll come if you do.
The professor also says you
should come more often.
Alright, I see.
It's not bad to drink outside,
given the opportunity.
Well...
You're very talented, though it's not
good for you to underestimate the importance
of communication between people.
I'm sorry.
By the way, Fuyutsuki-kun...
...there's a student who wrote an
interesting report on biotechnology.
A student named Ikari...
do you know the name?
Ikari?  No.
I told Ikari about you.  She
said, "I wish to see him."
You'll be contacted by her.
Please see this student.
Her name is Ikari-kun.  I understand.
Metaphysical Biology
First Research Lab - Fuyutsuki
I've read this.
I have two or three questions, although
it's quite a stimulating report.
Thank you very much.
You are Ikari Yui-kun.
Yes.
What are you going to do from here?  Are you
going to join some commercial company...
...or maybe join this lab?
I hadn't considered that.
And, there may be a third choice.
I'm also thinking about getting married.
I mean, if I meet a nice person.
AD 2015
Again
Incorporating the S2 unit into itself,
it's obtained the ultimate existence.
Evangelion Unit 01.
A living god created by us.
It's blasphemy.
The creation of a god is not allowed.
I won't allow him to have a god.
Ikari Gendo, can we trust you?
Rokubungi Gendo?
Well, I've heard the name.
AD 1999
Again
Well, I've never met him...
...though he generates a lot of rumors.
Kyoto Prefecture Police Office
Eh?  I was appointed as his advisor.
Yes, I'll visit him.
When is a good time?
I've heard rumors about you from people.
I've been wanting to meet you.
You were drunk and got into a fight.
That's so pathetic.
Before I had said anything, they
picked on me for no reason.
I'm not used to being liked.
I am used to being hated.
That's not my concern.
Fuyutsuki-sensei, you're exactly the
kind of person that I expected.
My first impression of him was
that he was a real bastard.
In those days, this country still
had seasons.  It was autumn.
Is that true?
Yes.  I'm going with Rokubungi-san.
When I heard that, I
couldn't hide my surprise.
You walk with that guy?
Oh, Fuyutsuki-sensei...
...he's such a cute man...
...it's just that no one knows it.
Ignorance can be a source of happiness.
I introduced you to him.
Were you disturbed by that?
No.  I admit that he's an interesting
guy, but I don't like him.
However, it was commonly accepted
by those who knew, that the objective
of his approach to Yui-kun...
...was her talent and the support of the
organization backing her.
That organization was called Seele,
according to the rumors I heard afterwards.
AD 2000
Antarctica
Second Impact...
...in the last year of the 20th
century, that tragedy took place.
AD 2001
In the first year of the 21st century,
there was nothing but time.
A year that had nothing else to say.
AD 2002
Aichi Prefecture -
The remains of Toyohashi City
They say it's going to be
another day of midsummer winter.
It's quite hot down here.
That's nothing new for the present Japan.
It's been summer for almost an
entire year now.  It takes its toll on you.
You're not going to move
up to the other boat?
You mean in the neighboring town?
That place still reeks of oil.
I can't get used to it.
Still, that's no reason to
open a practice here.
It took quite some time to find you.
They don't have enough doctors here.
I'm just acting like one,
but it's better than no doctor at all.
The South Pole?  Now?!
An official investigation of the incident
ordered by the UN Council.
It's only a temporary investigation...
...but I believe you would be far more use
to the world there, rather than working
here as an unlicensed doctor.
Professor Fuyutsuki...
That's 'ex-professor'.
By the way, my column is blank...
Who recommended me?
Same year - Antarctica
Was this the land of ice?
It hardly looks it.
Professor Fuyutsuki...
Oh, it's you.  You survived?
I hear that you participated in
the Katsuragi investigation team.
Fortunately, I returned to Japan the day
before the incident, and I escaped that tragedy.
Is that so?  Rokubungi-kun...
Excuse me, I changed my surname.
A postcard?  Not a business card?
We have married.
Ikari Yui
& Gendo
It's been a long time!
How are you?
Ikari!  Ikari Gendo!
My wife asked me to give you this.
She's a fan of yours.
I'm honored.
Ikari Yui & Gendo
a long time!
How are you?
How is Yui-kun?  Isn't she
participating in this expedition?
She wanted to come,
but we have a child now.
Your organization, Seele or whatever,
is creating a lot of bad rumors.
I don't like the way that it controls
the committee by force.
You're still too scrupulous.
In this age, no honest
organization can survive.
If this official investigation commission
were composed only of Seele personnel,
there would be a lot of trouble.
Were we assigned to avoid trouble?
AD 2015
Nerv Headquarters - 4th Isolation Ward
I still hate the darkness.  It brings
memories of nothing but horrible things.
Who is she?
The only survivor of the investigation commission.
AD 2002
South Pole Observatory Ship -
2nd Isolation Ward
Her name is Katsuragi Misato.
Katsuragi?  Is she
the daughter of Dr. Katsuragi?
Yes.  She hasn't spoken for two years.
How terrible.
She witnessed that hell.
Her physical injuries healed, but
mental injuries are hard to fix.
That's right.
It's difficult to figure out the
results of this investigation.
A change in atmospheric components
over a perfectly defined area...
The complete extermination of all
life right down to microorganisms....
The remains of a giant underground
cavity below the blast center...
And this giant of light...
This incident is surrounded by mysteries.
Afterwards, the United Nations officially
declared that the Second Impact was caused
by a massive meteor collision.
However, to me, that was obviously
fabricated information.
Behind it, there was Seele
and the man named Kihl.
I tried to find out the truth
about that incident...
AD 2003
Hakone
...even if the name "Ikari Yui"
was involved.
The Artificial Evolution Lab.
Under the direct control of the United Nations.
It's been a while.
Yes, it has.
Why do you hide the
existence of the giant?
You already knew that Second Impact
was going to happen, didn't you?
You told me that you returned the
day before the incident.
Was it also just good fortune that you returned
with all of the research results as well?
I didn't expect that these sort of
things would have escaped destruction.
I investigated your estate in detail.
I understand you need a lot of money to
educate a child.  But the amount was too
great to be possessed by one person.
Oh, the great Professor Fuyutuski.  How
about moving to the economics faculty?
I'll publish the truth behind Second Impact,
you, Seele, and the Dead Sea Scrolls.
I can't forgive the people who caused that.
As you wish.
But before that, I have
one thing to show you.
We're getting down very deep.
Are you worried?
Slightly.
What is this?
We didn't create it.  Someone left this cavity
behind, although 89% has been buried.
Then, this was originally a
spherical underground space.
Just like the underground
cavity in Antarctica?
The data is almost identical.
Do you intend to bring
about that tragedy...
...again?!
Why don't you see for yourself.
This is the installation which is
consuming all that humanity has.
Oh, Fuyutsuki-sensei!
Akagi-kun, you're here too?
Yeah.  This is the best place to investigate
the fundamental theory of the bio-computer
which we are attempting to create.
I'm going to name them the Magi.
Magi, the three wise men from the east?
Is this what you wanted to show me?
No.  This way.
Ritsuko, I'll be back soon.
This is...
Is this that giant?
We of Gehirn call that object Adam.
This is different.
Then...
Yes, the Adam created by humans, Eva.
Eva?
Our project to revive Adam is referred to
as Project E.  This is the model for the
project, Eva Unit 00.
The prototype of a god?
Fuyutsuki, let us create a new
era for humanity, together.
AD 2015
Umm, senpai...
Oh, sorry.  Let's hurry with Rei's re-test.
I haven't seen Katsuragi-san today.
Well, neither have I.
Katsuragi-san?
Yeah, Katsuragi Misato,
nice to meet you.
AD 2005
Second New Tokyo City
Mom, the other day, I happened
to meet a girl named Katsuragi.
University of Second Tokyo Campus
People always stare at me from a distance.
It forces me to remember the
importance of your name.
She's different.  She's really
honest, even with me.
I hear that she is the only survivor
from the investigation commission.
It seems that she was once mute.
But now she is quite talkative, like
she's trying to make up for those days.
Rit-chan, I'm always underground.
I'm tired of having the box
lunches they provide.
On the surface, the construction
of the Third Tokyo City has started, as a
result of the second capital transfer plan.
For a couple of days, Misato was absent
from school.  I forced her to tell me why.
She's such an idiot!
She had been at her apartment, in bed
with her boyfriend for a whole week!
I was impressed to hear
about another side of her.
Today, she introduced me to the guy.
He's handsome, but I'm
not used to his frivolity.
You've been afraid of boys
for a long time, Rit-chan.
That's because you were
only brought up by a mother.
Sorry, I've always let you do as you liked.
I'm terrible.  I'm your mother
only when I wish to be.
Mother...
AD 2003
Hakone - Lake Ashinoko Levee
The same weather day after day...
The disappearance of autumn from
this country is sad beyond words.
According to the scenario in Seele's secret
Dead Sea Scrolls, Third Impact will definitely
occur in a little over ten years.
Seele and Gehirn - organizations
for preventing the final tragedy.
I support your intentions, not Seele's.
Fuyutsuki-sensei, it would be terribly
dangerous to break that seal onto the world.
I've given all the materials to Ikari.
It's not something one can do alone.
We won't repeat what happened last time.
Oh, and I've also been given a warning...
It seems that it would be no
trouble at all for them to erase me.
And those who survived as well.
It's easy to exterminate people.
Still, that's no reason for
you to become a test subject.
Everything happens as it must.
That's why I'm with Seele,
for Shinji's sake...
AD 2004
Hakone - Second Underground
Experimental Installation
Why is there a child in here?
This is Chief Ikari's son.
Ikari, this is not a day school.
This is a very important day.
Sorry, Fuyutsuki-sensei.
I brought him here.
Yui-kun, it's your experiment today.
That's why.  I want to show the
promising future to my child.
Those were the last words from Yui-san.
A freak accident erased her from this world.
Just as I had wished.
What a disgusting woman I am.
Rit-chan, after that day, Chief
Ikari completely changed.
GLASS
Where were you this week?
I know you're depressed...
...but your body doesn't
belong only to yourself.
I know.  Fuyutsuki, today I'm
starting a new project.
I've already made the proposal
to Chairman Kihl.
You're going to do it?
Right.  The way to become a god,
which no one has achieved.
The Human Instrumentality Project.
AD 2008
Mom, congratulations on completing
the basic theory behind the Magi.
I have good news, to congratulate you with.
It has been informally decided
that I will officially join Gehirn.
Starting next month, I will
be engaged in Project E.
Who are you?
Akagi Ritsuko of the Technology
Development Division.  This is my ID.
I hear that the basic installation of the
Command Center has been completed,
so I came here to see it.
Well, it's just like a maze in here.
The Chief and Doctor Akagi will
see you in the Command Center.
Are you really all right?
I don't have regrets about my job.
You lie!  You still remember Yui-san.
But that's fine with me.
AD 2010
Geofront - Artificial Dome Portion
Lower Level, 2nd Direct Support Area
(Planned Site)
That's Gehirn Headquarters.
Chief, good morning.
Did you bring your child?
Oh, but it was a son...
This isn't Shinji.  I decided to take
care of an acquaintance's child.
Her name is Ayanami Rei.
Rei-chan, hello.
This child looks like someone.
Yui-san?!
All the files concerning Ayanami
Rei have already been deleted.
White paper.
What does this mean?
Completed
Magus Casper...
Magus Balthasar...
Magus Melchior...
The Magi are three of myself.
Me as a scientist, me as a
mother, and me as a woman.
These three are in conflict with each other.
Three moms.
The only thing you have to
do is to switch the power on.
Today, I'll be leaving early.
Misato is coming back.
Oh, yes, I heard she joined Gehirn.
In Germany, as I remember.
Yes.  The third branch office.
A long distance relationship?
I hear that they broke up.
Oh, they seemed to be such a good couple.
Things between man and woman are difficult
to understand, because they're not logical.
You're always cold about such things.
You might lose your happiness.
The definition of happiness is
even more difficult to figure out.
Well, it's been a while since
I went out to drink.
Good work.
What?  Do you have something
to ask me, Rei-chan?
I've lost my way.
Oh, then let's leave together.
No need.
But you can't get back by yourself.
That's none of your business, hag.
What?
I can get home by myself.
Leave me alone, hag.
You shouldn't call someone a hag.
You are a hag, aren't you?
I'm getting angry!  I'll ask
Chief Ikari to scold you.
It's the Chief who calls you that.
That's...
That hag is stubborn, that hag is now useless.
hag...  hag...
It's the Chief who calls you that.
...that hag is stubborn.
...useless...  useless...
You're useless, because there are
substitutes even if you die, Rei.
You're the same as me.
The Human Instrumentality Committee,
chaired by Kihl Lorentz...
...immediately dissolved the
research organization Gehirn.
In order to carry out the whole project,
the special institute Nerv was established.
And we all moved to Nerv,
except for one person...
...who had rendered remarkable
service to the Magi system, Dr. Akagi.
AD 2015
Well...  here I go.
It's you.
Yes, it is.
It's been awhile.  The guards are sleeping.
This action will result in your death.
All I want is to get closer to the truth...
...within me.
Besides, it seems they're catching on
to the fact that I smuggled the Adam
sample for Commander Ikari.
If I don't start looking out for myself,
things could be looking grim...  for me.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Oh, this soon?
Yes.  The case was solved.
I see.
How is he?
I have no idea.
Yo, you're late.
I'm back.
Katsuragi, it's me.
I'm sure you're listening to this message,
after I caused you so much trouble.
Sorry.
Please tell Rit-chan "I'm sorry".
And there's one more thing to trouble
you with.  I've been growing flowers.
I'd appreciate it if you
could water them for me.
Shinji-kun knows where they are.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Don't hesitate.  Move ahead!
If I can see you again, I'll say the
words that I couldn't say 8 years ago.
Bye.
It's 2 minutes past 2.
Idiot.
You're such an idiot.
That time, I did nothing but
run away from Misato-san.
There was nothing else I could do.
Nothing I could say, since I'm a child.
That's what I realized.
Shinji: Megumi Ogata~~~
Misato: Kotono Mitsuishi
Ritsuko: Yuriko Yamaguchi~
~~~~~Rei: Megumi Hayashibara
~~~~~~Gendou: Fumihiko Tachiki
Fuyutsuki: Genmu Kyokawa
Makoto: Hiro Yuuki
~~~~~Maya: Miki Nagasawa
Shigeru: Takehito Koyasu
Neon Genesis Evangelion
Episode 21'
Created by: GAiNAX
Subtitled by: deus X anime
http://www.deusxanime.com/
Script version: 1.12
Source:  DVD [KIBA-6]
Translations:
TV scenes - Kentaro Onizuka
(Literal Translation Series Edited by Matthew Opel)
Revised scenes - Bochan_bird
Editing:  deus
Timing:  deus
Special Thanks to Kotus for Sub Station Alpha
Preview
Surpassed by Shinji again, Asuka falls into a dark pit of despair,
and damage from the next Angel attack is even more horrifying.
Shinji can find no words to soothe her shattered soul.
Next Episode: "At Least, Be Humane"