Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
Once again, I owe you.
You’re not going to pay me
back anyway, are you?
Regarding the materials they demanded
under the Freedom of Information Act...
...I handled it by giving them
some falsified data.
The government is proceeding with
legal action, but that will be
blocked any day now.
So, should I do something about
that project as well?
No, judging by the material you sent
me, it would appear that there will
be no need for that.
Then I’ll continue with the plan.
Episode 7:
The Human
Creation
Good morning.
G’morning.
This’s the way to start your morning!
Not with coffee?
Look, a traditional Japanese breakfast
begins with rice, miso soup, and sake.
Not all Japanese breakfasts,
just Misato’s.
What’s that supposed to mean?
Come to think of it, who was supposed
to do the cooking today?
Now I know why you’re still
single at your age, Misato.
Well, excuse me, but are you
saying that I’m lazy?
And sloppy too.
Leave me alone!
I’m done.
Are you really going to come
to school today?
Of course, it’s your parent–teacher
meeting, after all.
But you’re so busy with your work.
No problem.  This is part of my
responsibilities, anyway.
It’s part of your job, huh?
Hi!
Oh, thanks for coming!  Yes, he’s
getting ready.
Misato, you shouldn’t go out like that.
It’s embarrassing.
I know.
Good morning, Mr. Ikari!
We’re taking off now, Misato!
Take care!
Come on!
How ironic...
It’s good that it’s getting easier
for him to express himself.
Yes?
He’s just left.  Please stand
guard over him.
There!  She came!
Cool!  Who is she?
Is she Ikari’s guardian?
What?  He’s got a babe like that
for a guardian?!
Those guys are dorks.
She’s gorgeous, truly gorgeous!
Is that so?
It’s amazing that someone so
beautiful could be NERV’s
Director of Operations.
Is that so?
It’s just an academic counseling session,
but my mother just had to dress up!
Thank God, Kensuke, he’s such a baby.
It’s just an academic counseling session,
but my mother just had to dress up!
Yeah, Shinji’s no rival for us!
It’s just an academic counseling session,
but my mother just had to dress up!
Yeah, Shinji’s no rival for us!
Don’t you think she’s silly?
You guys don’t know what
a slob she is...
Man, I wish she were my girlfriend.
Yeah, and you’d have to put up
with a lot of trouble.
You just don’t get it, do
you, Mr. Big Shot?
Okay, you can handle keeping the
Earth safe and peaceful...
...and we’ll take care of Misato!!
Unit 01 has achieved the
required cooling level.
Shifting operations to Stage 2.
Keeping the Earth safe...
...that’s what Eva is for.
Come to think of it, just what is the Eva?
The entry plug smells a lot like blood.
But why do I feel so comfortable
and relaxed here?
Now that I think of it, I don’t
know anything about it.
What’s the status of Unit 00’s
bio-chest components?
It was seriously damaged.
So we’ll have to make an entirely new
one, even though it’s close to
our ancillary budget.
Will our job get any simpler once
we get Unit 02 from Germany?
It could go just the other way.
Disposing of the dead Angels
costs a bundle.
Yeah, this place is ridiculously
underfinanced...
...especially since mankind’s future
rests on what we do here.
It can’t be helped.
“Man cannot live by Eva alone.”
All those survivors need
money to live, too.
Money!
So, is the Commander off to
another conference?
Yes, he’s on board and en route now.
Thank God, a little peace and quiet.
Excuse me, do you mind if I sit here?
The revised budget for the sample
collection passed quite
easily, didn’t it?
The committee’s main concern is for
their own survival.
They aren’t stingy when their
own lives are at stake.
Yes, they used to think there
were no more Angels.
But I have more good news.
All permanent members of the Security
Council except the United States...
...have approved the budget
for Eva Unit 06.
It’s just a matter of time before
the US approves it as well.
The Americans seem to be allergic
to unemployment.
And what about your country?
We will participate beginning with
the construction of Unit 08.
The plans for the second installation
project are still viable.
However, a pilot has not
yet been found.
The Angels have returned.
We have no choice but to defeat them.
We do not want a repeat of
the Second Impact, either.
So, you’re saying that the Second
Impact that evaporated
Antarctica wasn’t...
Yes, the history texts say that
it was a disaster caused by a
massive meteorite...
...but sometimes the true facts have
been concealed.
Fifteen years ago, in Antarctica,
mankind discovered the being
known as the first “Angel.”
In the middle of the investigation,
however, for unknown reasons,
the Angel exploded.
That is the real truth about
the Second Impact.
Then, the things we’re
doing here are to...
...to prevent a probable Third Impact
from happening.
That is the purpose of NERV
and the Evangelions.
By the way, the demonstration will
occur tomorrow, as scheduled.
I understand.
Good morning!
G...good morning.
I’m going to Old Tokyo on business.
I’ll probably be getting back late
tonight, so have something
delivered for dinner.
See ya!
O... okay.
It is hard to believe that this place
used to be the flourishing capital
known as Tokyo.
We’re here.
Why are they having it in
a place like this?
Is the DF getting involved?
The Strategic Self Defense Force?
No, they’re not allowed to interfere.
I see, so that’s why they can do
whatever they like.
Good afternoon, welcome to this
demonstration...
...of Japan Heavy Chemical Industrial
Cooperative’s new product.
Thank you for attending.
You will be observing the official
demonstration from the control room...
...but we’ll be taking your
questions here.
Yes...
Ah, the famous Dr. Ritsuko Akagi.
It is our honor to have you here.
May I ask a question?
Of course, certainly!
According to our earlier briefing, this
unit is equipped with an internal
nuclear reactor.  Is this correct?
Yes, this is one of our product’s most
distinguished features.
150 consecutive days of operating
power is assured.
But, from a safety perspective...
...isn’t incorporating a nuclear reactor...
...in a land-based weapon designed
for hand-to-hand combat, risky?
It’s more practical than a weapon that
won’t work for more than five minutes.
But in an emergency there could be
problems with remote control.
But it’s more humane than a system that
induces tremendous mental stress and
causes mental instability.
Cut it out.  This just makes
you look childish.
And there’s still the issue
of manual operation.
A weapon that cannot be
controlled is insane.
I believe that it is safer than...
...an extremely dangerous weapon...
...that can run out of control
and go berserk.
It’s like a hysterical woman!
In other words, completely
out of control!
Our pilots and technology are up to
the task of controlling it.
So, you’re saying that science and
human courage will tame that
hideous beast?
Are you serious?
Yes, of course I’m serious!
And because it depends on something
as vague as the human heart...
...NERV has allowed the situation to get
completely out of control.
As a result, the UN has had to
approve an enormous supplement
to your existing budget.
And as a result of that, 20,000 people
in several unnamed countries
are starving to death.
Of course, the actual cause of all this
is still under investigation.
Why don’t you at least take
responsibility for your handiwork?
I envy you.  How fortunate it must
be for NERV to be protected by
a super-legal act.
It doesn’t matter what you say, the fact
is that NERV has the only weapon
capable of defeating the enemy.
You mean the AT Field?
It is just a matter of time now.
NERV’s day in the sun
will not last forever.
Damn it!  Idiot!
Who does he think he is?!
That SOB’s just pissed at being
cut out of the profit loop!
That goddamn son of a bitch!!
Damn it!  Damn it!
Cut that out, behave yourself.
He’s just a show-off, begging for
praise and adulation.
He’s petty, not worthy of attention.
But how did he know about
the AT Field?!!
How could something so
classified leak out?
Intelligence must be dragging its ass.
We’re about to start the JA activation
test.  Don’t worry, there’s no risk at all.
Please, make yourselves comfortable
and watch through that window.
Ready to begin.
Start the test.
Discharge the power core.
Pressure levels, nominal.
Coolant system circulation, nominal.
Release the control rods.
The reactor has exceeded
threshold levels.
Output is nominal.
Begin walk cycle.
Walking.  Forward ahead, slow.
Forward right leg.
Roger.  Walk, forward ahead slow.
Balance is nominal.
Power core status, nominal.
Roger.
Now, forward left leg.
Keep her steady.
It walks!  Now that’s something
to be proud of.
What’s wrong?
This is odd.  The pressure inside the
reactor is increasing.
The temperature of the primary
coolant system is also rising!
Open the release valve.
Insert the neutron-deceleration fluid.
No effect!
The pump output isn’t increasing!
Shut off the power.  Emergency stop!
Abort signal transmission confirmed.
It’s not accepting it!
The radio circuit is being blocked!
It’s out of control!!
It can’t be!
No!  Oh, God!  Run away!
That robot is as badly behaved as
the guy who built it.
The compression valve is
operating irregularly!
The control rods aren’t working!
Possibility of meltdown imminent!
It’s unbelievable...
JA’s been programmed to handle all
possible contingencies!
This kind of thing can’t happen!
Yet, the fact is, the danger of a
meltdown is now before us!
Under the present circumstances,
our only option is to wait for it
to stop itself.
And what is the estimated probability
of an automatic stop?
0.00002%!  We’d better hope
for a miracle!
Determined efforts are better
than a miracle!
Tell me how to stop that thing!
We’ve tried every possible option.
Not yet.  There’s got to be a last resort,
a way to wipe everything out.
Give me the password.
The password to delete all
programming is top secret.
I can’t authorize it.
I’m not allowed to tell you!
Then get the clearance!
Right now!!
It’s me.  Let me speak to
Mr. Manda in Tokyo-2.
That’s right, the Director
of Internal Affairs.
Well, I’ll have to delegate
this to Mr. Yasugi.  Ask him.
I can’t give you authorization for such
an important matter orally.
Could you submit a written request?
So, now I need to get
Mr. Yoshizawa’s permission?
What?  Yes, I’ve already got an
approval from Mr. Witz.
Yes... yes, okay.
The evasion of responsibility...
A written order of clearance
will be sent.
That will make this an
official operation.
We can’t wait for it to get here!  Once
the thing explodes it’ll be too late!!
Jet Alone is heading for Atsugi.
Time is running out.
I’ll take responsibility for this myself.
Excuse me.
Hey, Hyuga?
I’ve already made arrangements with
Atsugi.  Bring Shinji and Unit 01 with
the F Equipment.
Yes, this is an emergency.
This is pointless.  Call this off,
Captain Katsuragi.
Do you have any idea how to stop it?
By inputting a direct
command manually.
Are you serious?
Yes.
But the interior must be flooded
with radioactivity!
It’s too risky!!
But if I make it, everyone will be saved.
The hatch can be opened manually
as soon as our command
signal is cut off.
You’ll be able to enter through
the backpack.
“Hope.”
That’s the password to delete
the programming.
Thank you.
JA is the target.
There’s a danger of meltdown
in five minutes.
Therefore, we cannot allow it to get
any closer to a populated area.
Hyuga?
Yes ma’am?
As soon as you drop off Eva,
ascend to a safe altitude.
Affirmative.
And Shinji...
Yes.
Run alongside the target and
place me on its back.
Then restrain the target
as best you can.
Are you going to get inside?
Yeah.
That’s crazy!
I know, but there just isn’t
any better way.
But it’s too dangerous!
No problem.
Eva can withstand a direct explosion.
Not that!  I meant for you, Misato!
Well, I’ve got to give it my best shot...
...or else I’ll regret it for the
rest of my life.
Target sighted.
Here we go.
Eva approaching drop position.
Docking release!
Roger!
We’ve caught up with it!
We’ve got less than 4 minutes.
Put me on, now!
Don’t think!  Just do it!
Misato!!
Be careful.
Talk about hot.
This looks bad.
Stop, you bastard!!
Misato!  Hurry!
I’m here.
Error?
What the hell is this?
There’s no doubt!  The program
must have been altered!
The power reactor is just 0.2 points
short of critical!
The control rods won’t function!
Guess I’ll try the long shot.
Misato, get out of there!!
Move, move damn you!!
Misato!
0.1 to critical!!
My God!!  It’s going to explode!!
Christ, it’s all over.
Misato!!
She made it!!
Internal pressure decreasing!!
All readings are nominal!!
We’re saved!!
Hooray, hooray!  She’s done it!
That crazy fool.
Misato, are you all right?!
Misato?!!!
Yeah, I’m okay, not in the
greatest shape however.
You’re alive!  I’m so glad!  You’re all
right!  You’re really all right!
Oh, thank heaven.  I’m so impressed!
It’s a miracle!!
Yeah...
But the miracle was set
up by someone.
Recovery of Unit 01 is complete.
No danger of radioactive
contamination.
Except for Captain Katsuragi’s
operation, everything went
according to the plan.
Good work.
G’morning...
Now, let me at that shower!
Where’s my bra and panties?
Good morning, Mr. Ikari!
Good morning.
I’m taking off!
See ya!
Misato is just so cool.
I thought so too, but she’s sloppy,
embarrassing and lazy
around the house.
She’s not embarrassed
about it, but I am.
How nice for you.
What do you mean?
He really is a kid.
Yeah, he sure is.
How come?
She lets you see the side of her that she
wouldn’t show to anyone else, right?
That means she’s your family.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Eva Unit 02 and its pilot have left
Wilhelmshaven to come to Japan!
With this aggressive girl, Shinji once
again experiences trouble in
communicating...
...and a surprise Angel attack forces
the now activated Unit 02 into an
underwater battle!
Can Misato triumph with the
entry plug in chaos?
It’s the next episode, “Asuka Strikes!”
Watch for it!
Next Episode:
ASUKA STRIKES!