Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
Good morning, Shinji.  How’s it going?
No problems.  I’m getting used to it.
That’s good.  Have you memorized
the positions of all the Eva
emergence points...
...emergency power junctions,
armament equipment buildings
and recovery zones?
I guess so...
Well, let’s review it now.
Normally the Eva runs off electricity
provided by an umbilical cable.
In emergencies, it can switch to a
built-in battery, with an active
life of 1 minute at full power...
...and no more than 5 minutes
in the minimal activity Gain Mode.
This is due to our current technological
limit in battery capacity.
Do you understand?
Yes...
Now let’s continue from where we left
off yesterday.  Initiate Induction Mode.
Position the target in the center...
...then squeeze the trigger switch “on.”
Take it easy.  Position the
target in the center...
Pull the switch...
Next!
You know, I can’t help but wonder
why Shinji agreed to be the pilot
after what happened.
It would seem that he simply does
what he’s told to do.
I suppose that’s just his way of
getting through life.
Target in the center... pull the switch.
Target in the center...
Episode 3:
The Phone That
Never Rings
And now, from Tokyo we go to
Natsuko Shinohara in Matsuzaki.
Good morning, this is Shinohara.
Guess what?
Today I’m in Matsuzaki in West Izu
for a little scuba diving!
Today’s forecast is sunny, with an
estimated high of 32 degrees C.
Miss Misato, it’s morning already.
Today’s forecast is sunny, with an
estimated high of 32 degrees C.
Miss Misato, it’s morning already.
We have hot days all year now, but we
used to have four seasons:
I just got back from night duty...
We have hot days all year now, but we
used to have four seasons:
I just got back from night duty...
Spring, Summer, Fall and Winter.
I don’t have to go to work until...
...this evening, so please, let me sleep.
We never see snow these days, instead,
due to the recent warmth...
I see... I’ll go.
We never see snow these days, instead,
due to the recent warmth...
...aquatic life has been coming
back little by little.
Hey, isn’t today Thursday?
...aquatic life has been coming
back little by little.
Hey, isn’t today Thursday?
As you dive into the sea you can clearly
see an abundance of fish that...
Take the burnable trash to...
As you dive into the sea you can clearly
see an abundance of fish that...
...the garbage, please.
As you dive into the sea you can clearly
see an abundance of fish that...
Yes, ma’am.
As you dive into the sea you can clearly
see an abundance of fish that...
...makes me think of catching some
for tonight’s dinner.
So, how’s school?
...makes me think of catching some
for tonight’s dinner.
Fine.
...makes me think of catching some
for tonight’s dinner.
Oh... Okay.  See ya.
...makes me think of catching some
for tonight’s dinner.
Oh... Okay.  See ya.
Although the town’s melancholy
appearance brings back...
I’ll see you later.
Although the town’s melancholy
appearance brings back...
I’ll see you later.
...sad memories, this is a hot diving spot.
Yes?  Hello?
Oh, it’s you, Ritsuko.
How’s it going?  Are you getting
along with him?
Him?
Oh, Shinji.
Well, it’s been two weeks since he
transferred into the school and he
doesn’t seem to have changed.
Development Conference
3 PM, Conference Room 1
No one ever calls him.
Calls him?
Well, since I figured he’d be needing
one, I gave him a cellular phone.
I don’t think he’s ever used it though,
or received any calls.
I’m not sure, but I don’t think he
has any friends.
Well, I would guess that Shinji’s not the
sort who’s easy to make friends with.
Do you know the fable of the
“Hedgehog’s Dilemma”?
Hedgehog?  You mean those animals
with the spiny hair?
Even though a hedgehog may wish to
become close with another hedgehog...
...the closer they get, the more they
injure each other with their thorns.
It’s the same with some humans.  The
reason he seems so withdrawn is
because he’s afraid of being hurt.
Well, he’s going to have
to learn someday...
...that part of growing up means
finding a way to interact with others
while distancing pain.
What’s up, Class Rep?
Journal
Did you give him the printout I
gave you yesterday?
What?  Well...
Well, there wasn’t anybody home
at Toji’s place.
Mr. Aida, aren’t you
Mr. Suzuhara’s friend?
Aren’t you worried about him?
Do you suppose he’s injured?
What?  In that robot incident?!
The television report said
that nobody was injured!
No way, you saw where the explosion
was on Mt. Takanosu, didn’t you?
There were fighters scrambled from
Iruma and Komatsu...
...and there were also troops from
Misawa and Kyushu.
I’ll bet at least ten or twenty
people were injured...
...and there had to be some killed, too.
Toji!
Suzuhara!
Wow, has the class population
dropped or what?
They’ve all been evacuated or
transferred to other schools.
After all, no one wants to stay after
that last battle inside the city.
Yeah, you’re probably the only one
who’s actually enjoying the chance
to see a real war.
Yeah, I am.
And speaking of which, where have
you been, Toji?  Why were you
absent so long?
Did you get involved in the war?
My little sister did.
She was crushed under a pile of debris.
She survived but she’s been in
the hospital ever since.
Both my dad and grandad
are working at the lab...
...and there’s no way they
can leave their posts.
So, if I’m not with her, she’s all alone.
That robot’s pilot was really dumb!
It makes me so angry!
How could he wreck our own city?
What was he doing?
Oh, speaking of the pilot, have you
heard the rumor about the new
transfer student?
What transfer student?
Him, over there.
He transferred here while
you were absent.
He came right after the incident.
Don’t you think it’s odd?
All rise!
And so, humankind was about
to face its greatest trial.
In the last year of the 20th century...
...a massive meteorite from outer space
slammed into the continent of Antarctica.
The continent’s ice cap was melted
almost instantaneously.
The water level of the oceans increased
dramatically, the Earth was
thrown off its axis...
2000 AD Second Impact
...and new, devastatingly
abnormal weather patterns
were spawned.
The lives of all living things on the
planet were threatened.
Several thousand species and half of
the world’s human population were lost
in the immediate aftermath.
That was the so-called
“Second Impact.”
The survivors still had to live through the
hell of worldwide economic collapse,
ethnic conflicts, and civil wars.
: Is it true that you re the pilot?
’
YN
⁄
However, it has been
15 years since then...
In only 15 years, we have
restored ourselves.
This is certainly proof of the human
race’s resilience, but even more so...
Is it true that you re the pilot?  Y ⁄ N
You a
You ar
You are
You are t
You are th
You are the
You are the o
You are the on
You are the one
You are the one,
r
ri
rig
righ
right
right?
:
Y
⁄
N
...it is the fruit of the blood, sweat and
tears your fathers and mothers have
dedicated to this cause.
Whaaat?
Really?
Cool!
Oh wow!
I lived in Nebukawa at the time, which
is underwater now...
Really, the new student was?
I lived in Nebukawa at the time, which
is underwater now...
We thought so!
I lived in Nebukawa at the time, which
is underwater now...
Hey, you guys!
I lived in Nebukawa at the time, which
is underwater now...
We’re still in class, you know!
Sit down now!!
Aw, you’re always so bossy!
Hey, come on!
Forget her!
Now cut that out!!
Cool, it’s awesome!
Well, umm...
Hey, how were you chosen?
Were there any tests?
Weren’t you scared?
What’s the cockpit look like?
Well, um...  I’m not supposed to
talk about secret stuff...
Oh, come on.
Don’t be mean.
Hey, what’s the name of the robot?
I don’t know much, but everyone
calls it Eva or Unit 01...
Eva?
And what’s its ultimate attack mode?
Uh... some kind of vibrating knife...
...an ultrasonic wave...
That’s amazing!  We’re so proud of you!
Yeah, right!  Cool!  Yeah.
And thus...
Oh...
Ikari, where do you live?
That’s all for today.
In the older part of the city?
Everyone stand up!  Bow.
Hey, you guys, why don’t you at least
show some manners at the end...
Sorry, newcomer, but I’ve got
to beat you up!
I’ve got to work off my anger.
Sorry, his sister was injured
because of the incident.
That’s his excuse, anyway.
I didn’t... pilot it by choice...
We’ve got an emergency call...
I’ll go.
A special state of emergency
has been declared...
...for the Kanto and Chubu regions
surrounding the Tokai district.
All residents must evacuate to their
designated shelters immediately.
Repeating: a state of emergency
has been declared...
The target has been sighted by our
cameras.  It’s already penetrated into
our territorial waters.
Assume battle stations, level one.
Roger, prepare for anti-aircraft
interception.
Tokyo-3 transforming to
battle formation.
Initiate accommodation of
the central block.
Accommodation of central block and
the first through seventh districts
has been completed.
Notification of the government and
other related ministries, completed.
Present effective rate of anti-aircraft
interception: 48%.
What’s the status of
noncombatants and civilians?
We’ve already received reports that
the evacuation has been completed.
334th Underground Shelter
Tokyo-3 Disaster Prevention Department
Total Floor Space: 2000 square meters
Maximum Occupancy: 250
Attention elementary school and junior
high school students: please form
groups with your individual classes.
A state of special emergency has been
announced for all of the Kanto and Chubu
areas surrounding Tokai.
We will bring you new reports as
soon as we receive new information.
Area residents, please group according
to your block numbers.
Not again!
Area residents, please group according
to your block numbers.
Not again!
Seventh district’s missing children center
are located in shelter 323.
Just text messages again?
Seventh district’s missing children center
are located in shelter 323.
It’s news censorship.  They won’t show
any of it to us civilians...
...even though it’s an incredible event.
The Fourth Angel would show up while
Commander Ikari is away.
It’s a lot sooner than we expected.
The last time they gave us
a 15-year break.
This time it’s been only 3 weeks.
They never care about our
situation, do they?
They’re the kind we women
hate the most.
It’s a waste of the taxpayers’ money.
The committee is demanding that we
dispatch an Evangelion again.
Oh, they get on my nerves.
If they hadn’t asked for it, I’d
have mobilized it anyway.
Entry procedure initiated.
LCL oxygenated.
Releasing airlock.
Why am I piloting this thing again,
even though my father’s not here?
Even though I got beat up?
Hey, I need to talk to you,
privately, you know?
What for?
Just give me a second, okay?
Well, okay.
Class Rep!
What?
We both have to go to the bathroom!
You were supposed to use the
bathroom before you came here.
So, what’s this about?
I’ve got to see it, at least once in my life.
You mean the battle up there?
Nobody knows when the enemy will
come the next time...
Kensuke, are you serious?
If we let this opportunity escape us,
we may lose it forever!
Out of Order
Please, help me unlock the gate.
But you could get killed if
you go out there.
If we stay here in the shelter, who’s to
say that the risk isn’t the same?
If I could be killed anyway,
I’d rather see it first.
You idiot.  What do you
think NERV’s for?
And what is NERV’s most
important weapon?
It’s the robot the new kid pilots.
He protected us the other day...
...but you hit him pretty hard.  Twice!
If he refuses to fight, we’re
all going to die.
Doesn’t that make it your obligation
to watch him fight?
Okay, you’re not leaving
me any options!
You’ll do anything to get what
you want, won’t you?
Shinji, are you ready?
Yes.
First, neutralize the enemy’s AT
Field, then fire a volley.
Do it just like we practiced.
Can you handle that?
Yes.
Launch!!
Cool!!  All my efforts really paid off!
This is it!
There it is!
Target in the center... pull the switch...
The AT Field has been deployed.
Do it just like we planned, okay, Shinji?
Target in the center... pull the switch...
Right.
You idiot!  You hid the enemy with
your own smoke!!
I can’t believe it!  He’s already losing!
Not a problem.
I’m sending you a spare rifle.
Take it!
Shinji?  Hey, Shinji?
Jesus...
Being beaten up must have really
messed him up.
S...shut up!
The umbilical cable’s been snapped off!
Eva has switched to its internal
battery power source.
4 minutes, 53 seconds of
activation remaining.
It’s coming this way!
Shinji, are you all right?  Shinji!
Damage report?
No problems detected.  He can make it.
Shinji’s classmates?
What are they doing there?
Why won’t he fight?
Because we’re here?
He can’t move because of us!
Activation time remaining:
3 minutes 28 seconds.
Shinji, let them into the cockpit!
Once you’ve got them, make a
temporary retreat.  We’ll start
again later!
What makes you think that unauthorized
civilians can be allowed into
the entry plug?!
I’m authorizing it.
You’re exceeding your authority,
Captain Katsuragi!
Unit 01’s remaining activation
time: 3 minutes.
Hold Eva on your current commands
and eject the entry plug.  Hurry up!
You two!  Get in!  Now!
What the...?  It’s water?
My camera!  My camera!
Abnormal conditions occurring in
the nervous system.
Of course.  It’s because you’ve allowed
two foreign bodies into the matrix!
They’re being detected as noise in
the nerve impulse systems!
Retreat!  Now!
Utilize recovery route 34, retreat to
the east side of the mountain.
Hey, new kid, she said “Retreat”!
Utilize recovery route 34, retreat to
the east side of the mountain.
Hey, new kid, she said “Retreat”!
New kid!
I mustn’t run away...
I mustn’t run away!
Progressive knife engaged!
Obey my orders, Shinji!
You’ve got to retreat!
Shinji!
That idiot...
Unit 01, activation time
remaining: 30 seconds!
28...  27...
26...  25...
14...  13...
12...  11...
10...  9...
8...  7...
6...  5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Eva Unit 01, activation ceased.
The target is completely silent.
It’s been three days...
You mean, since we were chewed out?
No, since he stopped
coming to school.
Who’s “he”?
The new kid, of course.
I wonder what he’s been
doing since then?
Are you worried about him?
No, not exactly worried...
Toji, for someone who’s so tactless,
you’re pretty stubborn.
If you had apologized to
him back then...
...you wouldn’t have had to agonize
over it for three days.
Here, this is the new kid’s phone number.
If you’re so worried, why don’t
you call him?
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
As the dreary rain pours down, Shinji,
overwhelmed and unable to overcome
his weaknesses...
...tries to run away from Misato.
It’s acceptable, however, considering
that he’s only fourteen.
The organization brings the aimlessly
wandering Shinji back.
There are no kind words waiting to
ease his feelings...
...except from the two boys.
It’s the next episode, “Rain, Escape
and Afterwards.”
And of course, I’ll give you lots of fan
service next time too!
Next Episode:
Rain, Escape
and Afterwards