Are you ready, Shinji?
Yes.
Release the final safety lock!
Evangelion Unit 01, lift off!
Shinji, just concentrate on walking right now.
Walk...
It walked!
Shinji, get it together!
Hurry! Get up!
Shinji, calm down! That's not your arm!
What's going on with the Eva's defense system?
The signal's not working!
The field's not deploying!
Have we failed?
Left arm damaged!
The circuits have disconnected!
Shinji, dodge!
There's a crack on the front of the cranium!
The armor won't last much longer!
The head's been damaged! Extent of damage, unknown!
The control nerves are disconnecting one after another!
We're not getting any readings on the pilot!
Shinji!
I don't know this ceiling.
Episode #02 Unfamiliar Ceiling
So, the Angels have returned, eh?
It's so sudden.
It's the same as it was fifteen years ago.
A disaster comes as it will, without warning.
We could say it was fortunate, in the sense that our prior investments were not a waste.
You can't be sure about that yet.
If it doesn't pay off, it's a waste all the same.
Precisely.
Now that the Angels, and the fact that we have been manipulating information, have become public knowledge, Nerv must operate in a speedy and prudent manner.
It's already been taken care of. You may rest assured of that.
In regards to the declaration of the special state of emergency, government officials have announced...
This incident was...
UN forces in Japan...
So it's public scenario B-22.
In response to reporters' questions...
So, we're hushing up the truth again?
No, there's no threat of contamination from the center of the explosion.
But at least our PR people are thrilled now that they've finally got something to do.
The only Angel samples collected were adhered to the Eva.
We're being pretty casual about it.
Correct, as in the model simulation, approximately 99.9% of it evaporated.
I don't know about that. I think everyone's actually scared.
Of course we are.
Well, we must acknowledge that.
Speaking of which, Ikari, isn't there a better way to utilize Nerv and Eva?
First the repairs to Unit 00, and now to Unit 01, which you wrecked in its first battle.
It's enough to bankrupt an entire country.
We also understand that you gave that toy to your son.
Manpower, time, and money.
How much more do you and your family plan on wasting?
And that is not your only responsibility.
The Human Instrumentality Project, that should be your top priority.
Top Secret Human Instrumentality Project United Nations Top Executive Meeting 17th Midterm Report Human Instrumentality Committee 2015 Business Plan Outline Summary
Precisely.
Under these desperate circumstances, that project is our one and only hope.
In any case, we cannot excuse any delays in that project's schedule, due to the reappearance of the Angels.
We will consider the issue regarding the budget.
Now, the rest of this meeting concerns only the committee.
Your presence here was appreciated, Ikari.
Ikari, there is no turning back.
I know.
Mankind has no time left.
Air conditioning has just got to be mankind's greatest treasure.
It's the triumph of science over nature.
Shinji's woken up.
How is he?
No external injuries. His memory is a bit muddled, however.
You don't think it could be mental contamination?
There appears to be no cause for worry.
Really?
I suppose he did have a pretty hectic day.
It's not surprising. His cranial nerves took a lot of strain.
Don't you mean his heart?
Construction Plan Notice
Okay, okay. Keep it coming. Good!
If Eva and this city both operate at their full potential, maybe we can make it through this.
Are you going to defeat the Angels? You're always such an optimist.
Hey, sometimes you need a little wishful thinking just to keep on living.
I see your point. It helps to hear things like that from you.
See ya!
Are you sure?
They don't want to live together?
I think that living apart is natural for Ikari and his son
And being together is unnatural?
Shinji Ikari
Alone?
Right. His room will be in the 6th Block, just beyond this one.
Is that satisfactory?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Shinji...
It's fine. I'd rather be alone.
Anywhere is fine.
What?!
So, I said, I'll take care of Shinji.
I've already got permission from the brass.
Hey, it's not like I'm going to "put the moves" on a kid.
Of course you're not!
What the hell are you thinking?
You're always like that. Honestly!
She just can't take a joke.
Well, we'll have to have a party tonight, right?
What for?
A welcoming party for my new roommate, of course!
Convenience
So, you're going to move after all?
Yes. I never dreamed that this city would become a battlefield.
Yeah.
My husband's saying that our kid and I should evacuate, at the very least.
Evacuate, huh?
This city may be a fortress, but that's no guarantee of safety.
Just remembering yesterday gives me the chills.
I hope you don't mind if we make a little stop on the way.
Where?
Someplace really cool.
It's such a lonely city.
It's time.
Amazing! The buildings are growing!
This city is a fortress, designed to protect against the Angels.
This is New Tokyo-3.
This is our city.
And it's the city that you helped to protect.
THE BEAST
Your things should have already been delivered, Shinji.
The truth is, I just recently moved to this city, too.
Come on in.
Pardon the intrusion.
Shinji, this is YOUR home now.
I'm home.
Welcome home.
As you can see, the place is a little bit messy, but make yourself comfortable.
You call this a "little bit" messy?
Oh! Sorry! Could you put the food in the fridge?
Sure.
Ice, snacks, and nothing but beer.
What kind of a life does she lead?
Excuse me. What's in the other fridge?
Oh, don't mind that. He's probably still sleeping!
Sleeping?
Let's eat!
Let's eat.
Life just doesn't get any better than this!
Don't you want to eat? It's pretty good, even if it is all instant.
I'm sorry, I'm just not used to it.
That's no excuse! You can't be so finicky.
No, that's not what I... well...
Isn't this nice?
Having dinner with somebody else!
Uh, yes.
Here we go for the next one.
Paper, stone and scissors...
Pon! Pon! Pon! Pon!
Sorry, Shinji.
Okay! That should be it for fairly splitting up the chores!
Our Chores Chart Day/Chore M T W Th F S Su Breakfast S S M S S S S Dinner S S S M S S M
Yes.
Starting today, this is your home, so you can take advantage of everything here.
Man. All you keep saying is yes, yes, yes. It's so depressing!
You're a boy, aren't you? Act like a man! Okay?
Yes.
Oh, well.
Why don't you go take a bath and scrub away all those bad memories?
Bathing is the laundry of life.
Miss Misato!
What?
A p... p... p...
Oh, him? He's one of those new hot spring penguins.
What...
His name is Pen Pen. He's your other roommate.
Toothpicks
Why don't you cover that up?
I wonder if I've been a little TOO cheery?
Maybe I'm the one who's transparent.
Miss Misato Katsuragi.
She's not a bad person.
Bathing is the laundry of life.
But bad memories always seem to find me when I'm in the bath.
My father
and Rei Ayanami...
So, how was Rei today?
You went to the hospital this afternoon, didn't you?
She'll be ready to work again in twenty days.
By then, we'll be ready to re-activate Unit 00 from cryo-stasis.
It must be so hard on those children.
There is no one else who can pilot the Evas.
As long as they survive, that is what I'll have them do.
With no regard to what they may want?
Little Shin's Room No.
1 Public Middle School Transfer Application Shinji Ikari
Yeah, after all the horrible stuff he went through, there's no telling if he'll pilot it again.
Maintaining him is part of your job.
I'm just scared. I don't know how to deal with him.
Grumbling already? You were the one who had the bright idea of taking him in.
Shut up!
That time, I was thinking of Shinji as a tool.
I'm as bad as Ritsuko.
We destroyed that Angel.
But I guess I can't be happy about it.
Another ceiling I don't know.
Of course. In this whole city, there's no place that's familiar.
This is your home.
Why am I here?
The head has been damaged! Extent of damage, unknown!
We're having problems maintaining activation!
Status report!
The synchrograph is reversing! The pulses are flowing backward!
Break the circuit! Block it!
We can't!
It's rejecting the signal! It won't take it!
What about Shinji?
His monitors aren't responding. Life signs unknown!
Unit 01's gone completely silent!
Misato!
This is it.
Abort the operation! Rescuing the pilot is our first priority!
Force eject the entry plug!
We can't! It's completely out of control!
What the hell?!
The Eva's re-activating!
Impossible! There's no way it can move!
It can't be...
It's gone berserk?
It looks like we've won.
An AT field!
No! As long as the Angel has that AT field up...
He can't touch the Angel!
Left arm, regenerated!
Incredible!
Unit 01 has deployd its AT field!
It's neutralizing the phase space!
No, it's eroding it!
It went through that AT field so easily...
It's going to self-destruct?!
Is the Eva...
That must be the Eva's...
...true form.
Circuits reconnected.
Systems restored. Graphs back to normal.
Pilot life signs, confirmed.
Send out the recovery team. Hurry!
Preserving the pilot's life is our first priority.
Shinji, I'm coming in.
I forgot to tell you something.
You did a very praiseworthy thing today.
You should be proud of yourself.
Good night, Shinji.
Hang in there.
To Be Continued
Preview
As Shinji lives his new life, drifting along without direction, there was no way for him to make friends.
But the fact that he is an Eva pilot makes him popular in his class.
Next Evangelion: "The Silent Phone" I'll give you fan service next time too!
Next Time The Silent Phone