Good morning, Shinji. How are you?
I'm getting used to it.
I think it's not bad.
That's good.
Have you memorized the positions of all the Eva emergence points, emergency power junctions, armament buildings, and recovery zones?
I think so.
Then, I'll review it one more time.
Normally the Eva runs off electricity provided by an umbilical cable.
In emergencies, it can switch to an internal battery, with an active life of one minute at full power, and no more than five minutes in the minimal activity gain mode.
This is the limitations of our current technology.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Now let's continue from where we left off yesterday. We'll initiate Induction Mode.
Position the target in the center, then switch "on".
Calm down. Position the target in the center.
Switch...
Next!
But I'm surprised that Shinji agreed to be a pilot it.
He simply does what he's told to do.
Maybe that's his way of getting through life.
Target in the center, pull the switch.
Target in the center....
Episode #03 The Silent Phone
And now, from Tokyo, we go to Miss Natsuko Shinohara in Matsuzaki.
Good morning, this is Shinohara. Guess what?
Today I'm in Matsuzaki in West Izu for a little scuba diving!
Today's forecast is sunny, with an estimated high of 32 degrees C.
Miss Misato, it's morning already.
I just got back from night duty.
,Spring, Summer, Fall and Winter.
I don't have to go to work until this evening, so please, let me sleep.
,We never see snow these days, instead, due to the recent warmth, aquatic life has been coming back little by little.
I see. I'll go.
Hey, is today Thursday?
As you dive into the sea you can clearly see an abundance of fish.
Take the burnable trash to the garbage, please.
Yes, Ma'am.
It makes me think of catching some for tonight's dinner.
So, are you adjusting to school?
Yeah.
Oh, okay. See you later.
Although the town brings back sad memories, this is a hot diving spot.
I'll see you later.
Yes? Hello?
Oh, it's you, Ritsuko.
How's it going? Are you getting along with your boyfriend?
Boyfriend?
Oh, you mean Shinji.
Well, he transferred into school two weeks ago and he hasn't changed.
No one ever calls him.
Calls him?
Well, since I figured he'd need one, I gave him a cell phone a while back.
I don't think he's ever used it though, or received any calls.
I'm not sure, but I don't think he has any friends.
Well, I would guess that Shinji's not the sort who makes friends easily.
Do you know the fable of the "Hedgehog's Dilemma"?
Hedgehog? You mean those animals with the spiny hair?
Even though a hedgehog may wish to get close to another hedgehog, the closer they get, the more they injure each other with their spines.
It's the same with some humans.
Shinji is probably afraid of pain and has become a coward somewhere in his heart.
Well, he'll eventually learn that growing up means getting closer to people and distancing them, finding a distance where you can avoid hurting each other too much.
What's up, class rep?
Class Daybook
Did you give him the printout I gave you yesterday?
What? Well...
Well, there wasn't anybody home at Toji's place.
Aida, you're good friends with Suzuhara, right?
He's been absent for two weeks. Aren't you worried?
Do you suppose he's been seriously injured?
What? In that robot incident?!
The television report said that nobody was injured!
No way, you saw the explosion site on Mount Takanosu, didn't you?
Not only were Iruma and Komatsu dispatched, they brought in troops from Misawa and Kyushu.
There had to have been well over a couple dozen people injured, and even some killed.
Toj!
Suzuhara!
Wow, has the class population dropped or what?
They've all evacuated and transferred to other schools.
After all, no one wants to stay after that fierce battle inside the city.
Yeah, you're probably the only one who's actually enjoyin' the chance to see a real war.
I suppose so.
So where have you been, Toji? You were gone for so long.
Did you get caught in the crossfire or something?
My kid sister did.
She was crushed under a pile of debris.
She survived, but she's been in the hospital ever since.
Both my pop and gramps work at the lab, and there's no way they can leave their posts right now.
So, if I ain't with her, she's all alone at the hospital.
Man, that robot's pilot was plain awful! I'm downright pissed off!
What the hell's the point of our own guy wreckin' the city?
Oh, about the pilot, have you heard the rumor about the new transfer student?
Transfer student?
Him, over there.
He transferred here while you were absent.
He came right after the incident. Don't you think that's odd?
All rise!
And so, humankind was about to face its greatest trial.
In the last year of the 20th century, the massive meteor from space slammed into the continent of Antarctica.
The continent's ice cap was melted almost instantaneously.
The water level of the oceans rose, the Earth was thrown of its axis, and abnormal weather patterns threatened the lives of all living things.
Several thousand species and half of the world's population were lost for eternity.
That was the so-called "Second Impact".
The survivors still had to live through the hell of worldwide economic collapse, ethnic conflicts, and civil wars.
Is it true that you're the pilot of that robot? Y/N.
However it has been fifteen years since then.
In only fifteen years, we have restored ourselves.
This is certainly proof of the human race's resilience, but even more so, it is the fruit of the blood, sweat and tears your fathers and mothers have dedicated to this cause.
It's true, isn't it? Y/N.
What?!
Really, Oh, wow!
Cool!
I lived in Nebukawa at the time, which is underwater now...
Really, the new student was?
Hey, you guys!
We're still in class, you know!
Sit down now!
Aw, you're always so bossy!
It's okay, it's okay!
It's not okay!
Well...
Hey, how were you chosen?
Were there any tests?
Weren't you scared?
What's the cockpit look like?
Well, that's all secret.
Hey, what's the name of the robot?
I don't know much, but everyone calls it Eva or Unit 01.
Eva?
And what's its ultimate attack?
Some kind of knife.
It vibrates... An ultra-sonic wave...
That's amazing! You're the pride of the school!
Yeah, right! Cool!
And thus...
Oh...
That's all for today.
Ikari, where do you live? All rise! Bow!
Hey, you guys, why don't you at least show some manners at the end?
Sorry, transfer student, but I've gotta beat you up!
I won't feel right until I've smacked you.
Sorry, his little sister was injured in the incident the other day.
Well, there you have it.
I'm not piloting it by choice either.
An emergency call.
I'll go on ahead.
A special state of emergency has been declared for the Kanto and Chubu regions surrounding the Tokai district.
All residents must evacuate to their designated shelters immediately.
Repeating...
A TRANSFER
The target has been sighted by our cameras.
It's already penetrated into our territorial waters.
All personnel, assume battle stations, Level One.
Roger, Prepare for anti-aircraft interception.
New Tokyo-3 transforming to battle formation.
Initiate accommodation of the central block.
Accommodation of central block and the first through seventh districts has been completed.
Notification of the government and other related ministries, completed.
Target is still advancing.
Present operational rate of anti-aircraft interception: 48%.
What's the status of noncombatants and civilians?
We've already received reports that the evacuation has been completed.
Underground Shelter 334 Disaster Prevention Department, Tokyo-3 Total Floor Space Maximum Capacity
Attention, elementary school and junior high school students.
Please form groups with your individual classes.
At noon today, a special emergency declaration was issued for the Kanto and Central regions centering on the Tokai area. Details will be reported as they come in.
Not again!
Just text messages again?
It's news censorship. They won't show any of it to us civilians.
Even though it's an incredible event.
The fourth Angel would show up while Commander Ikari is away.
It's a lot sooner than we expected.
The last time they gave us a fifteen year break.
This time it's been only 3 weeks.
They never care about our convenience, do they?
They're the type we women hate the most.
Hakone Ropeway
It's a waste of the taxpayers' money.
The committee is demanding that we dispatch an Evangelion again.
Those pesky bastards.
Even if they hadn't asked for it, I'd have dispatched it anyway.
Entry procedure initated.
LCL oxygenated.
Releasing airlock.
Why am I piloting this thing again, even though my father's not here?
Even though I got beat up?
Hey, I need to talk to you, privately, you know?
What for?
Just give me a second, okay?.
Well, okay.
Class rep!
What?
We've both hafta go to the john!
You were supposed to use the bathroom before you came here.
So, what's this about?
I've got to see it, at least once in my life.
You mean the battle up there?
Nobody knows when the enemy will come the next time.
Kensuke, are you serious?
Do not use
If we let this opportunity escape us, we may lose it forever!
Please, help me unlock the gate.
But you'll get killed if you go out there.
You don't know if that'll happen, even if we stay here.
If I could be killed anyway, I'd rather see it first.
Idiot. What do you think Nerv's for?
And what is Nerv's most important weapon?
It's the robot the new kid pilots.
He protected us the other day, but you hit him pretty hard.
Twice!
If he refuses to pilot the robot, we're all going to die.
Don't you have a duty to watch him fight?
Ah, whatever.
You sure are upfront about what you want, ain't you?
Shinji, are you ready to head out?
Yes.
Listen to me. Neutralize the enemy's AT field, then fire a volley from the pallet gun.
Do it just like we practiced. Can you handle that?
Yes.
Launch!
Cool! All my efforts really paid off!
Oh! This is what I've been waiting for!
There it is!
Target in the center, pull the switch.
Target in the center, pull the switch. Do it just as planned, okay, Shinji?
The AT field has been deployed.
Right.
You idiot! You hid the enemy with your own smoke!
What the hell?! He's already losing!
It's all right.
I'm sending you a spare rifle.
Take it!
Shinji? Shinji?
Oh, man!
Being beaten up must have really messed him up.
Shut up!
The umbilical cable's been severed!
Eva has switched to its internal battery power source.
4 minutes, 53 seconds of activation remaining.
It's comin' this way!
Shinji, are you all right? Shinji!
Damage report?
No problems detected. He can make it.
Shinji's classmates?
What are they doing there?
Why won't he fight?
Because we're here?
He can't move because of us!
Unit 01 activaton time remaining, 3 minutes 28 seconds.
Shinji, let them into the cockpit!
Once you've got them, make a temporary retreat.
We'll regroup!
You think you can allow unauthorized civilians into the entry plug?!
I'm authorizing it.
You're exceeding your authority, Captain Katsuragi!
Unit 01's remaining activation time, 3 minutes.
Hold Eva on your current commands and eject the entry plug. Hurry up!
You two! Get in! Hurry!
What the... It's water?
My camera! My camera!
Abnormal conditions occurring in the nervous system!
Of course. It's because you've allowed two foreign bodies into the plug.
They're introducing noise in the nerve impulse systems!
Now! Retreat!
Recovery route 34, retreat to the east side of the mountain.
Hey, new kid, she said, "Retreat!
New Kid! I mustn't run away.
I mustn't run away!
Progressive Knife engaged!
Obey my orders, Shinji! You've got to retreat!
Shinji!
That idiot...
Unit 01, activation time remaining, 30 seconds!
28... 27...
26... 25...
14... 13...
12... 11...
10... 9...
8... 7...
6... 5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Eva Unit 01, activation ceased.
The target is completely silent.
It's been three days.
You mean, since we were chewed out?
No, since he stopped comin' to school.
Who's "he"?
The new kid, the new kid.
I wonder what he's been doin' since then?
Are you worried about him?
No, not exactly worried.
Toji, for someone who's so tactless, you're pretty stubborn.
If you had apologized to him back then, you wouldn't have had to agonize over it for three days.
Here, this is the new kid's phone number.
If you're so worried, why don't you call him?
To Be Continued.
Preview
Unable to overcome his feelings, Shinji even runs away from Misato.
But the organization brings him back without hesitation.
There were no kind words waiting for him.
Next Evangelion: "Rain, After Running Away" And of course, I'll give you lots of fan service next time too!
Next Time Rain, After Running Away