Once again, I owe you.
You're not going to pay me back anyway, are you?
About the materials they wanted under Freedom of Information, I handled it by giving them some falsified data.
First Interim Report Concerning Objects Referred to as Angels and the Human Instrumentality Project
The government is quietly pursuing legal action, but that will be blocked any day now.
So, should I do something about that project as well?
No, judging by the material you sent me, there should be no problem.
Then, I'll continue as planned.
Episode #07 That Which Is Manmade
Good morning.
G'morning.
This is the way to start your morning!
Not with coffee?
A traditional Japanese breakfast begins with rice, miso, and sake.
You mean YOUR traditional breakfast.
What's that supposed to mean?
Besides, who was supposed to cook this morning anyway?
Now I know why you're still single at your age, Miss Misato.
Well, excuse me for being coarse.
And sloppy too.
Leave me alone!
I'm done.
Are you really going to come to school today?
MISATO Of course.
It's your parent-teacher meeting after all.
But you're so busy with your work.
Don't worry about it. This is part of my job too.
It's part of your job?
Yes?
Oh, thanks for coming all this way! Yes, wait just a minute.
Miss Misato, please don't go out like that.
It's embarrassing.
Okay, okay.
Good morning, Ikari!
We're taking off now, Miss Misato!
See you!
Let's get going!
Ah, sarcasm.
Well, I guess it's good that he's loosening up and expressing himself more.
Yes?
He just left. I'll leave guarding him from here to you.
She's arrived!
Cool! Who is she?
Ikari's guardian?
What?! He's got a babe like that for a guardian?!
They're such dorks.
Miss Misato really is awesome!
You think so?
It's even more amazin' that she's Nerv's Ops Director.
It's just a counseling session but my mother had to dress up!
Good thing that Shinji's such a baby, Kensuke.
Yeah, Shinji's no rival for us!
Don't you think she's silly?
You guys don't know what a slob she is.
Man, I wish I had a girlfriend like her!
I bet you'd have a tough time.
You just don't get it, do you, Mr. Big shot?
All right, we'll leave protecting the Earth to you, so you leave Miss Misato to us!
Unit 01 has achieved the required cooling level.
Please shift operations to stage 2.
Protecting the Earth...
That's what Eva is for.
Come to think of it, just what is the Eva?
The entry plug smells like blood.
But I feel so relaxed here. Why?
In the end, I don't know anything.
What's the status of Unit 00's bio-chest components?
It was seriously damaged.
We'll make a new one, but it'll barely fit within our supplementary budget.
Will our job get any simpler once we get Unit 02 from Germany?
It could go the other way.
Disposing of the Angel on the surface isn't cheap, right?
Yeah, this place is really tight when it comes to money.
We're talking about the fate of mankind here!
It can't be helped. "Man cannot live by Eva alone.
All those survivors need money to live too.
Budgets...
So, is the Commander off to another conference?
Yes, he's on the plane now.
It's nice and quiet here when he's not around.
Excuse me. since we're sharing the flight, do you mind if I sit here?
The revised budget for the sample collection passed quite easily, didn't it?
The Committee's main concern is for their own survival.
They aren't stingy when their own lives are at stake.
After all, the basis of their argument was that no more Angels would appear.
Oh, I have one more piece of good news.
All members of the UN except the U.s. have approved the budget for Eva Unit 06.
Well, it's probably just a matter of time for the U.s. as well.
That country is allergic to unemployment, after all.
And what about your country?
We will participate beginning with the construction of Unit 08.
The plans for the second installation project are still viable.
However, there is the problem of not yet having found a pilot.
The Angels have appeared once again.
We have no choice but to defeat them.
We don't want another Second Impact either.
Then you're saying that the Second Impact that evaporated Antarctica wasn't...
Yes, the history texts say it was a disaster caused by a huge meteorite, but sometimes the truth has been covered up.
Giant Explosion at the South Pole
Fifteen years ago at the south Pole, mankind discovered the humanoid being known as the first "Angel".
However, in the middle of the investigation, for reasons unknown, there was a huge explosion.
That is the real truth behind the Second Impact.
Then, what we're doing here...
To prevent a probable Third Impact from happening.
That is the purpose of Nerv and the Evangelions.
By the way, the event will occur tomorrow as scheduled.
I understand.
Good morning.
I'm going to Old Tokyo on business.
I'll probably be back late tonight, so have delivery for dinner.
Later.
Okay.
A HUMAN WORK
Abandoned Zone 28 (Center of Old Tokyo)
It's hard to believe this used to be the flourishing capital of Tokyo.
We're here.
Of all places, they didn't have to hold it here.
So, is the SSDF involved in this project?
The Strategic Self Defense Force? No, they're not allowed to interfere.
No wonder they're doing as they please.
Celebrating JA Completion Announcement Commemoration
Thank you very much for taking the time out of your busy schedules today
Nerv Party
to attend the demonstration of the new product that we at Japan Heavy Chemical Industries are so proud of.
Later, you will be observing the offical demonstration from the control room, but we'll be taking your questions here.
Yes!
The famous Dr. Ritsuko Akagi.
It is our honor to have you here.
May I ask a question?
Of course, certainly!
According to our earlier briefing, this unit is equipped with an internal nuclear reactor, correct?
Yes, this is one of our product's most distinguished features.
150 days of consecutive operating power is assured.
Nerv Party
But from a safety perspective, isn't incorporating a nuclear reactor into a weapon designed for hand-to-hand combat risky?
It's better than a weapon that won't work for over five minutes.
But in an emergency there could be problems with remote control.
Still it's more humane than a system that induces great mental stress, and causes mental instability.
Cut it out. This just makes you look childish.
And there's still the issue of manual control.
I believe that it is safer than a most dangerous weapon that can go out of control and run wild.
A weapon that cannot be controlled is utter nonsense!
It's like a woman in hysterics!
Unmanageable!
That is what our pilots and technology are for.
You're not saying that science and the human heart will tame that beast?
Are you serious?
Yes, of course I'm serious!
Because Nerv depends on something as unreliable as the human heart, you've allowed a loss of control such as we just saw.
That's why the UN had to approve that colossal supplementary budget.
As a result, over 20,000 people in several countries are starving.
On top of which, regardless of it having been such a critical incident, the causes of it are still unknown?
I wish you would at least fulfill that much of your responsibilities!
Nerv Party
I envy you. Nerv is protected by a super-legal act that allows you to avoid responsibility.
It doesn't matter what you say.
The fact is that only Nerv's weapons have the ability to defeat the enemy.
You mean the AT field?
That's just a matter of time as well.
Nerv's day in the sun will not last forever.
Nerv Party
Damn it! Idiots! Who do those fat cats think they are?!
This is just payback for getting cut out of the profit loop!
I am so pissed!
Damn it! Damn it!
Stop that. This just makes you look childish.
He's just a show-off, begging for praise.
He's a small man.
But how did he even know about the AT field?!
There's been a huge leak of classified material.
What the hell is Intelligence doing?
We will now begin the JA activation test.
There is absolutely no danger.
Make yourselves comfortable, and watch through that window.
Ready to activate.
Start the test.
Open all power circuits.
Pressure levels nominal.
Coolant system circulation nominal.
Release the control rods.
The reactor has exceeded threshold levels.
Output is nominal.
Begin walk cycle!
Walking. Forward ahead, slow. Forward right leg.
Roger.
Walk, forward ahead slow.
Forward Stop Reverse Slow Half Speed Normal Flank speed
Balance is nominal.
Power core status nominal.
Roger.
Now, forward left leg.
Keep her steady.
It actually walks! I guess they did have something to be proud of.
What's wrong?
This is odd. The pressure inside the reactor is increasing.
The temperature of the primary coolant system is also rising!
Open the release valve.
Insert the neutron-deceleration fluid.
No effect!
The pump output isn't increasing!
Not good! Shut off the power. Emergency stop!
Abort signal transmission confirmed.
It's not accepting it!
The radio circuit is being blocked!
It's out of control!
It can't be!
Run away!
That robot is as badly behaved as the guy who built it.
The compression valve is operating irregularly!
The control rods aren't working!
At this rate, a meltdown is possible!
I don't believe it.
JA's been programmed to handle all possible contingencies.
This kind of thing can't happen!
Yet, the fact is, the danger of a meltdown is now before us!
Under the circumstances, our only option is to wait for it to stop.
And what is the estimated probability of an automatic stop?
0.00002%! It would be a miracle!
Determined efforts are better than waiting for a miracle!
Tell me how to stop that thing!
We've tried every possible option.
No, there's got to be a last resort, a way to wipe everything out.
Give me the password.
The password to delete all programming is top secret.
I can't authorize it.
I'm not allowed to tell you!
Then get the clearance!
Right now!
It's me. Let me speak to Mr. Manda in Tokyo-2.
That's right, the Director of Internal Affairs.
Well, I've delegated this to Yasugi. Ask him.
I can't give authorization for such an important matter on the phone.
Could you submit a formal written request?
So, I just need to get Mr. Yoshizawa's permission?
Yes, I've already got an approval from Mr. Witz.
Yes... yes, okay.
The evasion of responsibility...
A written order of clearance will be sent.
That will make this an official operation.
We can't wait for that! Once that thing explodes, it'll be all too late!
Jet Alone is heading for Atsugi.
Time is running out.
From here on, I'll be acting independently.
Excuse me.
Nerv Party
Hey, Hyuga?
I've arranged it with Atsugi, so bring Shinji and Unit 01 equipped with the F module.
Yes, this is an emergency.
This is pointless. Call this off, Captain Katsuragi.
Besides, how do you plan to stop it?
By inputting a direct command manually.
Are you serious?
Yes.
But the interior must be flooded with radioactivity!
It's too risky!
But if I make it, everyone will be saved.
The hatch can be opened manually as soon as our control signal is cut off.
You'll be able to enter through the backpack.
"Hope".
That's the password to delete the programming.
Thank you.
JA is the target.
There's a danger of meltdown within five minutes.
Therefore, we cannot allow it to get any closer to a populated area.
Hyuga?
Yes, Ma'am?
As soon as you drop off the Eva, break away immediately and ascend to a safe altitude.
Roger.
And shinji...
Yes.
Run alongside the target, and place me on its back.
Then restrain the target as best you can.
You're going inside?
That's right.
That's crazy!
I know it's crazy, but there just isn't any other way.
But it's too dangerous!
Don't worry.
If it comes down to it, the Eva can withstand a direct explosion.
Not that! I meant for you, Miss Misato!
Well, I've got to give it my best shot, or else I'll regret it for the rest of my life.
Target sighted.
Here we go.
Eva in drop position.
Docking release!
Roger!
We've caught up!
We've got less than four minutes. Put me on, now!
That's fine! Just do it!
Miss Misato!
Be careful.
Talk about hot.
This looks bad.
Stop, you bastard!
Miss Misato! Hurry!
This must be it.
Hope
Error?
What in the hell is this?
There's no doubt! The program must have been altered!
The power reactor is just 0.2 short of critical!
The control rods won't function!
Guess it's time to sink or swim.
Miss Misato, get out of there!
Move, damn you!
Miss Misato!
0.1 to critical!
It's no use! It's going to explode!
It's all over.
Miss Misato!
She made it!
lnternal pressure decreasing!
All readings are nominal!
We're saved!
We did it! We did it! We did it!
That idiot.
Miss Misato, are you all right?!
Miss Misato?!
Yeah, but I feel like crap.
I'm so glad you're alive! Thank goodness!
Really, thank goodness!
But that was really amazing! I'm so impressed! It really was a miracle!
MISATO Yeah...
But the miracle was set up by someone.
Recovery of Unit 01 is complete.
No danger of radioactive contamination.
Except for Captain Katsuragi's actions, everything went according to plan.
Good work.
G'morning.
Now for a morning shower!
Where are my bra and panties?
Good morning, Ikari!
Good morning.
I'm taking off!
See ya!
Miss Misato is just so cool!
I thought so too, but at home she's shameless. she's so coarse, uncool, and really sloppy.
It makes me embarrassed for her.
How nice for you.
What do you mean?
He really is a kid.
Yeah, he sure is.
How's that?
She lets you see a side of her that she won't show to anyone else.
That means she's your family.
To Be Continued
Preview
Eva Unit 02 and its pilot have left Wilhelmshaven, Germany to come to Japan!
The sudden attack of an Angel forces a first submarine battle onto the activated Unit 02!
It's the next episode: "Asuka Arrives in Japan"
Next Time Asuka Arrives in Japan