Lucky!
I'm so lucky that I can go shopping with you today, Mr. Kaji!
What?! Isn't this the swimsuit section?
Please allow us to announce a call for a customer.
Mr. Yamazaki from Ibaragi City, your friend is waiting for you.
You're just so behind the times, Mr. Kaji.
Please come to Customer service on the first floor.
Aren't you a little young for that?
Slow down, school girl.
This is pretty normal nowadays.
How do you like this?
Hey!
Really? I had no idea.
But this is the big school trip. You've got to go all out!
Travel Pamphlet Public Middle school 1
And where are you going for the trip?
Activity Destinations Day 1 - Depart from New Tokyo-3 International Airport to Okinawa (New Kadena, Main Island) Day 2 - Main Island to Kerama Islands to Miyako Island Day 3 - Miyako Island to Arrive at New Tokyo-3 International Airport
Okinawa!
We're even scheduled to go scuba diving!
schedule Day 2 Wake up Breakfast (buffet) Scuba Diving (first time) Lunch (boxed) Scuba Diving (second time)
Scuba diving...
Come to think of it, it's been three years since I've gone diving.
Say, where did you go for your school trip?
Oh, we didn't have one.
Why not?
Because of the Second Impact.
Episode #10 Magma Diver
I can't go on the trip?!
Right.
Why not?!
Because you're on standby for combat duty.
You never told me anything about that!
I just told you.
Who in the hell decided that?!
Me, the Operations Planning Manager.
Hey, why don't you stop slurping that tea and say something!
You're a man, aren't you?
Actually, I kind of anticipated it would be like this.
And you've already given up?
How pathetic. Nothing's more useless than a housebroken male.
Please don't talk about me like that.
I know how you must feel, but there's just no helping this.
There's always the possibility of an Angel attack while you're gone.
Sohryu
It's always standby! Standby, standby, standby!
We've always got to be ready to defend against an enemy who may not even come!
Why don't you try to find out where they are, and attack them for once?!
If we could do that, we'd have already done it.
Look, think of this as a good opportunity.
While the rest of your class is on the trip, the two of you can study a little.
Or do you think I don't know about these?
You're greatly mistaken if you thought I wouldn't find out about these.
What you get on your tests at school is piped directly to me.
It's ridiculous. Who cares about grades?
I've got absolutely no interest in the old-fashioned grading system.
When in Rome, do as the Romans do.
Try to adjust to Japanese school life.
No way!
Asuka, I'll bring you some souvenirs!
Well, it's just too bad for you guys!
I'll have enough fun for both of ya!
Paste the observation data on Mt.
Asama from Balthasar to Melchior as soon as possible.
A school trip?
That's pretty carefree for times like these.
Well, it's because the times are so hard that they want to have a little fun while they can.
What are you up to?
Studying science.
You're such a diligent student.
You can say that, but I have to do it anyway.
Ta da!
Since I can't go scuba diving in Okinawa, I'm going to do it here!
Really?
Let's see. What're you working on?
Let me take a look.
You can't solve an easy equation like this?
There, done.
It's so easy.
How can you solve a difficult problem like this, and not make good grades on your tests?
Because I couldn't figure out what the questions said.
You mean you couldn't read the questions in Japanese?
Right, I haven't learned all the Chinese characters yet.
We didn't study it in college over there.
College?
Oh, I graduated last year.
So, what does this one say?
It's about thermal expansion.
Thermal expansion? That's kid stuff!
To put it simply, things expand when they get hot, and shrink when they get cold.
Well, yeah, but...
If I were to warm up just my breasts, do you think they'd grow a little bigger?
I wouldn't know anything about that!
What a boring guy.
Watch this, Shinji!
Back roll entry!
This just isn't clear enough.
But just as the report from Mt.
Asama Earthquake Research Laboratory says, this shadow is definitely suspicious.
Of course, we can't ignore this.
What is the Magi's judgment?
Fifty-fifty.
Is someone there yet?
Captain Katsuragi's already on site.
You're too deep!
Not yet. Another 500, please.
WOMAN (OFF) Depth 1200.
The pressure resistant partition is cracking.
Ms. Katsuragi!
If it breaks, we'll pay for the damage. 200 more.
We're monitoring a reaction!
Begin analysis!
Yes, Ma'am!
The probe has imploded due to the extreme pressure.
What about the analysis?
Just barely made it. The pattern is blue.
There's no doubt, it's an Angel.
As of now, this laboratory will be completely sealed off!
It's under Nerv's jurisdiction now!
Any and all access to the outside world is prohibited, and all records of the events of the past six hours are classified.
Seismic Wave Analysis Room 2 Seismic Wave Analysis Room 1
Request an A-1 7 from Commander Ikari, top priority!
Watch what you're saying. This is an open line.
I know. Hurry up and switch to a scrambled line.
A-17?!
We're going to launch an offensive?
Correct.
Unacceptable, it's too dangerous.
You had better not say you've forgotten what happened fifteen years ago.
This is a chance to move from a consistently defensive posture to an offensive one for the first time.
The risk is too large.
However, I'm sure you're aware how important a live Angel sample would be.
We will not tolerate failure.
Failure?
If we fail, it will result in the extinction of the human race.
You're really sure about this?
This is an Angel?
Yes, it's something like a chrysalis prior to reaching the adult stage.
This operation's prime objective is to capture this Angel.
We must capture it alive, as close to its original state as possible.
And if we can't?
Then you must destroy it immediately. Do you understand?
Yes, Ma'am!
The designated pilot for the actual operation is...
Hey, let me! I'll dive!
But I'll bet it's going to be me again.
Asuka.
Carry out the mission using Unit 02.
Sure! This'll be a piece of cake.
And me?
The prototype Unit 00 isn't compatible with the special equipment we'll be using.
Rei and Unit 00 will remain at headquarters on standby.
Yes, Ma'am.
Oh, too bad for you.
You don't get to go to the hot springs.
Since an A-17 has been ordered, we'll scramble immediately.
Get ready.
Yes, Ma'am!
You say this is the heat resistant plug suit, but it's not any different.
Try pressing the switch on the right.
Oh, no!
What is this?!
Unit 02 is also ready.
No! What is that?!
The suit is designed to protect you from heat, pressure, and radiation.
This is Type-D equipment, for combat under extreme environmental duress.
Is that my Unit 02?
No way! Count me out!
I don't want to appear in public in this!
This sort of thing is up Shinji's alley!
That's too bad.
I was anticipating seeing Asuka's gallant figure!
No!
But I don't have the courage to go in front of Mr. Kaji looking so uncool!
This is a problem.
Yes...
Excuse me, but I...
I'll go in Unit 02.
Sorry, but I don't want you touching my Unit 02!
I'd rather do it than let the First take my place.
I know it's uncool, but put up with it, okay?
MAGMADIVER
Eva Units 01 and 02 have arrived.
Have both units stand by in position.
Move in the laser bore, and ready the crane.
Roger.
Boom arm fixed in place.
Coolant circulation system going on auto.
Hey, where's Mr. Kaji?
That jerk won't be here. There's nothing for him to do.
Damn! I wanted him to see how great I am.
So, an A-17 has been ordered.
That includes the freeze of all current assets.
I'm sure there are many people who will be put out by that.
Why didn't you stop them?
I didn't have any excuse. The order was official.
But if Nerv fails, it'll mean the end of the world.
They're not that arrogant.
What are those?
The UN's Air Force is on standby alert.
Until this mission has been completed.
Are they going to help us?
No, they're here to clean up.
In case we fail.
What do you mean?
They will use N2 depth charges to destroy the Angel, and us with it.
That's awful!
Who would order something like that?
Commander Ikari.
Laser operation, complete.
The bore path has been secured.
The Type D equipment is functioning normally.
Unit 02 is in position to dispatch.
Roger.
Asuka, are you ready?
Anytime you are.
Launch!
Looks hot!
Unit 02 is entering the lava.
Watch this, Shinji!
Giant stroke entry!
Current depth, 170. speed of descent, 20.
No problems detected.
Visibility is zero. I can't see a thing.
Switching to CT monitor.
Even with this, visibility is no more than 120.
Depth, 400...
450...
500...
550...
600...
650...
900...
950...
1000...
1020...
We're over the maximum safe depth.
Depth is 1300. Estimated target level.
Asuka, can you see anything?
No reactions detected. It's not here.
It seems the lava current is faster than we thought.
The target's velocity doesn't match our predictions.
Hurry up and re-calculate.
Continue the operation. Resume descent.
Depth, 1350...
1400...
A crack has occurred in the second coolant pipe.
Depth, 1480...
We're over the maximum allowed depth.
We haven't made contact with the target yet.
Keep going.
How's it going, Asuka?
Looks like we're still good. I just want to hurry up, finish this, and take a shower.
There's a nice hot spring near here. We'll hit it once we're done.
Hang in there a little longer.
Maximum allowed depth plus 120.
Eva Unit 02 has lost its prog knife.
Maximum allowed depth plus 200.
Miss Katsuragi, any more than this and...
There's a human on board this time!
I am in charge of this operation.
Proceed, please.
Misato's right. I'm okay. I can keep going.
Depth, 1780...
We've reached the adjusted target depth.
There it is!
Visual confirmation of the target.
Prepare to capture.
Both of you are being moved by convection currents, so you'll only have one chance to make contact.
I know. Leave it to me.
T-minus 30 to contact.
Relative velocity 2.2. I'm now on the axis.
Electromagnetic cage deployed. No problems detected.
The target has been captured.
Nice one, Asuka.
Capture operation completed.
I'm coming up now.
Are you all right, Asuka?
Of course! Fear is often worse than the danger, as they say.
It really was a piece of cake.
But this is more of a sauna suit than a plug suit.
I can't wait to get to the hot spring.
Looks like the tension let loose all at once.
You think?
You were scared about this operation too, weren't you?
Well, yeah, because if we handled it badly, we'd have had a repeat performance.
That's true, the Second Impact.
We don't need another of those.
What's going on?!
Not good! It's started to emerge!
It's much earlier than we predicted!
Status of the cage?!
No way it can hold!
Abort the capture! Jettison the cage!
We're changing the operation!
Destroying the Angel is now top priority!
Unit 02, prepare for combat as you withdraw!
What I've been waiting for!
Damn, I forgot I dropped the knife!
It's right in front!
Releasing ballast!
It's fast!
This is bad. I've lost sight of it.
In addition to that, I've got lousy visibility, I'm really hot, and this suit's plastered to me and feels disgusting.
This really sucks.
Asuka!
We'll take this chance to drop you Unit 01 's knife. Catch it!
Roger!
Oh, no! Have you dropped it yet, Shinji?
Contact with knife, 40 seconds.
The Angel is approaching rapidly!
No! Go away!
Hurry up with it!
Come on, it's too slow!
Oh, no!
Unbelievable! How could it open its mouth in such an environment?
Its construction must be incredible!
Left leg damaged!
Engage heat shields!
Damn you!
If it can withstand such a high heat, high pressure environment, then the prog knife will be useless against it!
Then what should we do?
I know!
Just like earlier!
Eat this!
I see! Thermal expansion!
Transfer all coolant pressure to cable three! Hurry!
Right when I succeeded...
Oh, man, is this it?
Shinji?
Idiot, don't go overboard.
Oomiya
Welcome Nerv Party
Hello?
Is there anyone from Nerv here?
Yes!
Cool Cool DELIVERY MAN (OFF) I need your signature here.
Thanks so much.
From Mr. Kaji?
What could it be?
The bath is over there, to the left.
Bath Men's Today
Heavenly!
I never knew a bath could feel this good.
Shinji, can you hear me?
Yes, Ma'am!
Would you throw me the body shampoo?
We ran out of ours.
Here it comes.
Roger.
Ouch!
You idiot! Watch where you're throwing! You suck!
Sorry.
Don't hit me in some weird spot.
Let me take a look.
Wow, your skin is so soft and smooth, Asuka!
Don't! You're tickling me!
How about right here?
Don't touch that!
Come on, it doesn't wear out!
It expanded.
How embarrassing!
Oh, this? I got this in the Second Impact.
You know all about my past, don't you?
Well, yeah. It's part of my job.
It's all ancient history for both of us.
We shouldn't let it bother us.
To Be Continued
Preview
Those who don't think well of Nerv cut off the power supply to all of New Tokyo-3.
With none of the modern facilities operational, an Angel closes in.
Next episode: "In the Still Darkness" Expect more fan service next time too!
Next Time In the Still Darkness