Cool! I won, I won!
Coin Cleaning 24 Hours OK
Done Take Out Thank you very much
Boy, the cost of doing laundry has been killing me lately.
I wish I at least had the time to wash my own clothes.
You should appreciate the fact you can at least sleep at home.
Please make sure to take your pass.
Take Out
Train Approaching
Hello, Vice Commander.
Good morning, Sir.
Good morning, Sir!
Morning.
You're quite early today.
Well, I have to go up top in Ikari's place.
I see. Isn't today the City Council's regular meeting?
It's a pointless job.
Ikari has always thrust the sundry tasks onto me.
Without the Magi, I'd be lost.
Speaking of which, the city elections are approaching up there, right?
The City Council is merely a shell.
The municipal government, after all, is in fact run by the Magi.
The Magi? You mean the three supercomputers?
Government by majority decision of three different computers.
It's a system that is properly in line with the fundamentals of democracy.
And the council just obeys their decisions?
It's a most efficient form of government.
That's a city of science for you.
It's really an era where science reigns supreme.
Talk about an old-fashioned line.
Come to think of it, you're running an experiment on Unit 00, aren't you?
Yes, we're going to run the second prolonged activation test at 10:30.
I'm looking forward to good news.
Abort experiment! Cut the circuits!
Switching circuits.
Power supply being restored.
This is still the problem here, huh?
Yes, the fact that the conversion efficiency is 0.008 lower than our theoretical value concerns me.
It's just barely within tolerance, though, but what do we do?
Let's try it again using the same configuration, but lower the reciprocal conversion rate by 0.01.
Roger.
Now, let's recommence the reactivation experiment.
Episode #11 In The Still Darkness
Hey, hold up!
Man, that was a run!
You've certainly got a black expression.
It's from seeing your loathsome face first thing in the morning.
Yes, please hold for just a moment.
What?
Um, Father...
What is it? Spit it out!
Well...
Actually today...
We were told to tell our parents that they're having a career discussion interview at school.
I've delegated all such things to Captain Katsuragi.
Don't call me over such nonsense.
Don't forward any more of these calls to...
Oh?
A blackout?
No way. That's not possible.
That's strange. Do you suppose there was an accident?
Maybe Akagi messed up an experiment?
The main power supply has been interrupted.
Voltage level is zero!
It wasn't me.
What do you think?
Well, it'll switch to the backup power supply soon.
It's no good, the backup circuits aren't connecting.
That can't be!
Which circuits are still functioning?
A total of one point two percent! Only the old circuits from number 2567!
Route all remaining power supplies to maintaining the Magi and Central Dogma.
But that will interfere with life support systems.
I don't care! That's our top priority!
Press Button To Cross
Aiming for a politics that everyone can love, with justice and truth...
Boy, she's such a lazy slob.
Can't Captain Katsuragi at least pick up her own laundry?
Press Button To Cross
What?
Maybe Commander Ikari was just really busy?
I don't know...
It wasn't like he hung up, but more like a mechanical failure.
You know, you ARE a man.
Why don't you stop worrying about every little detail?
What?
What are you doing? Here, let me try that!
Damn! It must be broken!
Anyway, let's hurry to the command center.
It's already been down for seven minutes!
This isn't normal.
What's the power system here?
There are three systems, main, sub, and reserve.
It's unthinkable that all three would fail simultaneously.
Which means...
We should assume that the breakers didn't fail on their own, but were taken down on purpose.
Regardless of the cause, it would be disastrous if an Angel were to attack right now.
Radar has detected an unidentified object.
Projected landing point is in the former Atami region.
Projected Course
Central Alert Control Command Center
It's likely the eighth one.
Fuchu General Supreme Command Center
I agree, it must be an Angel.
What are we going to do?
Integrated Alert Control Room
Go to alert status for now. That's the procedure, after all.
This one's destination is going to be New Tokyo-3 anyway.
I agree. Well, there's nothing we need to do.
Projected Course 22nd Alert Group Old Omaezaki S.S.
The Angel has landed.
It's still advancing.
What about New Tokyo-3?
Still no response.
What in the hell are those Nerv guys doing?
I thought gangway ladders were decorative holdovers from the past.
Who'd have thought I'd be using one?
To prepare is to prevent.
This one doesn't work either!
None of the facilities work. This is odd.
Does that mean that something happened down below?
It would be natural to assume that.
In any case, let's try to make contact with Nerv Headquarters.
No good, the emergency phones aren't getting through either.
No good, Line 77 won't connect either.
No, no response.
Not here either. The emergency landline is down too.
What do we do now?
What're you doing?
What are you, stupid? It's the emergency manual!
Anyway, let's go to headquarters.
Yeah, but first let's decide on a group leader before we take action.
And naturally, I am the leader.
No objections, I assume?
Now, let's go.
We can get below through Route 07 over here.
But the doors won't work, will they?
Manual door...
Okay, Shinji, you're up.
Sheesh! You only rely on people at times like this!
Damn those Joint Staff bastards! They only rely on us at times like this.
What does the government say?
Those bastards in Tokyo-2? They're apparently getting ready to run.
Beware of Forest Fires
The Angel is still active and advancing.
In any case, get in contact with the people at Nerv.
But how?
By actually going there.
This is the 3rd District ASDF!
An unidentified object is moving toward this area.
All residents must evacuate to their designated shelters.
Big trouble! I've got to report this to Headquarters right away!
But how?
Remember Takahashi remains calm even in situations like this!
Please support candidate Takahashi!
Lucky!
But you know, it sure is hot.
Yeah, the air conditioners are out too.
Katsuragi, if you're so hot, why don't you take off your shirt?
There's no reason for shyness between you and me.
Don't get any funny ideas just because we're in this situation.
Okay, okay!
This is bad. Now the air is getting stagnant.
To think this facility represents the most advanced technology on Earth...
But look at the Commander and Vice Commander.
Even this heat isn't getting to them at all.
For Fire Prevention
It's lukewarm.
Yeah.
THE DAY TOKYO-3 STOOD STILL
Pursuant to the declaration of a state of emergency in this district, emergency vehicle, passing through!
Nozomu Takahashi
Excuse me, that's a dead end!
It's okay! Charge!
This is an emergency, after all!
Roger!
No! Stop the car!
This Geo-Front was designed to be a self-sufficient colony, even when isolated from the outside.
Theoretically, it's impossible for all of the power sources to fail at once.
Which means that someone did it deliberately, correct?
Their purpose is likely to be to investigate this facility.
So they could determine HQ's structure through the progress of restoration?
Disrespectful bastards.
I'll run a dummy program through the Magi.
That will make it harder for them to get a complete picture.
I'll leave it to you.
Yes, Sir.
The first havoc wreaked upon our headquarters wasn't caused by an Angel, but by another member of our species.
Just goes to show.
Ultimately, the enemy of mankind is mankind.
This would normally take only two minutes.
Is this really a corridor?
Once we get over there, we should be able to come out in the Geo-Front.
I've heard that from you four times already.
You really are a nitpicky man!
You're always focusing on the stupidest things.
Quiet.
What now, Miss Perfect?
Someone's voice.
Ang proaching...
That's Mr. Hyuga!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
An Angel is approaching! Repeat, an Angel is approaching!
An Angel is approaching?!
There's no time to waste. Let's take a short cut.
I'm the leader! Don't just take over!
So where's this short cut?
This may be the quickest way, but we look really lame.
Say, what do you suppose the Angels are?
Why are you talking about that at a time like this?
Angels, messengers of God, enemies named after servants of Heaven.
Why are we fighting them?
What are you, stupid?
Strange beings are attacking us.
If you're going through a fire, you've got to brush away the embers, of course!
To the right!
I think it's left.
Oh, be quiet!
What do you think, Shinji?
Well...
I wonder?
Honestly! I'm the leader, so just shut up and follow me!
I still think this is weird. We're going uphill.
What do you mean, you still think? You're such a nag!
Look, this has got to be it this time!
Well, we've visually confirmed the Angel's presence.
Now, we know we have to hurry.
Angel is approaching! Immediate Eva dispatch will be necessary!
Oh, no!
Fuyutsuki, I'll leave the rest to you.
Ikari?
I'll start preparing for the Eva launch in the cage.
Don't tell me...
Manually?
There's an emergency diesel generator.
But...
We have no pilots.
Not again!
This way.
I've heard that you're Commander Ikari's favorite.
I guess being Miss Perfect, the teacher's pet, really shows.
Let's not do this now.
You always get to look all smug.
Don't think that being favored means that you can mess with me!
I'm not messing with you.
And I'm not favored either.
I know that quite well.
Heave ho! Heave ho!
Roger.
Ejection of the terminal plug is complete.
Good, prepare to insert the entry plug for all three units.
But the pilots aren't here yet.
Don't worry, they'll come without fail.
I can't open this with my hands.
It can't be helped. We'll have to break into a duct to get through.
This First Child is scary!
She's the type who will do anything to accomplish her objectives.
In other words, a self-righteous bitch.
The plug is fixed and ready.
Now, we just have to wait for the kids.
Don't you dare look forward! If you do, I'll kill you!
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
Didn't I just say not to look?!
I couldn't help it! I've got to...
You guys!
All units, prepare for entry!
Roger, open the hatches manually.
How are the Evas?
They're in standby.
But nothing's working.
It was all done by hand.
It was the Commander's idea.
My father's?
Commander Ikari had faith that you would come, and prepared everything.
Flywheel, ready for connection!
All units, interior set.
We're good! Run the cell motor!
Plugs inserted.
All units activated using backup power supply.
Release the primary lock bolts.
Hydraulic locks numbers 2 through 32, released.
Zero pressure.
The situation is free.
Go ahead. Each unit, force open the restraints under your own power.
Head out!
The target appears to have halted directly above us!
Get ready! Hurry up!
The emergency batteries have been loaded!
All right, we can do this!
Launch!
Geez! This is SO uncool!
We're approaching the vertical shaft.
This is still uncool.
Watch out! Dodge!
No!
It appears the target is going to invade HQ using a powerful liquid solvent.
What'll we do?
We're going to beat it, of course.
Sure, but how?
We dropped our rifles, and the battery packs are running out.
They won't last more than another three minutes.
I have a plan.
The one who stays here will be defense.
Their job is to neutralize the AT Field, and to protect the offensive player from the liquid solvent.
The backup player will go down, pick up the rifles, and hand them to the offense.
The offense will then fire a volley to destroy the target.
Does that sound good?
Fine. I will take the defense.
Sorry, but it's not you.
I'll do it.
No way! It's dangerous!
That's why.
I don't want to stay indebted to you from last time.
Shinji's on offense. Miss Perfect is the backup.
Got it?
Understood.
Okay, here we go!
Gehen!
Ayanami!
Asuka, get out of the way!
Now we're even.
Oh, damn it! Why won't it open?!
This is an emergency!
I've gotta go!
Hey, I told you not to look up!
Yeah, yeah...
Disgusting...
It's ironic that the stars are so beautiful when there's no electricity or artificial lights.
But without the lights, it doesn't feel like anyone lives there.
See? I feel much more comfortable this way.
Man has always feared the darkness, carving away at it with fire.
How philosophical!
Is that what makes mankind a special species?
Is that why the Angels keep attacking us?
What are you, stupid?
There's no way to know that.
To Be Continued
Preview
Misato sublimates her frustration into destroying the Angels.
A past is revealed.
However, the largest Angel yet, flying in from the stratosphere, causes people to abandon hope.
Next episode: "The Value of a Miracle" Watch it with all your friends!
Next Time The Value of a Miracle