15 Years Ago Year 2000 A.D.
Father...
Episode #12 The Value of a Miracle
Thanks, Shinji, you really saved us from the rain.
Where's Miss Misato?
I guess she must still be asleep.
She's been working all night recently.
That's right, she has a tough job.
Let's keep it quiet so that we don't wake her up.
What are you guys doing here?!
Taking shelter from the rain.
You sure you guys aren't after me?
Well, I'm changing, so if you peep, I'll kill you!
Shut up, ya idiot!
Who'd wanna see ya changin' clothes?!
She's way too self-conscious.
Sorry for disturbing you!
Well, welcome, you two.
I see you're back. We've got a harmonics test tonight, so don't be late.
Right.
Did you hear that, Asuka?
Yes, Ma'am!
Congratulations on your promotion!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
You're most welcome.
Well, see you later.
See you!
What's up? Did something happen to Miss Misato?
Didn't you see her collar tab?
The number of lines increased to two.
That means that she's been promoted from captain to major.
Really? I didn't notice that.
Yeah, I wonder when...
Are ya serious? You guys are pathetic!
Don't you two have any compassion?
You know, it's a tough job for someone so young to foster two junior high kids!
We're the only ones who've got any human compassion.
Units 00 and 02 are both on the edge of the contamination zone.
They've reached their limit.
Unit 01 can still tolerate a little more though, can't he?
Lower the graph depth another 0.3.
He's almost reached the contamination zone.
And he's still getting these readings? Incredible.
His harmonics and sync rate are also catching up with Asuka's.
Is this what you call a gift, I wonder?
It's like he was born to pilot an Eva.
Even if he doesn't want to.
I doubt that'll make him happy.
Good work, you three.
Shinji, you did well.
What do you mean?
Your harmonics value increased by eight points since the last test.
That's very good.
But it's still fifty points lower than mine!
Yes, but it's eight points in ten days. That's impressive.
That's not impressive!
Isn't that great?
Such words of praise for you!
I'm going on ahead, idiot!
...and that was a postcard from "Mr. Wah" of Tokyo-2.
But you know, don't get all sulky because you got dumped by a girl.
Congratulations on your promotion.
Thanks.
When I was a kid, this area was filled with barracks and we were just grateful if we got to eat that day.
But to be honest, I'm not really all that thrilled.
I can understand that.
Getting praised like earlier doesn't make me all that happy either.
We didn't have the leisure to do anything about the people we liked.
All it does is make Asuka angry.
Our parents are safe and food isn't a problem, so we have a lot to be thankful for in this era.
I wonder why she got mad?
We live in a great time in which we can really enjoy happiness.
What did I do wrong?
That bothers you?
You got that, Mr. Wah?
Yes.
That's because all you ever do is worry about what other people think.
Congratulations On Your Promotion Celebration Spot Reserved Today
Congratulations!
Thanks, guys!
Thank you, Suzuhara.
Nah. He's the one who came up with this.
That's right! I, Kensuke Aida was the planner! Kensuke Aida!
Thank you, Aida.
Oh, no, all I did was what anybody would have done!
But why's the class rep here?
Because I invited her.
Right?
What about Rei?
Of course I invited her, but that girl's unsociable.
Man, Mr. Kaji's so late.
Is Mr. Kaji really that cool?
Totally!
He's so much better than these dorks that it's like night and day.
It's an insult to compare him to them.
What'd ya say?!
Let's hear that again!
Is it still difficult for you to be in this kind of situation?
I'm okay.
I'm just not used to being with so many people.
Why do they have to be so noisy?
A promotion...
That means that people have acknowledged your work, right?
Yeah, I suppose.
That's why they're happy.
But it doesn't make you happy?
Oh, it's not like I'm not happy. I am, a little.
But that's not the reason I work here.
Then why did you join Nerv?
Congrats Major
Well, it's been so long that I forgot.
That's got to be Mr. Kaji!
I came directly from HQ. We just happened to meet on the way.
That's rather suspicious.
Oh, are you jealous?
As if.
Anyway, I'd like to offer my congratulations, Major Katsuragi.
I guess I can't gripe to you anymore.
What are you trying to say, you jerk?
But anyway, it's unprecedented for both the Commander and vice Commander to leave Japan together.
That just shows how they trust you to hold down the fort while they're gone.
My father's not here?
Commander Ikari is at the South Pole right now.
The South Pole, a world of death which permits no life to exist.
Or should I simply call it Hell?
Nevertheless, we, mankind, are here.
We're living things, and we're alive.
That's because we're under the protection of science.
Science is the power of man.
That arrogance is what caused the tragedy of fifteen years ago, the Second Impact.
And here is the end result.
This is a greater punishment than we deserve.
This is truly the Dead Sea.
Yet this is a world that has been purified, purged of the original sin.
I'd prefer a world where people live, no matter how stained with sin.
Reporting. Telegram received from Nerv Headquarters.
An Angel has been detected in orbit above the Indian Ocean.
It appeared suddenly, two minutes ago.
Search Satellite 6 moving to that orbit.
Two minutes to contact.
We have video of the target.
That's impressive.
Now that's just ridiculous.
Closing on target.
Start search.
Data transmission commencing.
Reception confirmed.
Commencing analysis.
Was that an AT Field?
It's a new way of using it.
What incredibly destructive power.
That's an AT Field!
It's using kinetic energy too.
It's like this Angel is a bomb in and of itself.
In any case, the first blast was way off and hit the Pacific.
And two hours later, the second shot struck there.
Since then, it has been steadily adjusting for error.
That means it's learning.
Photo: Search Satellite 7 Maximum Magnification
N2 aerial mines had no effect on it either.
The Angel's movements since then are unknown.
It's probably coming here.
Yes, and next time it'll drop itself.
So, that will give us a third Ashinoko Lake?
All five Fuji Lakes will be fused into a single body linked to the Pacific, taking Headquarters with it.
What about Commander Ikari?
We're unable to contact him due to the Angel's powerful jamming.
What is the Magi's judgment?
They unanimously agree in recommending evacuation.
What will you do?
You're the one who's in charge now.
Notify all of the Japanese government ministries.
Under special declaration D-17, provided for under Nerv's authority, all residents within radius of 50km are to evacuate immediately.
Ask Matsushiro to back up the Magi.
We're abandoning this location?
No, but it's not necessary to place everyone at risk.
A D-17 Special Declaration has been made by the government.
All Lanes Outgoing
All residents must evacuate to their designated locations.
Beginning with the 6th and 7th blocks, move according to your district chief's direction immediately.
The evacuation of the city is complete.
In accordance with Department Alert C, the evacuation of noncombatants and D class personnel has been completed.
You're going to do this? Seriously?
Yes, I am.
You're going to throw away all three Evas with your selfish decision?
The chance of success is only 0.00001 %!
That's not even one in ten thousand!
It's not zero. I'm just banking on the Evas.
Major Katsuragi!
I am currently in charge.
I want to do whatever I can.
Destroying Angels is my duty.
Your duty? Don't make me laugh.
This is for your own sake, isn't it?
Your revenge against the Angels!
SHE SAID, "DON'T MAKE OTHERS SUFFER FOR YOUR PERSONAL HATRED."
WHAAAAAAT?
Catch it in our hands?
That's right. We'll position the Evas in the estimated drop zone.
You'll catch it while maintaining your AT Fields at full strength.
What if the Angel is far off course?
We'll be out of luck, then.
What if the Evas aren't able to withstand the impact?
We're out of luck then too.
Our chance of success?
God only knows, is all I can say.
If we succeed, it'll truly be a miracle.
The only miracles with any value are the ones you work.
Meaning, make it work somehow?
I'm sorry, but we have no other options for this operation.
How can you call this an operation?!
You're right, we really can't.
So if you don't want to, you can refuse.
Are you all okay with this?
Regulations say you're technically supposed to write a will. What do you want to do?
That's fine, I don't plan on needing one.
I'm fine too. I have no need.
I'm also fine.
I'm sorry.
Once this is over, I'll treat everyone to a steak dinner!
What? Really?
I promise.
Yay!
Don't forget!
You can count on it.
So I suppose steak defines a great dinner.
Does she think a kid these days would be impressed with steak?
That's why I say the Second Impact generation has really cheap standards.
She can't help it.
What was with that "Yay!"? Pretending you're so happy!
If it helps Miss Misato feel good about being in command, what's wrong with that?
Now, since she's going to treat us, I wonder where we should have her take us?
Tokyo Gourmet
You're coming with us this time.
I'm not going.
Why not?
I don't like meat.
Because of the Angel's radio disturbance, the target has been lost.
We can't determine the exact location, but based on the data up until we lost it, the estimated point of impact calculated by the Magi is here.
The range is this wide?
The distance from one side to the other is enormous.
Given the size of the target's AT Field, it could totally annihilate HQ by hitting anywhere in this zone.
Given that, we'll station the Evas at each of these three points.
On what grounds is this dispersal based?
Intuition.
Intuition?
Yes, a woman's intuition.
How slipshod!
I can see our miracle getting further and further away.
Miss Misato has never won the lottery.
Say...
What?
Asuka, why do you pilot an Eva?
To exhibit my talent to the world, of course.
You mean to prove that you exist?
Yeah, something like that.
You're not going to ask her?
I've asked Ayanami before.
My, how intimate the two of you are.
It's not like that.
Then what about you, Shinji?
I don't know.
You don't know? What are you, stupid?
Maybe I am.
You really are stupid.
One hundred twenty minutes to estimated time of impact.
You all evacuate too.
I can take care of this myself.
No, this is our job as well.
We can't let the kids risk their lives by themselves.
They'll be fine.
Even if the Evas are badly damaged, their AT Fields will protect the kids.
Inside an Eva is the safest place to be.
Shinji, yesterday you asked me why I joined Nerv.
My father was a man who lived for his research, for his dreams, to the exclusion of all else.
I could never forgive him for that.
I even hated him.
Just like my father.
He never took care of me, my mother or the family.
His friends always said he was very sensitive and delicate.
But the truth was that he was just a weak person running away from reality, the reality called his family.
He was like a kid.
I readily agreed with my mother when she decided to divorce him, because she was always crying.
It seemed to have come as a shock to him, but at the time, I laughed at him because I felt he'd brought it on himself.
But he sacrificed himself to save my life at the end.
Back during the Second Impact.
Then, I didn't know whether I hated him or loved him.
The only thing that was clear to me was I wanted to destroy the Angels who caused the Second Impact.
So in order to do that, I joined Nerv.
In the end, maybe I just want to get revenge on my father, so that I can free myself of him.
I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away.
Right.
I must not run away.
Target has been sighted at maximum magnification.
Distance is approximately 25,000.
Here it comes.
All Evas, start positions.
All we have is a rough estimated trajectory from optical sightings.
So the Magi will guide you until the distance is 10,000 meters.
After that, use your own judgment.
I'm leaving it all to you.
Maximum Magnification Relay: Optical Observation Post 3 Angel approaching, approximate distance 20,000.
Commence operation.
Here we go.
Start!
Distance 12,000!
Field at maximum!
Unit 02! Field to maximum!
I'm doing it!
Now!
Bastard!
Our wireless communications have been restored.
We're receiving a message from Commander Ikari at the South Pole.
Connect him here.
Yes, Ma'am.
I'm very sorry, Sir.
My selfish decision has caused Unit 01 to incur damage.
The responsibility is entirely mine.
That is not a problem. Destroying Angels is the Evas' purpose.
In fact, we are fortunate to have sustained such minimal damage.
Yes, excellent work, Major Katsuragi.
Thank you, Sir.
By the way, is the pilot of Unit 01 there?
Yes, Sir!
I've received the report. Good work, Shinji.
Yes, Sir.
Now, Major Katsuragi, I'll leave the rest in your hands.
All Lanes Incoming
New Tokyo-3 Loop 7
Next station is New Miyanoshita, New Miyanoshita.
The exit will switch to the left side at the next station.
Now you're going to have to keep your promise.
Of course!
I withdrew a fortune, so I can even handle a full-course dinner.
Though it's before payday...
Ramen
We know the state of your wallet.
You can take it easy.
And Miss Perfect said she'd join us if it was for ramen noodles.
I'll have a garlic ramen with no roast pork.
I'll have shark fin with roast pork. Large!
There you go, one shark fin with roast pork!
Say, Miss Misato?
What?
When I heard my father's words earlier, I think I finally understood what it's like to feel happy when you're praised.
And I also realized that maybe I pilot the Eva because I wanted to hear those words from him.
You're piloting for something like that?
You really are stupid.
To Be Continued
Preview
An incident occurs during a simulation plug experiment, the underground faciities are corrupted one after another, and finally Nerv is confronted with making the decision to self-destruct.
Next episode: "Angel lnvasion" And expect more fan service next time too!
Next Time Angel Invasion