Apoptosis work for the three Evas will be performed as scheduled as soon as the Magi system is reactivated.
Operation confirmed. 450 through 670 omitted.
Command has granted approval.
Way to go, Maya. That was fast.
Of course, you're the one who trained me.
Wait a second, A-8 would be faster there.
Let me see that.
Impressive as ever, Ma'am!
How's it going? Are you finished giving the Magi their check-up?
Pretty much. As promised, we made it in time for today's tests.
That's my Ritsuko.
Considering it's a tough job with three of them.
That one's cold.
Regular Screening Under Inspection Done
All three Magi systems have entered self-diagnostic mode.
127th routine maintenance, all normal.
Roger. Good work.
Everyone, take a break until the tests begin.
Everything checked out.
As usual, Mother's in good shape, but...
Is getting older the only thing I'm going to do?
Episode #13 Angel Invasion
What? You want me to take off my clothes again?
The next chamber is an ultra-clean room environment.
Just taking a shower and changing your undergarments is insufficient.
Why do I have to go through all this for a simple autopilot test?
Time isn't just passing us by.
The technology of the Evas is making progress as well.
We constantly need new data.
All right, here I am, just the way you wanted, after being run through the wash cycle seventeen times.
Now, I want all three of you to stay that way as you walk through the room and board the entry plug.
What?!
Don't worry. The video monitors have been shut off.
Your privacy is protected.
That isn't the point! It's an emotional thing!
This test's purpose is to remove the support of your plug suits and conduct harmonics directly from your bodies.
Asuka, that's an order.
Oh, fine! Don't you dare peek!
All pilots are ready for entry.
Start the test.
Beginning the test. Initiate autopilot recording.
Monitors, nominal.
Inserting simulation plugs.
Connecting simulation bodies to the system.
The simulation plugs are now under the Magi's control.
Wow, this is going really fast! Thank goodness for the Magi.
It's hard to believe that the first experiment took a whole week.
The test is scheduled to end in approximately three hours.
How does it feel?
It's a little different.
Yes, I think it's different than usual.
The sensations are kind of weird.
My right arm is all I can feel clearly. Everything else is fuzzy.
Rei, imagine moving your right hand.
Yes, Ma'am.
Data collection is proceeding smoothly.
There don't seem to be any problems so far.
Return the Magi to their normal state.
Resolving Processing
A dilemma...
You can sure see the creator's personality, can't you?
What are you talking about? You're the one who created them, right?
You don't know anything, do you?
That's because you don't babble about yourself like I do, Ritsuko!
That's true. I just brought the system up.
The one who developed the fundamental theory and the mainframe was my mother.
Submitted Resolving Processing
You're double-checking this?
Yes, just in case.
Sigma Unit D-17 87th Protein Wall
These are the parts that were brought in three days ago.
This is the area that's deteriorating.
The 87th protein wall...
With magnification, you can see something that looks like stains.
I wonder what they could be?
It's got to be corrosion.
There are slight variations in the temperature and conduction rates.
Deterioration of sterilized rooms is happening a lot lately.
The construction schedule was cut by about sixty days, so there were probably some air bubbles mixed in again.
The construction of B Wing is just sloppy.
It was built after the Angels appeared, after all.
It's not surprising. Everyone's exhausted.
Take care of it by tomorrow.
Otherwise we'll never hear the end of it from Ikari.
Roger.
Another water leak?
No, it's apparently some kind of corrosion in the protein wall above us.
Wonderful.
Any effect on this test?
No, not at the moment.
Then, let's continue.
We can't abort this test over minor technical issues.
We'd never hear the end of it from Commander Ikari.
Roger. Synchronization value is nominal.
No changes to plug signals.
Connecting the simulation plugs to the Evas via the simulation bodies.
Contact with Eva Unit 00 has been confirmed.
AT Field will be generated at output of 2 yocto.
What's happening?!
We've got a contamination alert on Floor A in the Sigma unit.
The 87th protein wall is corroding and releasing heat.
Abnormality detected in pipe six as well.
Corrosion area of the protein wall increasing!
At an explosive rate!
Abort the experiment.
Initiate emergency shutoff of the sixth pipe.
Yes, Ma'am!
Close All
Emergency Closure
Numbers 60, 38 and 39 are all closed.
Corrosion has occurred in 6-42.
No effect! Corrosion is spreading along the walls.
Prepare the polysomes.
Set laser power at maximum. Fire upon contact.
Corrosion has reached 6-58. It's coming!
Rei!
Rei's simulation body is moving.
Impossible!
The corrosion is spreading further.
It's invading the simulation bodies' suspension system.
Pull In Case Of Emergency
How's Rei?!
She's all right.
All plugs emergency eject.
Hurry up with the lasers!
An AT Field?!
It can't be!
What is this?
The pattern analysis is blue.
There's no question. It's an Angel.
An Angel?! You let an Angel get inside?
I'm sorry, Sir.
Save the excuses.
Physically isolate Central Dogma.
Quarantine it from Sigma Unit.
Initiating physical isolation of Central Dogma.
Quarantining from Sigma Unit.
We're abandoning the Box! All personnel evacuate!
What the hell are you doing? Hurry!
Quarantining Sigma Unit from Floor B.
Closing all partitions. All area personnel must evacuate.
I know. Please take care of it.
Stop the alarm.
Stopping the alarm, Sir.
This is a malfunction, an error in the alarm system.
Report that to both the Japanese government and the committee.
Yes, Sir!
The contaminated area is descending further.
It's spreading all over Sigma Unit from the Pribnow Box!
That's a bad area.
Yes, it's too close to Adam.
Stop the corrosion within Sigma Unit!
If necessary, sacrifice the Geo-Front. What's the Evas' status?
Standing by in cage seven.
We can launch them as soon as the pilots are recovered.
There's no need to wait for the pilots. Launch them immediately.
Unit 01 has top priority. Sacrifice the other two if necessary.
Unit 01?
But Sir, we can't physically destroy the Angel without the Evas.
If the Evas are contaminated first, it'll all be over. Hurry!
Yes, Sir!
All of Central Dogma under Sigma Unit will be completely closed off in sixty seconds.
So that's the Angel.
Thirty seconds until activation of vacuum pump.
Guess I don't have time for work now.
Central Dogma has been completely sealed.
Mega-depth facilities are entirely occupied by the intruder.
Well now, how will we fight an Angel without an Eva?
LILLIPUTIAN HITCHER
Look, this is the border between the normal and heavy water.
There's a higher level of oxygen here.
Their preference is pretty obvious.
The area where ozone is vented in to maintain aseptic conditions isn't contaminated.
So does that mean that its weakness is oxygen?
It would seem so.
Injecting ozone.
Concentration is increasing.
It's working, all right.
Will this work?
It appears Zero A and Zero B will recover.
The area around the pipes has returned to normal.
As expected, the central portion is proving to be tougher.
All right, inject more ozone.
This isn't right.
What? It's increasing?
Something is wrong. Heat levels are increasing.
The contaminated area is spreading again.
It's no use! The ozone is no longer having any effect.
Now it's absorbing the ozone.
Stop the ozone!
Amazing...
It's evolving.
What's wrong?
Something's hacking into the sub-computer.
Intruder unknown.
Not now! Damn it! Dealing with C-mode.
Unfreeze the barrier. Open a decoy entry.
Decoy entry has been avoided.
Eighteen seconds to completion of trace.
Deploying barrier.
Barrier has been penetrated.
Open another false entry.
No human being could do this.
Trace complete. The hacker is inside this facility!
B Wing basement, in the Pribnow Box!
Optical pattern is changing.
Those glowing lines are electronic circuits.
This is just like a computer.
Opening decoy entry.
Failed. We've been blocked.
Sever the main cable.
Negative, it refuses to accept the command.
Fire the lasers.
It's generating an AT Field. No effect.
It's accessing security's main computer bank. Cracking the password.
Twelfth digit... sixteenth digit... D word has been cleared!
It's broken into security's main bank!
It's reading the main bank. We can't stop it.
What is its objective?
Scanning the main bus.
This code is... Oh, no!
It's going to infiltrate the Magi!
Shut down the I/O system.
Count it down!
Three... Two...
One!
We can't cut the power!
The Angel is intruding further.
It's made contact with Melchior.
It's no good! It's going to be taken over!
Melchior has been reprogrammed by the Angel.
Artificial Intelligence Melchior's has submitted an order to independently self-destruct.
Submitted Resolving Processing
Rejected. Rejected. Rejected. Rejected.
Melchior is now hacking into Balthasar!
Rejected
Damn it, it's fast!
What computation speed!
Change the logic mode.
Change synchronization code to every fifteen seconds.
Roger!
Submitted Resolving Processing
How long will it hold for?
Considering the speed up until now, maybe two hours.
To think that the Magi would turn against us...
We can think of them as micro-machines.
Angels the size of microbes.
Those individuals have aggregated together and have undergone explosive evolution to achieve intelligence circuits in this short amount of time.
Evolution...
Yes.
They're continuously changing themselves, searching for a system that can cope with any situation.
That's truly the system of life itself.
Against an enemy that evolves to overcome its weaknesses, the only effective countermeasure is to eliminate the host and let the parasite die with it.
We have no choice but to have it die with the Magi.
I propose the physical elimination of the Magi.
That's impossible.
Destroying the Magi is tantamount to destroying headquarters itself.
Then I officially request it on behalf of the Operations Division.
I refuse.
This is a matter for the Technology Department.
Why are you being so mule-headed?!
This situation is a result of my carelessness.
You've always been like this.
You always take the responsibility on your own shoulders and won't depend on others.
If the Angel keeps evolving, we have a chance.
Expedite its evolution?
Yes.
The end of evolution is self-destruction. Death itself.
Thus, we just need to accelerate its evolution.
If the Angel considers it the only practical means of survival, it may choose to co-exist with the Magi system.
But how?
If the target is a computer itself, we can counter-hack it by connecting Casper to the Angel and uploading a self-destruct acceleration program, but...
Submitted Resolving Processing
At the same time, we'll be turning off the barrier to the Angel.
So it would be a battle of speed between Casper and the Angel.
Yes.
That program had better make it on time.
If Casper is contaminated as well, it'll all be over.
I'll keep my promise.
Alert R issued! Alert R issued!
An emergency has occurred in Nerv Headquarters.
All D-class personnel must evacuate.
What is all this?
Scribbles left by the developer.
Amazing! These are back doors! Magi's back doors!
So it's a veritable encyclopedia of all the tricks up the Magi's sleeve.
Is it okay to see these?
What a surprise! This is INT-C!
With these we can program much faster than we thought, right, Ma'am?
Ikari, you jerk!
Thank you, Mother. We can make it for sure now.
Give me the wrench.
Doesn't this remind you of our college days?
Board number twenty-five.
Hey, tell me a little about the Magi.
It's a long story.
And not a very interesting one, at that.
Do you know about personality transplant OS?
Yes, it's a system that implants an individual's personality into a seventh generation organic computer so it can think.
It's the same technology used for operating the Evas, right?
I've heard Magi was the first of them.
My mother developed the technology.
So, it was her personality that was implanted?
Right.
In a very real sense, this is my mother's brain.
Is that why you wanted to protect the Magi?
I don't think so. I didn't really like my mother that much.
This was a decision as a scientist.
There it is!
Balthasar has been taken over!
Independent self-destruct has been approved by the artificial intelligence.
Has it begun?!
Self-destruct device will be triggered 02 seconds after the consent of all three members.
Self-destruct will encompass geoid depth -280, -140 and Floor Zero.
Special Command 582 requires the consent of two computers to cancel the action.
Balthasar is now invading Casper!
We're losing ground!
What speed!
Twenty seconds to self-destruct.
Not good!
Casper will be taken over in eighteen seconds!
Fifteen seconds to self-destruct.
Ritsuko, hurry!
No problem. I've got almost one whole second to spare. Ten seconds to self-destruct.
Only one?!
9...
8...
At least it's not a zero or a minus.
7...
6...
Maya!
We're set! 5...
4...
3...
2... Hit it!
1 ...
Zero.
Submitted Resolving Rejected
Independent self-destruct has been canceled by the artificial intelligence.
All right!
Furthermore, Special Command 582 has also been canceled.
Magi system returning to normal mode.
Alert R canceled. Alert R canceled.
All hands return to first stage alert.
What the heck's going on?
Jeez, I can't go anywhere naked!
Somebody hurry up and help me!
Sigma Unit released. T minus zero three to Magi system reactivation.
Maybe I'm getting old. Staying up for these all-nighters is rough.
You kept your promise again.
Good job.
Thank you.
This is the first time I've ever really appreciated your coffee.
The night before she died, my mother told me that the Magi are three aspects of herself.
Herself as a scientist.
Herself as a mother.
Herself as a woman.
The Magi is those three aspects struggling for dominance.
She intentionally left in the dilemmas of human experience.
Actually, each of the three programs are slightly different.
I don't think I'll ever be a mother, so I don't understand her as a mother.
But I respected her as a scientist.
However, as a woman, I even hated her.
You're rather talkative today.
It's been known to happen.
Casper contains the pattern of her as a woman.
She stayed a woman to the last. How totally like my mother.
To Be Continued
Preview
Nerv, and the secret organization Seele that is behind the Human Instrumentality Project.
Are Commander Ikari's actions solely to realize what is contained in the Dead Sea Scrolls?
Next episode: "Seele, Throne of Souls" And there'll be more fan service next time too!
Next Time Seele, Throne of Souls