It's eating the Angel?
And now those bindings are being undone by the Eva's own might.
We can no longer stop the Eva.
Unit 01's been awakened and set free.
Seele won't stay quiet for this.
The Eva series aren't capable of generating S2 engines themselves.
We never imagined it would take one into itself this way.
This incident is at extreme odds with our script.
It will not be easy to correct for this.
Were we not mistaken to have entrusted Nerv to Gendo Ikari in the first place?
But without that man, we could not have executed all of our plans.
Ikari, what are you thinking?
It's begun, hasn't it?
Yes, it all begins here.
Episode #20 Form of the Mind Form of the Man
Damage on both Eva units is beyond the Hayflick Limit.
It'll take time before everything goes back to normal.
Fortunately, the Magi System can be transferred.
We'll start working on that as early as tomorrow.
But this place will have to be scrapped.
It's just a matter of time before the brass decides to abandon it.
That's true.
For the time being, we'll have to use the backup Secondary Control Center.
You mean, even without the Magi?
That's right.
We'll dust it off and be working again by this afternoon.
But these chairs are hard, and the sensors haven't been broken in, so it's difficult to work here.
Even though the layout is the same as the control center we're familiar with.
It just doesn't feel right, you know?
At least we can use this place.
But what we don't know is whether we can still use Unit 01.
Restrained by the cage... are you sure it's safe?
No internal thermal, electron, electromagnetic, or chemical energy readings are being detected.
The S2 engine is completely inactive.
Nevertheless, under those conditions, Unit 01 has moved on three separate occasions.
You can't treat it carelessly based only on what we can see and measure.
We don't know what it'll do if we meddle with it carelessly.
Just like you, Miss Katsuragi.
I'm sorry.
However, our concerns are not limited to Unit 01 .
Correct. Serious damage was sustained by Units 00 and 02.
Headquarters was partially destroyed, Central Dogma exposed.
The damages are enormous.
We can't even estimate how much money and time we've lost.
All this is because we didn't put a bell around Ikari's neck.
There is a bell, it just didn't ring.
A bell that doesn't ring serves no purpose.
We'll have the bell take action next time.
My, my, what an unexpected turn of events.
The committee...
I mean, how do you intend to explain this to Seele?
Unit 01 wasn't under our control.
This was an unexpected accident.
Therefore Unit 01 will stay frozen until the Committee gives us further orders.
That's a very appropriate decision.
However, is your son still trapped inside it?
As expected, it's not working. The code to eject the entry plug isn't being accepted.
What about the backup and dummy signals?
They're being refused. We can't open a direct circuit either.
We've connected to the plug's video monitor.
Switching to the main monitor.
What in the hell is this?
This is the truth behind the 400% synch rate.
I can't believe it. What in the world happened to Shinji?
He's been taken into Eva Unit 01.
What does that mean?! Just what is an Eva?!
It is something created by man in man's own image.
I really can't describe it any other way.
Something created by man?
Didn't you just copy what you found then at the South Pole?
I'm sure the original would be appalled to hear this.
This is not just a copy, because it is imbued with a human will.
Are you saying somebody willed this to happen as well?!
It could be the Eva's...
Do something, damn you!
You created it, didn't you?! Take responsibility for it!
On the issue of the Nansa Islands, the government has officially announced there is no federal involvement.
In other news, it has been a month since the terrorist act in Tokyo-2, and the government has passed new legislation to prevent another.
I am still alive.
I got that she made it, okay?!
Damn it, Misato, don't keep calling me over every little thing!
To think... to think I couldn't do anything!
I can't believe I lost to that stupid Shinji!
I hate this!
A plan to salvage Shinji?
That's right. That which can be called Shinji's life still exists.
Now you're respecting human life?
We can't afford to lose Shinji right now.
Well, I wonder?
Isn't what Nerv wants not Shinji's life, but Unit 01 as its tool?
I won't deny it.
We can surmise that Shinji's body lost its ego border, and he's floating in the entry plug in quantum form.
In other words, Shinji has shifted into a form we can't see?
Yes, the composition of the LCL inside the plug has chemically altered into something very similar to the sea water of primitive Earth.
A soup of life, huh?
All of the substances which composed Shinji are still preserved in the plug, and what could be called his soul exists there as well.
In fact, his self-image is pseudo-substantiating his plug suit.
In other words, salvaging him means reconstructing his body and anchoring his psyche within it.
Is that possible?
With the Magi's support, yes.
Theoretically, right?
You can't know what will happen until you try it.
What is this?
Where am I?
In the entry plug?
In Unit 01?
But there's nobody here. I'm not even here.
What is this? What is this? What is this?
I don't really understand.
These people...
Yes, they're people I know, people who know me.
I see. This is all part of my world.
What is this?
This is supposed to be my world, but I don't really understand.
An image from outside?
An unpleasant image?
That's right! The enemy!
Enemy (repeated)
Enemy! Enemy! Enemy! Enemy!
Our enemies, the Angels, given the names of heavenly beings.
They are the targets of the Evas and Nerv.
The object of revenge for Miss Misato's father!
Why do I fight despite all I've been put through?
What are you, stupid?
Strange beings are attacking us.
If you're going through a fire, you've got to brush away the embers, of course!
Maybe I don't need a reason.
Maybe I'm not supposed to think about it.
Enemy! Enemy! Enemy! Enemy!
They're all my enemies!
Those that threaten me... us... they are the enemy.
That's right! What's wrong with protecting my life, our lives?!
Enemy! Enemy! Enemy! Enemy!
My enemy! My enemy!
Damn! Damn! Damn!
How dare you hurt Toji and kill my mother!
Father!
Of course! Anyone would.
You can't understand your father?
Of course not. I've hardly ever seen him.
Is that why you hate him?
Yes, my father doesn't need me! My father deserted me!
And am I the substitute?
That's right! That's got to be it!
He abandoned me because he had you!
As if you didn't run away all by yourself.
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
It's all his fault!!
That time, I was actually going to tell him I hate him!
Come. Gendo Ikari
Welcome to Nerv
Rei Ayanami Gendo Ikari Yui Ikari Father Mother Child Stranger Self The Ego Hypocrisy Needs Repression The Weak Identification Self Internalization Breasts Inferiority Complex Will Symbiosis Solitude Compensation Reality Ideal Inculcation Mind and Body Fear Insecurity value Dependence Escape Estrangement Loss Oral Stage Obsession Inculcation Shinji Ikari
Are you telling me to get on that thing and put myself in danger, Father?
Correct.
What's with that?! I don't want to! Why are you saying this now?!
I thought you didn't need me, Father!
I merely called you because I needed you.
Why me?
Because it's impossible for anyone else.
But that's impossible.
I've never even seen or heard of it. There's no way I could do it!
No, I knew.
That's right! I knew the Eva.
And that time, I ran away!
Away from Mother and Father!
WEAVING A STORY 2: ORAL STAGE
Current LCL temperature holding steady at 36 degrees.
No problem with oxygen concentration.
Electromagnetic radiation pulse is normal. Wave pattern is B.
All instrumentation is functioning normally.
Operation Plan Type EP2 Salvage Work Procedural Outline (and Type LP3 Complementation Procedure) IBUKI Salvage Plan Outline...
Only you could have created all this in just one month.
Unfortunately, I didn't come up with the idea.
It's data from experiments completed ten years ago.
IBUKI This kind of thing happened during the Eva's development?
It was before I worked here.
It seems my mother was here, but I only know the data.
And how did it come out back then?
I heard they failed.
Kindness...
Warmth...
Is this the warmth of a human?
I never knew it.
What is loneliness?
I didn't understand it before, but I think I do now.
What is happiness?
Are others kind to you?
Yes.
Why?
Because I'm an Eva pilot.
Because I pilot Eva, they treat me well.
That's the reason why I'm allowed to be here.
It's all that sustains me.
So I have to pilot Eva.
Pilot, and?
Enemy! Yes, I have to fight what everyone calls the enemy!
Fight, and?
I have to win!
Right, I mustn't lose.
I have to pilot the Eva as I'm told.
And I have to win as I'm told!
Otherwise...
Nobody...
Do your best.
What are you doing? Do it right.
Do your best, man.
Do your best.
Good work, Shinji.
Miss Misato, Miss Ritsuko, Asuka, Toji, Kensuke, and Father.
They all praise me.
When I pilot Eva, they all praise me.
They praise someone like me, and they all tell me to pilot it.
Father...
The father that abandoned me...
I'll show him!
Do your best.
I'm doing my best.
I am doing my best!
Somebody be nice to me.
I've fought so hard! I'm fighting with everything I've got!
Treat me well!
Be nice to me!
I am nice to you.
Tell me, Shinji, do you want to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It's a very, very comforting feeling.
It's okay, you know. I'm okay whenever you are.
Hey, stupid Shinji, don't you want to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
Because it's a very, very comforting feeling.
You don't hear me say this every day. Come over here already.
Ikari, do you want to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It's a very, very comforting feeling.
Ikari?
Do you want to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It's a very, very comforting feeling.
Come on, relax, and release your soul.
All investigative probes inserted.
Fixed at electromagnetic radius of zero minus three.
Ego border pulse connection is complete.
Roger. Start salvage.
Roger, transmitting first signal.
Eva has received the signal. No sign of rejection.
Proceeding to transmit second and third signals.
Subject cathexis is normal.
Destrudo cannot be confirmed.
Roger, shift the subject to stage two.
Shinji!
Asuka Stupid Shinji!
Ritsuko
Shinji!
Toji Hey, Shinji!
Kensuke
Yo, Shinji!
Ikari...
Shinji! (repeated)
Misato
It's no good. The ego border is frozen in a loop.
Try firing all range of waveforms in all directions.
It's not working. The signals are being trapped in Klein space.
What does that mean?
It means we failed.
Abort intervention. Reverse tangent plug.
Return the additive value to zero.
Yes, Ma'am.
Destrudo reaction in the old area. Pattern sepia.
We've detected a change in the core pulse too! Plus 0.3 is confirmed!
Maintenance of the status quo is top priority. Prevent back flow.
Yes, Ma'am.
Plus 0.5... 0.8... This is odd.
I can't stop it!
What is this? Why?
Don't you want to come back, Shinji?
I don't understand.
I...
What do you wish?
Eva has rejected the signal.
The self-formation of LCL is breaking down.
Pressure in the plug is increasing!
Abort all operations. Drop the power.
It's not working. The plug is venting!
Shinji!
Where am I?
Inside the Eva.
Inside the Eva?
Did I pilot the Eva again? Why?
You won't pilot the Eva anymore?
I've decided I will never pilot Eva again.
But you did pilot Evangelion Unit 01 .
Shinji, you are here now because you piloted the Eva.
You are the person you are now because you piloted the Eva.
You cannot deny it, that you in fact piloted the Eva, nor can you deny the self that you have been so far, which is your past.
But as for what you will do from now on, you must decide for yourself.
I...
If it can't...
If it can't even save one life, then what good is science?!
Give Shinji back! Give him back!
A smell...
A person's smell?
Miss Misato?
Ayanami?
No, not them.
That's right.
This is the smell of my mother.
So he will live in this world, in the hell after the Second Impact?
Oh, but if you have the will to live, anywhere can be heaven.
Because he is alive.
He'll have plenty of chances to find happiness.
I see. That's very true.
Mother...
Have you decided yet?
If it's a boy, Shinji. If it's a girl, I'll name her Rei.
Shinji...
Rei...
Mother...
Shinji!
Sure, I can understand, but I guess that's what's called the oral stage.
The restoration of Unit 01 will be complete the day after tomorrow.
It's something a psychologist came up with a long time ago.
In the end, I guess humans will even use God's powers as a tool.
In other words, it's where you want to be with your mother forever.
It refers to people who want to always be dependent on someone.
There's someone like that among my acquaintences too, and you're a lot like him.
I don't know about that.
I hear some on the committee have even suggested a freeze.
So, well, as far as I can see from your letter, from your girlfriend's standpoint,
The artificial human Evangelion...
being your lover, your mother, and what else, your kid sister?
For it being man-made, don't you think the black box of unknowns is too large?
I think being all of these things for you is pretty rough.
And you know, aren't you sort of taking advantage of her place as a lover,
Well, not that I care, since Shinji was ultimately saved.
using it as your personal outlet for your libido?
Okay, well, that might have been a little extreme.
That wasn't me. It was you, probably.
But a woman is very sensitive to whether someone loves her or not.
So I think she's probably twigged onto that by now, that you're looking for a mother you can sleep with in her.
How about it? Want to go out for a drink for once?
And if she still hasn't brought up splitting up with you,
Sorry, I've got somewhere to go today.
she might be one of those nice girls that are pretty rare these days, you know?
I see.
See you!
Going on a tryst with a man the moment she knows that Shinji is safe?
I guess I'm in no position to talk.
Ritsuko must be thinking I'm pretty disgusting right about now.
Indulging our carnal desires is more realistic as humans.
We can fool them a little.
Our Intelligence Department?
Or Commander Ikari and Ritsuko?
Or me?
No, myself.
You mean others, don't you?
You don't have any interest in others, but you want their attention anyway.
You really are just like my father.
I didn't know you still smoked.
I only smoke after this sort of thing.
So nobody knows but you.
Well, I'm honored.
So, how far has the Human Instrumentality Project gotten?
Adam, destroyer of humanity.
Why is it being kept underground?
Are you seeing me because you want to know that?
Well, that's one of the reasons, to be honest.
I'm most honored to be used by a lady, but I can't tell you in a place like this.
All I care about right now is for you to understand what I want.
What is Nerv's and Commander Ikari's true objective?
I'd like to know that myself.
Hey, don't dodge my questions by doing that!
Hey, no!
Don't put strange things in there!
What are you doing at a time like this? What's that?
A present for you, the first in eight years.
Though it may be the last.
To Be Continued
Preview
vice Commander Fuyutsuki is abducted by Seele.
Year 2015 Kyoto, Year 1999
Memories of the past that pass through his mind.
Antarctica, Year 2000 Year 2001 Year 2002
Everything started in Kyoto, in 1999.
Hakone, Year 2003 Year 2005 New Tokyo-2, Nagano Prefecture Year 2004
Will Nerv be enough of a fortress for mankind?
Year 2008 Year 2010 Complete
Next episode: "The Birth of Nerv"
Year 2015 Once Again
Next Time The Birth of Nerv