Hello, I'm not home right now.
Please leave your message after the beep.
My last job...
The red is as if it's for the color of blood.
Episode #21 Nerv Is Born
Abducted?! The vice Commander?
It happened two hours ago.
He was last seen in District 8 on the west side.
That's within our compound!
What was your Intelligence Department doing?!
There's an insider who leaked information and instigated this.
He was able to get the better of us.
Someone who can pull the wool over the eyes of Intelligence Division 2?
It can't be!
Ryoji Kaji is the man believed to be the mastermind behind this.
And that's why you're here.
We appreciate your quick understanding.
As a member of the same organization, it is regrettable that we must suspect the Chief of Operations, but this is part of our job.
Considering the history between me and him, it seems like the logical step to take.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Take her away.
It has been a while, Chairman Kiel.
This is quite a rude welcome.
I need not apologize to you for the impropriety.
This is a necessary procedure in order to speak with you at leisure.
You certainly haven't changed.
Does my convenience mean nothing then?
07: The problem being discussed is an urgent matter.
It was unavoidable.
03: Please understand.
So, it's Seele and not the Committee.
We have no intention of creating a new god.
We would like your cooperation, Professor Fuyutsuki.
Professor Fuyutsuki...
Professor! Professor Fuyutsuki!
Year 1999, Kyoto
Oh, it's you two.
You wanna join us for some beer in Kamogawa?
Again?
Ryoko and the others are saying they'll go if you go.
Our professor was also saying you should show up once in a while.
Sure, all right.
It's good to go out and have a drink every so often.
Yes, Sir.
You excel at your work, but you don't take socializing seriously and that's not good.
I'm sure you're right.
By the way, Fuyutsuki, there's a bioengineering student who submitted an interesting paper.
The student's name is Ikari. Do you know her?
Ikari? No, I don't.
I told her about you and she said she was interested in meeting you.
She'll probably contact you eventually, so take care of things, will you?
Ikari, was it? All right.
Metaphysical Biology Research Room 1 Fuyutsuki
I read your paper.
I found a couple of things questionable, but it was a stimulating paper.
Thank you very much.
Yui Ikari, wasn't it?
Yes.
What are your plans for the future?
Are you going to find work?
Or do you intend to join the research lab here?
I haven't thought that far ahead yet.
And besides, aren't you forgetting a third option?
I'm also considering a domestic life.
Of course, that's only if I can find someone nice.
Back in the Year 2015 02: With an S2 engine on board, Evangelion Unit 01 has become an absolute being!
03: We have no use for an actualized god.
We must not create a god.
We cannot allow that man to create a god.
Gendo Ikari, is he a man that can be trusted?
Gendo Rokubungi? I've heard of him.
Back in the Year 1999
No, I've never met him, but there's always some rumor going around about him.
Kyoto Prefecture Police Department
He asked to be released into my custody?
What?
No, I'll come.
When should I come over there?
I heard about you from a certain person, so I wanted to meet you.
You're a rather coarse man, to get into a drunken brawl.
There was no time to talk. They just picked a fight with me.
I'm not very good at being liked, but I am used to being treated coldly.
Well, it's none of my business anyway.
Professor Fuyutsuki, you seem to be exactly the person I expected you to be.
Yes, my first impression of him was of distaste.
And back then, seasons and autumn still existed in this country.
Are you serious?
Yes, I am seeing Mr. Rokubungi.
When I heard that, I wasn't able to hide my surprise.
I never would have thought you would share your time with him.
Oh, but Professor Fuyutsuki, he's quite a sweet person.
It's just that no one knows it.
Maybe it's more blissful not to know.
Did I inconvenience you by introducing you to him?
No, I'll admit that he's an interesting man, though I can't get to like him.
But within our circle, the common opinion was that he had approached Yui for her talent and for the organization backing her.
Later, I would hear rumors that this organization was called Seele.
Year 2000, Antarctica
The Second Impact.
That tragedy occurred in the final year of the 20th century.
TEXT Year 2001
And the first year of the 21st century was pure hell.
There is no other word to describe that year.
Year 2002
To think this was once a continent of ice...
There's no trace of it left.
Professor Fuyutsuki...
You?
I'm surprised you survived.
I'd heard that you were a member of the Katsuragi Research Team.
Luckily, I had returned to Japan the day before the incident, so I was able to escape the tragedy.
I see.
Rokubungi, you...
Excuse me, I have a different name now.
A postcard? Not a business card?
We're Married Gendo & Yui Ikari It has been a long time. Are you doing well?
Ikari? Gendo Ikari...
My wife has been nagging me to get this to you, Professor Fuyutsuki.
She seems to be a fan of yours.
I'm honored.
How is Yui doing?
Isn't she participating in this expedition?
Yui wanted to come, but we have a child now, so...
Safety First
Your organization...
Seele, was it?
I've heard nothing but bad things about it.
I can't approve of forcibly pinning down the board of directors.
You're fastidious as ever.
No clean organization can survive in this day and age anymore.
The official investigation of the Second Impact...
If the investigation team consisted only of Seele people, you would run into all sorts of issues later.
We're just a makeshift solution to avoid that, aren't we?
Year 2015 Nerv Headquarters - Isolation Facility 4
I still don't handle dark places very well.
All the bad memories come flooding back.
Who is she?
She's the sole survivor of the original expedition.
Year 2002 South Pole Investigation Ship - Isolation Facility 2
Her name is Misato Katsuragi.
She's Dr. Katsuragi's daughter?
Katsuragi?
Yes, she hasn't spoken for almost two years now.
That's terrible.
It attests to the hell that she witnessed.
Her physical injuries have healed, but psychological wounds do not heal so easily.
I suppose so.
Safety First
We can't conclude our findings for our investigation lightly either.
This giant of light... This incident is full of mysteries.
United Nations Moves Headquarters to Japan In Five Years, Candidate is New Tokyo-2 Second Impact Caused by a Massive Meteor Impossible to Predict or Avoid Probability of Once in Every Several Hundred Million Years Official United Nations Statement At 20-30% of the Speed Of Light
Soon after, the United Nations issued an official statement stating that the Second Impact was caused by a massive meteor.
But from where I stood, I could see that the information had been blatantly massaged.
Behind all this was Seele and hints that a man named Kiel was involved.
And it made me want to learn the dark truth of that incident.
Year 2003, Hakone
Even if that might eventually lead me to the name of Yui Ikari.
United Nations Artificial Evolution Laboratory
Director's Office
Why do you hide the existence of the giant of light?!
You guys knew about the Second Impact, didn't you?
That it would happen on that day?
Laboratory Director Gendo Ikari
You said you were lucky enough to get out the day before.
Was it also luck that you took all your research with you?!
I am surprised that this material escaped destruction.
I did a thorough investigation of your assets.
I'm sure raising a child is expensive, but isn't the amount rather large for you to have privately?
You impress me, Professor Fuyutsuki.
Why not transfer to the department of economics?
I'm going to go public about Seele and the Dead Sea Scrolls being secretly behind the Second Impact.
I have no intention of letting the people who caused that get away with it!
Feel free.
But before you do, there is something I would like to show you.
We're going down quite a ways.
Does it worry you?
Somewhat.
What is this?
A cavern left behind by someone, who was not us.
Though eighty-nine percent of it is buried.
An underground cavern that was originally a neat spherical shape...
All the resources mankind has to offer are being poured into that facility.
Oh, Professor Fuyutsuki.
Akagi, you too?
Yes, this is the best place to research the fundamental theories for the bio-computers of the future.
I see.
I intend to name it Magi.
Magi? After the three wise men from the East?
Is this what you wanted to show me?
No, this way, please.
Ritsuko, I'll be right back.
What is this?
Is this that giant?!
Here at Gehirn, we call that giant Adam.
But this is not it.
It is not the original.
Then...
Yes, it is an Eva, made from Adam by man.
An Eva?!
This is the Adam Revival Project, generally known as Project E, and this is our mockup, Eva Unit 00.
A prototype for a god?!
Fuyutsuki, work with me to create a new era in the history of mankind.
HE WAS AWARE THAT HE WAS STILL A CHILD.
Year 2015
Excuse me, Ma'am?
Oh, I'm sorry. Let's hurry up and retest Rei.
I haven't seen Miss Katsuragi around today.
You're right.
Miss Katsuragi?
Right! Misato Katsuragi! Nice to meet you!
Year 2005 New Tokyo-2, Nagano Prefecture 2nd Tokyo University, School Grounds
Mother, I met a girl named Katsuragi the other day.
Other people will only look at me from afar, and each time, I am reminded of the weight your name carries, but this girl has no reservation towards me for some reason.
I am told that she is the sole survivor of that expedition.
She was apparently aphasic for a time, but now, she chatters away a mile a minute as if to make up for lost time.
Ritchan, I am still burrowed underground, the same as always.
I've grown tired of the lunches they provide.
On the surface, they have apparently begun working on the plans for New Tokyo-3 in accordance with the Second Capital Transfer Project.
Lately, Misato hadn't been showing up at the university, and when I finally got her to tell me why, it was so idiotic.
Apparently, she had been sleeping with her boyfriend at her apartment, for an entire week!
I feel like I have seen an unexpected side of her.
She introduced him to me today.
He's good-looking, but I just cannot get to like his frivolous attitude.
As I recall, you have never been good around boys, Ritchan.
In the end, being raised only by a woman...
No, I'm sorry. I have left you to your own devices for so long.
It's awful of me to act like a mother only when it's convenient.
A mother...
Year 2004 Hakone - Underground Laboratory 2
LCL electrified. Pressure at plus zero point two.
No destrudo readings detected in transmissions.
Para-base is stable.
What is this child doing here?
He's Director Ikari's son.
Ikari, this is not a nursery school. Today is a crucial day!
I'm sorry, Professor Fuyutsuki. I'm the one who brought him.
Yui, this is your experiment today.
That's why.
I want to show my child the bright future.
Those were Ms. Yui's final words.
The irregular circumstances erased her from this world.
Exactly as I had wished.
I am such a horrible woman.
Ritchan, Director Ikari changed after that day.
Where have you been for the past week?
You're allowed to grieve, but you need to be aware that you are responsible for more than yourself now.
I know.
Fuyutsuki, I am going to recommend a new project starting today.
I have already proposed it to Chairman Kiel.
You're not going to...
That's right.
The path to godhood that none have ever succeeded in before.
The Human Instrumentality Project.
Year 2008
Mother, congratulations on the completion of the fundamental theory of Magi.
This is not exactly a gift to celebrate it with, but my formal admission into Gehirn has been unofficially approved.
I will be working on Project E starting next month.
Who's there?
Technology Development Department, Ritsuko Akagi.
Here's my ID.
I heard the command center had been completed, so I came to see it, but this place is a maze.
If you want the command center, the Director and Dr. Akagi are there.
Are you really sure?
Yes, I have no regrets concerning my work.
Liar! You just can't forget about Ms. Yui, right?
But I don't mind.
Year 2010 Geofront Artificial Canopy Lower Level 2 Direct Support Area (Future Location)
That's the headquarters for Gehirn.
Good morning, Director.
Did you bring your child today?
Oh, but you have a son, if I'm not mistaken.
This isn't Shinji.
I'm taking care of a friend's daughter.
Her name is Rei Ayanami.
Hello, Rei.
This girl reminds me of someone...
Ms. Yui?
All files concerning Rei Ayanami have been erased already?
It's blank.
What does this mean?
(S.C.
MAGI SYSTEM) Completed
Magi Casper, Magi Balthasar, and Magi Melchior.
The Magi are the three parts that make up who I am.
The scientist in me, the mother in me, and the woman in me.
And those three elements will be in constant conflict with one another.
The three parts of you...
The only thing left is to power it up, right?
I'm going to go home early today.
Misato's coming back.
That's right, I didn't know she was a member of Gehirn.
I believe she's in Germany?
Yes, she's serving in Branch 3.
Then I suppose it's a long-distance relationship.
I heard they broke up.
Oh, and they looked so good together too.
You can never tell with a man and a woman, because it's not logical.
That cool attitude of yours certainly hasn't changed.
You're going to let your own happiness slip away.
Happiness is even harder to define.
Well, it's been a long time since I've gone drinking.
Goodnight.
Did you want something, Rei?
I got lost.
Oh, really? Then you want to leave here with me?
That's okay.
But you won't be able to get home by yourself, right?
That's none of your business, you old hag.
What?
I can go home by myself, so leave me alone, you old hag.
It's not nice to call someone an old hag.
But you are an old hag, aren't you?
I'm going to get mad. You need a good scolding from Director Ikari.
That's what the Director calls you.
That...
He says, "That old hag is pushy," or that he, "doesn't need that old hag anymore.
He doesn't need that old hag anymore.
It's what the Director calls you.
You're nothing but a...
It doesn't matter if you die, you can always be replaced.
Rei...
The same as me.
The Human Instrumentality Project Committee, chaired by Kiel Lorenz, dissolved the research organization, Gehirn, the next day.
And they formed the special duty organization, Nerv, as the organization that would carry out all projects.
All of us were moved directly into Nerv, with the exception of one, Dr. Akagi, the remarkable creator of the Magi System.
Year 2015
Oh, it's you.
Long time no see.
I've put the guards outside to sleep for a while.
This will cost you your life.
I just want to get closer to the truth within myself.
Thank you very much for your cooperation.
Is it over?
Yes, the problem has been resolved, so...
I see.
What about him?
I do not know.
Hey, you're late.
I'm home.
Play Messages
Play
Katsuragi, it's me.
I've probably put you through a lot of trouble by the time you're listening to this.
I'm sorry.
Tell Ritchan I said I'm sorry too.
Also, since I've troubled you so much anyway, there's this flower I've been growing...
It'd make me happy if you'd water it for me.
Shinji knows where it is.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Go forward without any hesitation.
If I ever get to see you again, I'll say the words I wasn't able to say eight years ago.
Bye.
Message recorded at 12:02pm.
Jerk...
You're really such a jerk...
Right then, all I could do was run away from Misato.
There was nothing I could do or say. I was a child.
It made me realize that.
To Be Continued
Preview
Asuka falls into a psychological pitfall due to having lost to Shinji.
Furthermore, the psychological attack from an Angel delivers the finishing blow to Asuka's mind.
Shinji is unable to offer her any words of comfort.
Next time, "At Least, Be Human"
Next Time At Least, Be Human