Mom! Mom! I've been chosen!
I'm an elite pilot, chosen to protect all of mankind!
I'm the best in the world!
It's supposed to be a secret!
But I'll tell you anyway! Just for you!
Everyone will be nice to us from now on!
So, we won't be lonely anymore!
So, we'll be fine, even without Dad around! We won't be lonely anymore!
So, look! Look at me!
Come on, Mom!
I don't want to hear any more of that garbage from you!
You're just stupid anyway, Shinji!
How many times do I have to tell you?! Kaji's gone!
You're lying!
Synch rate, zero...
Not qualified to be the Second Child...
There's no reason for me to exist anymore.
Because no one will look at me now.
Not Dad, not Mom, not anyone.
There's no reason for me to live now.
Asuka Langley Sohryu, correct?
Intelligence Division 2 reports that they have the Second Child safely in their custody.
I see.
It isn't like Division 2 to take seven days to find her on top of losing her in the first place.
It's probably on purpose.
Maybe they're trying to spite us here in the Tactical Division.
Possibly.
And today, Asuka's replacement, the Fifth Child, arrives.
Everything is just too perfect.
Rei Ayanami...
So, that feeling I got really was her.
Like Mother...
Rei Ayanami and Mother...
What are you doing, Father?
Commander Ikari...
The cat died.
The one I'd left in my grandmother's care.
I hadn't paid any attention to her for so long, but now, suddenly, I'll never see her again.
Why did you destroy the dummy system?
Not the dummy system, what I destroyed was Rei.
I will only ask you this once. Why?
Because I am no longer happy, even when you make love to me.
Why don't you just have your way with my body?!
Like you did that time!
I'm disappointed in you.
Disappointed?!
You never hoped or expected anything from me to begin with!
Nothing from me! Not anything! Nothing!
What am I supposed to do, Mother?
I wonder where Asuka is?
But what would be the point in seeing her?
Talk to her about Ayanami or something?
Everyone, including Toji and Kensuke, lost their homes and left.
My friends...
I don't have anyone I can call a friend anymore.
There's no one.
I can't go see Ayanami.
I don't have the courage for it.
I don't know how I'm supposed to face her.
Asuka, Miss Misato, Mother...
What should I...
What should I do?
Singing is great.
Singing enriches the soul.
It's the crowning achievement of the civilization that the Lilim created.
Don't you feel the same?
Shinji Ikari?
My name...
Everyone knows your name.
I don't mean to be rude, but I think you should be a little more aware of your position.
You think so?
Who are you?
I'm Kaworu, Kaworu Nagisa.
One of the children that's part of the design, just like you.
I'm the Fifth Child.
The Fifth Child?
You are? Nagisa?
You can just call me Kaworu, Ikari.
You can call me Shinji too.
It appears the Fifth Child has just arrived.
Kaworu Nagisa, his past records have already been erased.
The same as Rei...
But the one thing we do know is that his birthday coincides with the Second Impact.
The Committee sent him directly to us.
There's bound to be something to this.
In the Marduk Report, the matter of the Fifth Child is also designated as confidential.
So, I did a little hacking into the Intelligence Department's database.
You're so reckless!
It was worth it though.
I found out where Miss Ritsuko's being held.
How do you want to go about the Fifth Child's synch test?
Let's hold off on the trick questions today and get a straight reading on what he's capable of.
Fixing graph depth.
Try lowering it another point three.
Yes, Sir.
Are these data readouts accurate?
All instrumentation is operating normally, Sir.
The Magi have not detected any errors in the data, Sir.
Who would have expected that he would synchronize with Unit 02 without the core being reconfigured?
This boy...
But this is beyond belief!
This should be impossible, given the system.
Nevertheless, these are the facts.
First, accept the facts for what they are, and then investigate the why behind them.
Central Dogma is currently locked down. Please use Route 22 as a detour.
You're the First Child, aren't you?
Rei Ayanami...
You're the same as me.
So, both of us ended up in the same form as the Lilim while we inhabit this planet.
Who are you?
It seems the Fifth Child has made contact with Rei.
I see.
The Magi are currently pouring all their resources into analyzing the data we got from the Fifth Child.
And yet, we still have no idea what he is.
Who in the world is that boy?
Do not enter without permission. I'll kill you if you come without asking!
Shinji still hasn't returned either.
I've failed as a guardian.
Central Dogma is currently open.
Please use Route 3 to transfer.
Hi, were you waiting for me?
No, not really. That's not what I was...
What are you doing today?
Well, the regular tests are over, so all I have left is to take a shower and go home, but...
But the truth is, lately, I don't really want to go home.
A place to return to...
The fact that you have a home will lead to your happiness.
It's a very good thing.
You think so?
I'd like to talk more with you.
May I come with you?
To take a shower. You still need to go take one, right?
Is that a no?
Oh, no, that's not what I meant.
You go to such extremes to avoid first contact.
Are you afraid of connecting with other people?
If you don't get close to others, you'll never be betrayed and you'll never hurt each other.
But you'll also never be able to forget your loneliness.
Humans can never banish their loneliness for good, because being human means being alone.
But humans are able to go on with their lives because they're able to forget it every so often.
It's time.
Is it over already?
Yeah, we better go to bed.
Together?
Oh, no! I think there's probably a room ready for you.
A separate one.
I see.
Humans constantly feel pain in their hearts.
Because the heart is so sensitive to pain, humans also feel that to live is to suffer.
You're so delicate, like glass, especially your heart.
Me?
Yes, you have my regard for it.
Regard?
It means, I love you.
Episode #24' The Final Messenger
THE BEGINNING AND THE END, OR "KNOCKIN' ON HEAVEN'S DOOR"
Nerv, the organization formed to be Seele's executive branch...
It was created in order to put our script into practice.
But now, it has become an organization in the possession of one individual.
Precisely, we must take it back.
Before the promised day.
Nerv and the Eva series must be in their true forms.
Ikari, you will bear the responsibility of your malfeasance towards Seele.
The time that has been given to us runs short.
But the Lance of Longinus that stood in the way of our desire is no more.
Soon, the final Angel will appear.
If we destroy it, our wish will come true.
Just a little longer, Yui.
Why am I here?
Why am I alive again?
For what?
And for whom?
The Fifth Child...
That boy...
I feel as if he's the same as me.
Why?
I'm glad we're on the outskirts of the city, because it kept you safe from all that.
But there's no guarantee that will be the case next time.
So, the Horaki family will be taking care of you starting tomorrow.
This will be goodbye for a while, Pen Pen.
Come on, I'll sleep on the floor.
It's okay.
You're the one who's doing me a favor by letting me stay over.
I'm fine where I am.
What do you want to talk about?
There are things you want me to hear, right?
All sorts of things have happened since I came here.
Before coming here, I used to live with my teacher.
The days were peaceful. Nothing ever happened.
I only had to exist there.
But that was okay, because there was nothing I had to do.
Did you hate people?
Not really, I think it didn't matter, one way or another.
But I did hate my father.
Why am I telling Kaworu all this?
Maybe I was born, so that I would meet you.
Humans cannot create anything out of nothingness.
Humans cannot accomplish anything without holding onto something.
After all, humans are not gods.
But there is one man who is trying to obtain power equal to that of God.
There is a man, who is not one of us, attempting to open Pandora's Box once again.
There is a man trying to close the Box before the Hope at the bottom appears.
Hope?
You're saying that is the Lilim's hope?
Hope exists in as many forms as there are people.
And that is because hope only exists in the hearts of people.
However, our hope is becoming substantiated.
That is Lilith, the progenitor of mankind who are the false successors from the black moon.
And Adam, the progenitor of the Angels who are the true successors from the lost white moon.
His salvaged soul exists only within you.
However, his resurrected body already exists within Ikari.
Shinji's father...
So, he is also the same as me.
That is why we entrust you with our wish.
I know. That's why I'm here now after all.
It's no good. I can't read his lips from here.
But he certainly is a shady character, going out for a walk so early in the morning to talk to himself.
He noticed me?
No, it's not possible.
All will be as the Lilim direct it.
How did it go? Did you get any data on him?
Here it is.
I borrowed it from First Lieutenant Ibuki without her permission.
I'm sorry I keep making you do these theft-like things.
What is this?!
It's no wonder Maya can't release this information.
It's all theoretically impossible data.
You're right. It only deepens the mystery.
To think that he can freely set his synch rate with the Eva...
And of his own will at that.
I guess this is yet again no time to be worried about appearances.
I'm surprised you made it in.
There's something I want to ask you.
All conversations in here are recorded, you know.
I don't care.
Just who is that boy? The Fifth Child?
He is likely the final messenger.
Come on, let's go.
Come with me, Adam's alter ego and servant of the Lilim.
Eva Unit 02 is activating!
That's impossible! Where's Asuka?
In med room 303! It's been confirmed!
Then who in the world is...
It's unmanned! No entry plug is present in Unit 02!
There's no one? It's not the Fifth Child?
A developing AT Field has been detected in Central Dogma!
Is that Unit 02?!
No, its pattern is blue!
There's no doubt about it! It's an Angel!
What did you say?!
An Angel? That boy?
Target has passed through Level 4 and is still descending!
It's no good! We can't cut the power to the linear carriage!
Target has passed through Level 5!
Emergency lockdown! Close all partitions in Central Dogma!
Buy us some time, no matter how little.
Emergency lockdown, all Malebolge levels being closed.
All personnel, evacuate. All personnel, evacuate.
I never imagined Seele would send one directly to us.
The old men intend to step up the schedule by forcing our hand.
Humans forget their foolishness and repeat their mistakes.
If humans do not redeem themselves willingly, they will not change.
We will not rely on the powers of Adam or the Angels.
Our only choice is to make changes with our own hands for the future.
I will be praying that Unit 01 will accomplish its task.
Unit 02 is breaking through the armored partitions!
Target has passed through Cocytus 2!
Send Eva Unit 01 after it.
Yes, Sir.
Stop it from invading Terminal Dogma at all costs.
But why did the Angel take Unit 02?
Could it be planning to merge with Unit 02?
Or possibly to bring about destruction.
It's a lie! A lie! A lie!
That Kaworu is...
He's an Angel?!
That's a lie!
It's a fact. Accept it.
Move out, understood?
Shinji's so late.
Eva Unit 01 heading down Route 2!
In pursuit of target!
You betrayed me! You betrayed my feelings!
You betrayed me, just like Father did!
Unit 01 has reached Level 4.
Coming into contact with the target!
There he is!
I've been waiting for you, Shinji.
Kaworu!
Asuka, sorry!
The Eva series.
Born from Adam, they are an abhorrent existence for humans.
And the Lilim will even use them in order to survive.
I can't understand.
Kaworu, stop this! Why?!
The Eva are made of the same body as I am.
Because I am born from Adam as well.
I could merge with them, if only they didn't have souls.
Unit 02's soul has shut itself away for now.
An AT Field!
That's right. That's what you Lilim call it.
The sacred domain where none may trespass.
The light of the soul.
Lilim, you know, don't you?
That the AT Field is the wall that everyone has in their heart?
I don't know anything about that, Kaworu!
Both Eva units have reached the lowest level.
Target distance to Terminal Dogma, 20.
If Unit 01's signal disappears and another change occurs...
I know. We set this place to self-destruct, right?
It'll be better than letting them set off the Third Impact.
I'm sorry.
It's okay, as long as I'm with you.
Thank you.
The fate of man...
The hope of man is written in sorrow.
What's going on?!
It's an AT Field of unprecedented power!
Light, electromagnetic, and particle waves!
It's blocking them all! We can't monitor anything in there!
We're truly sealed off.
We've lost the target along with Eva Unit 01 and Unit 02!
We can't contact the pilot!
Kaworu!
Wait!
The final safety has been released!
Heaven's Door is opening!
So, an Angel has finally reached it.
Hyuga...
What's that?!
What's the situation?
It's an AT Field!
The same kind of AT Field that we saw earlier has developed near the barrier around Terminal Dogma!
It's entering the barrier!
It can't be! Another Angel?!
It's no good! We can't confirm that!
Oh, no, it disappeared!
Disappeared?! The Angel did?!
Adam, our mother.
Must all who were born of Adam return to Adam?
Even at the cost of destroying humanity?
No! This is...
Lilith?
I see, so that's what this is about, Lilim.
Thank you, Shinji.
I wanted you to stop Unit 02.
Otherwise, I may have gone on living with her.
Kaworu, why?
Because it's my destiny to continue to live even if it may result in the destruction of humanity.
But I can also die here.
Life and death are of equal value to me.
Dying of your own will.
That is the one and only absolute freedom there is.
What?
Kaworu, I don't understand what you're saying!
Kaworu...
My last will and testament.
Now, erase me from this world.
If you don't, you will be the ones who are erased.
Only one life form will be chosen to survive the time of destruction and be given a future.
And you are not a being who should die.
Your people need the future.
Thank you. I'm glad I met you.
Kaworu said that he loved me.
It was...
It was the first time someone told me they loved me.
He was like me, and like Ayanami.
I loved him.
Kaworu was the one who should have survived.
He was a much better person than I am.
Kaworu should have been the one to survive.
You're wrong.
Only those who have the will to live get to survive.
He wished to die.
He abandoned his will to live, clinging instead to a false hope.
You did nothing wrong, Shinji.
You're cold, Miss Misato.
To Be Continued
Preview
Shinji defeated the final angel, but unable to deal with reality, he shuts the world out.
And the promised time comes.
The impending annihilation of Nerv.
Asuka is driven to the brink of death.
The Human Instrumentality Project is about to be activated along with Rei.
Over the heads of the people rebelling against their own reality and feeding their dreams, the Eva series descends as if mocking the deception that is about to be uncovered.
Next time: "Air."
Next time (Air)