Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
15 years ago
2000 AD
Father...
Episode 12:
The Value of
a Miracle is...
Thanks, Shinji, you really saved
us from that rainstorm.
Where’s Misato?
I guess she must still be asleep.
She’s been working all
night recently.
That’s right, she has a tough job.
We’ve got to be quiet.
Don’t wake her up.
What are you doing in here?!
Taking shelter from the rain.
You guys are after me, aren’t you?
Well, I’m changing and if
you peep, I’ll kill you!
Shut up, idiot.
Who would want to see
you changing clothes?
She’s way too self-conscious.
Sorry for disturbing you!
Hi, how’s it going?
Shinji, don’t be late tonight,
we’re having a harmonics test.
Right.
Did you hear that, Asuka?
Yes, ma’am!
Congratulations on your promotion!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
You’re most welcome.
See you later.
See you!
What’s up?  Did something
happen to Misato?
Didn’t you see her badge?
The number of lines
increased to two.
That means that she’s been promoted
from Captain to Major.
Really?  I didn’t notice that.
Yeah, I wonder when...
Are you serious?
What a bunch of dweebs!
Haven’t you got any sympathy?
Don’t you realize how hard it is to
foster two junior high school
students at her age?
It looks like we’re the only ones who
have some human compassion.
Units 00 and 02 are both on the
edge of the contamination zone.
They’ve reached their limit.
Unit 01 can still tolerate a little
more though, can’t he?
Lower the graph depth another 0.3.
He’s almost reached the
contamination zone.
And he’s still getting these readings?
He’s wonderful.
His harmonics and synch ratio are
rapidly catching up with Asuka’s.
It is a talent, isn’t it?
He was born to pilot an Eva,
wasn’t he?
Not that he wants to.
I know he’s not happy.
Test completed.  Good work.
Excellent work, Shinji.
What do you mean?
Your harmonics value has increased
by eight points since the last test.
That’s very good.
But still it’s fifty points
lower than mine!
Yes, but he increased it by eight
points in only ten days.
That’s really something.
It’s not so great!!
Are you happy with your
little praise?
I’m going home now!  Idiot!!
...and here’s a message for
“Mr. Waaa” of Tokyo-2.
Having your girlfriend dump you
isn’t really such a big deal.
Congratulations on your promotion.
Having your girlfriend dump you
isn’t really such a big deal.
Thanks.
When I was a kid, we lived in a dirty
hut, and barely had food to eat.
But, I’m not really all that thrilled.
When I was a kid, we lived in a dirty
hut, and barely had food to eat.
But, I’m not really all that thrilled.
We couldn’t really afford to be
depressed about relationships.
I understand...
We couldn’t really afford to be
depressed about relationships.
I don’t like to be praised either.
We couldn’t really afford to be
depressed about relationships.
All it does is make Asuka angry.
We couldn’t really afford to be
depressed about relationships.
All it does is make Asuka angry.
You should be glad that your parents
are alive and you have food to eat.
I don’t know why she gets so mad.
These are better, peaceful times and
you can have hardships like that.
That bothers you?
These are better, peaceful times and
you can have hardships like that.
That bothers you?
You got that, Mr. Waaa?
Yes.
That’s because you’re always
watching everyone else’s faces.
You got that, Mr. Waaa?
That’s because you’re always
watching everyone else’s faces.
Congratulations!
Thanks, guys!
Thank you, Mister Suzuhara.
No, no.  This wasn’t my brainchild,
it was this guy right here.
That’s right!
It was I, Kensuke Aida!
Kensuke Aida was the planner!
Thank you, Mister Aida.
Oh, you’re welcome!  But it’s not
such a big deal, really.
By the way, why is the
class rep here?
Because I invited her.
Right!
Did you invite Rei too?
Yes, I invited her...
...but that girl is one
strange customer.
Darn, why is Mister Kaji so late?
Oh, Mister Kaji?  Is he that
really cool guy?
Oh, yeah!
He’s so much better than these
dweebs that it’s like night and day.
It’s an insult to compare him to them.
What did you say?
How dare you?
Is it still difficult for you to be here...
So what?  You son of a...
...in this kind of situation?
I’m okay.
I’m just not used to being with...
...so many people.
Why do they have to...
...make so much noise like that?
Your promotion...
That means that someone must have
noticed the kind of work you’ve
been doing, right Misato?
Yeah, I suppose.
That’s why they’re happy.
But you don’t look very happy at all.
Oh, I’m happy.  I am.
But that’s not the reason I work here.
Then why did you join NERV?
Well, I don’t remember.
It’s been a long time since then.
That’s got to be Kaji!
I came directly from headquarters.
We just happened to meet
on the way.
That’s rather suspicious.
Hey, are you jealous?
Absolutely not.
Anyhow, I’d like to give you my
fondest regards, Major Katsuragi.
I suppose I’ll have to be polite
to you from now on.
What are you trying to say?
You jerk!
You know, it’s unprecedented for
both the Commander and the Vice-
Commander to leave Japan together.
I guess they must really count
on ol’ Katsuragi here.
My father’s not here?
Commander Ikari is at the South
Pole at the moment.
Nothing living is allowed to exist
in this world of death we
call Antarctica.
Or should I simply call it Hell?
Nevertheless, we, mankind, are here.
We’re living things, and we’re alive.
That’s because we’re under the
protection of science.
Science is the power of man.
That arrogance is what caused the
tragedy of fifteen years ago,
the Second Impact.
And here is the end result.
This is a greater punishment
than we deserve.
This is the real Dead Sea.
Yet this is a world that has been
purified, purged of the original sin.
I’d rather live in a world where
people can live...
...no matter how stained with sin.
Report from the bridge.
Telegram received from
NERV Headquarters.
An Angel has been detected in orbit
above the Indian Ocean.
The Angel appeared suddenly,
two minutes ago.
Send Search Satellite Number 6
to that orbit.
T-minus 2 minutes to contact.
The target has been sighted.
That’s impressive.
I don’t believe it.
Satellite Number 6 is closing for
contact with the target.
Commence data search.
Data transmission commencing.
Reception confirmed.
Was that an AT Field?
It’s a new way of using it.
What incredible destructive power.
That’s an AT Field!
It uses kinetic energy, too.
This Angel is, itself,
like a huge bomb.
In any case, the first blast missed its
target and hit the Pacific Ocean.
Two hours later, the second
shot struck there.
Since then, it has been steadily
correcting the error ratio.
That means it’s learning, huh?
An N2 air bomb had no effect on it.
The Angel has been missing
since then.
It’s probably coming here.
Yes, and next time it may drop itself.
So, that will give us a third
Ashinoko lake?
All five of the Fuji lakes will be
fused into a single body linked
to the Pacific Ocean...
...destroying this headquarters
in the process.
Can we reach the Commander?
It’s impossible due to the Angel’s
powerful jamming.
What is the MAGI’s judgment?
They unanimously agree in
recommending evacuation.
What will you do?
You’re the one who’s in charge
of all this now.
Notify all of the ministries concerned
of the following D-17 Special
Declaration...
...as provided for under
NERV’s authority.
All residents within a radius of 50 km
are to evacuate immediately.
Also, ask Matsushiro to
back up the MAGI.
Are we going to evacuate as well?
No...
...but it’s not necessary to place
everyone at risk.
A D-17 Special Declaration has been
announced by the government.
All residents must evacuate to their
designated locations.
Beginning with the 6th
and 7th blocks...
...move according to your district
chief’s direction immediately.
The evacuation of the
city is complete.
The evacuation of all noncombatant
and D Class personnel by Alarm C
has been completed.
Are you serious?
Yes, I am.
Are you going to waste all three
Evas with your irresponsible
selfishness?
The chance of success is
only 0.00001%!
That’s not even one in ten thousand!
It’s not zero.  I just trust the Evas.
Major Katsuragi!
I’m in charge.
I have to do what I have to do.
And destroying Angels is my duty.
Your duty?
You must be kidding!
This is for your own sake, isn’t it?
This is just your revenge
against the Angels!
Catch it in our hands?
That’s right.  We’ll position the Evas
in the estimated drop zone.
Then you’ll catch it while
maintaining your AT Fields
at full strength.
What if the Angel doesn’t come
down exactly where you
expect it to?
We’ll be a little put out.
What if the Evas aren’t able to
withstand the shock?
We’ll be put out in that case, too.
What’s our probability of success?
God only knows.
I have no idea.
If we succeed, it’ll be a miracle.
It’s not until we’ve done everything
we can to cause a miracle that it
becomes viable.
You mean, we’ve got to be willing to
sacrifice ourselves?
I’m sorry, but we have no other
options for this operation.
An operation?  How can you call
something this crazy an operation?!!
No, you can’t really call it that.
You can refuse to do it, if you wish.
So, are you okay with this?
Regulations say you’re all supposed
to write a will.  Have you done that?
I don’t need to.  I’m not going
to die just yet.
Neither do I.  There is no use for it.
Not me, either.
Again, I’m sorry.
But once we complete this operation,
I’ll treat all of you to a steak dinner.
Really?
I promise.
Yeah!!
Don’t forget!
You can count on it.
I guess she thinks a steak dinner is
supposed to impress us.
Does she really think a steak dinner
will impress us?
The Second Impact generation has
really cheap standards.
She can’t help it.
What was with that fake
cheer you made?
I just wanted to make her feel
a little easier about it.
Now, since she’s going to treat us...
...I’d better figure out where to go.
You’ve got to join us this time.
No, I won’t.
Why not?
I dislike meat.
Because of the Angel’s ECM,
we’ve lost track of it.
Since it’s impossible to calculate the
collision point exactly...
...the MAGI’s estimated a drop zone
based on the data that had been
collected before it was lost.
This is it.
The range is this wide?
The distance from one side to
the other is enormous.
Given the size of the target’s
AT Field...
...it could completely annihilate
headquarters by dropping on
any of these locations.
Given that, we’ll disperse the Evas
so that there’s one at each of
these three points.
And on what grounds is this
dispersal based?
Intuition.
Intuition?
Yes, a woman’s intuition.
How sloppy!  Our miracle is getting
farther and farther away.
Misato has never won the lottery.
Say...
What?
Asuka, why do you pilot an Eva?
To exhibit my talent to
the world, of course.
You mean to prove that you exist?
Yeah, more or less.
You’re not going to ask her?
I’ve asked Ayanami before.
My, how intimate the two of you are.
It’s not like that.
Now, what about you, Shinji?
I don’t know.
You don’t know?
What are you?  Stupid?
Maybe I am.
I suppose you really are.
20 minutes to estimated
time of impact.
You must all evacuate now.
I can take care of this myself.
No, this is our job as well.
That’s right.  We can’t let the kids
risk their lives by themselves.
They’ll be fine.
No matter how badly the Evas might
be damaged, their AT Fields
will protect them.
Inside an Eva is the safest
place to be.
Shinji, yesterday you asked me
why I joined NERV.
My father was a man who
lived for his research...
...for his dreams...
to the exclusion of all else.
I could never forgive him for that.
In fact, I even hated him.
Just like my father.
He never took care of me,
my mother or the family.
His friends always said he was
very sensitive and delicate.
But the truth was that he was
just a weak person...
...who didn’t want to face reality,
the reality called his family.
He was like a kid...
...so I agreed with my mother when
she decided to divorce him...
...because she was always crying.
He was depressed about it...
...but I laughed at him because he
deserved what he got.
But he sacrificed himself...
...to save my life during
the Second Impact.
Then I didn’t know whether
I hated him or loved him.
The only thing that was clear to me...
...was that I wanted to destroy the
Angels who had caused
the Second Impact.
So, in order to do that,
I joined NERV.
It might be that I still hate him and I
just want to avenge my father...
...so that I can free myself of him.
I musn’t run away.
Right!
I must NOT run away.
The target has been sighted at
maximum magnification.
Distance is approximately 25,000.
Here it is.
All Evas, start your engines.
We can only give you a rough
estimated trajectory based upon
optical observations.
So, the MAGI will guide you until
the estimated distance is
10,000 meters.
After that, you’ll have to use
your own judgment.
I’m placing my trust in you.
The Angel is approaching,
distance 20,000.
Commence operation.
Here we go!
Start!
Distance 12,000!!
AT Field full spread!
Unit 02!  Spread your field!
I’m doing it!!
Do it now!
Our wireless communications
have been restored.
We’re receiving a transmission from
Commander Ikari in Antarctica.
Connect him here.
Yes, ma’am.
I’m very sorry, sir.
Because of my irresponsible
judgment, I have caused Unit 01
to incur some damage.
It was completely my fault.
That is not a problem.  Destroying
Angels is the Evas’ purpose.
It was fortunate that the amount
of damage was minimal.
Excellent work, Major Katsuragi.
Thank you, sir.
And on that subject, is the pilot
of Unit 01 there?
Y...yes!
I’ve received the report.
Good work, Shinji.
R...right!
Now, Major Katsuragi, I’ll leave
the handling of the rest of
this in your hands.
Yes, sir.
Next station is New Miyanoshita,
New Miyanoshita.
The exit will switch to the left
side at the next station.
Now, you’re going to have to
fulfill your promise.
Of course...
I’ve withdrawn some large bills from
the bank so I can even pay for a
full course French dinner.
Although, before payday
comes along again...
Take it easy, we know how
poor you are.
This’ll be fine.
And even Wonder Girl says she’ll
join us for ramen noodles.
I’ll have a garlic ramen with
no roast pork.
I’ll have shark’s fin soup ramen
with roast pork.  Large!
There you go!!
Say, Misato...
What?
When I heard my father’s
words today...
...I think I finally understood...
...the good part of being
praised by someone.
And I also realized...
...that the reason I pilot my Eva is to
hear those words from him.
That’s why you’re a pilot?
You really are an idiot.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
The MAGI are a trio of
supercomputers that command
all of NERV Headquarters.
They’re usually inspected by
Technical Division 1 following each
simulated plug activation.
But then trouble occurs and all of
the underground facilities and even
Central Dogma itself are invaded.
Finally, NERV is forced to accept a
course of self-destruction.
It’s the next episode,
“Angel Invasion.”
And expect service and
more fan service!
Next Episode:
Angel Invasion