Like a cruel angel
Become a legend, young boy
When a blue wind
Knocks on the door to your heart
You just gaze back at me
And smile oh so gently
So eager for something
You touch so softly
Those innocent eyes
Know nothing of the fate that awaits
But one day, you will realize
That upon your back
You have wings
You can fly to the faraway future
The cruel angel's thesis
One day, you'll take off through a window
If your overflowing pathos
Leads you to betray your memories
Then embrace the heavens and shine bright
Become legend, young boy
Apoptosis process on three Evas
will begin as scheduled
following Magi system restart.
Confirming process.
Abbreviate steps 450 to 670.
Command Center, approved.
You're very fast, Maya. I'm amazed.
I should be.
I learned from the best, Senpai.
Hold on. An A-8 would be faster there.
Let me drive.
That's my Senpai...
How's it coming? You done with
the Magis' diagnostic testing?
Just about. As promised,
they'll be ready before today's testing.
That's my Ritsuko! Checking over three
identical systems is a tall order!
That coffee is cold.
ROUTINE DIAGNOSTIC
All three Magi system units
have entered self-diagnostic mode.
Routine diagnostic no. 127
shows all systems green.
Roger. Good work, everyone.
Get some rest until the testing starts.
All systems green, huh?
Mother is as healthy as ever,
while I get older with each passing day.
We have to undress again?
Yes, you'll be going into
a super-clean room.
A shower and change of underwear
won't cut it.
Why do we have to go through all this
just to test some autopilot system?
Time isn't the only thing that marches on.
So does the Evas' technology.
We constantly need
new data to work off of.
There! Here we are,
exactly how you want us.
Squeaky clean
after 17 thorough scrubbings.
Okay, I need the three of you
to remain undressed.
Go through this room
and get into your entry plugs.
Don't worry, the visual feed is off.
We'll respect your privacy.
That's not the point, and you know it!
I'm seriously uncomfortable here!
The aim of this test is to gauge how well
harmonics are picked up from your bodies
without the aid of plug suits.
Asuka, that's an order.
Oh, fine! But don't you dare peek!
All pilots ready for entry sequence.
Start test.
Starting test.
Now commencing autopilot recording.
Inserting simulation plugs.
Connecting systems to imitation bodies.
Simulation entry plugs
now under Magi control.
Wow, look at it go!
The Magi sure make a big difference.
This is a far cry from those first tests
that took a whole week!
Test scheduled to end
in approximately three hours.
-How do you feel?
-Something is different.
Yeah, it's not the same as usual.
My senses are all messed up.
I can feel my right arm just fine,
but everything else feels hazy.
Rei, mentally picture
your right arm moving.
Yes, ma'am.
Data collection proceeding smoothly.
Everything seems to be fine.
Return the Magi to normal mode.
An inner conflict...
It really shows the personality
of the person who built it.
What are you talking about?
I thought you built them.
You don't know much
about the Magi, do you?
That's your fault for not talking about
yourself as much as I do, Ritsuko.
I suppose it is.
I only got the system up and running.
The one who came up with the core theories
and built it was my mother.
-You've verified this?
-Yes, just to be sure.
This is a part we got in three days ago.
Here, this is the area
that's deteriorating.
Protein wall no. 87, eh?
Under magnification, you can see
what appears to be stains.
What do you suppose it is?
It must be corrosion. There are minute
temperature and conductivity fluctuations.
There's been a lot of cases of
clean room deterioration lately.
The construction schedule was
shortened by 60 days or so,
so some air bubbles
must have gotten mixed in again.
The construction in Wing B
is awfully slipshod.
That wing was built
after the Angels showed up.
I can't say I'm surprised.
Everybody is exhausted.
Address the issue by tomorrow.
Ikari will raise a stink otherwise.
Yes, sir.
Another water leak?
No, they say there's corrosion.
In the protein wall above us.
Oh, terrific. Has it affected the test?
Not so far, ma'am.
Continue, then. We can't abort this test
midway without good reason.
-Cdr. Ikari would raise a stink.
-Roger.
Synchronization position nominal.
Connecting simulation plug to Eva
primary body via imitation body.
Connection to Eva-00, confirmed.
Projecting A.T. Field
at strength of 2 yoctos.
What happened?!
Contamination alert, Sigma Unit, Floor A!
Protein wall no. 87 has degraded!
Emitting heat!
Abnormalities also detected in tube no. 6!
The corrosion is expanding
along the protein wall!
It's like spreading wildfire!
Abort experiment!
Emergency seal, tube no. 6!
Yes, ma'am!
Sixty, 38, and 39 have been sealed!
Corrosion in segment 42 of tube no. 6!
It's not working! The corrosion is
spreading along the walls and lining!
Ready polysomes!
Set lasers to maximum!
Fire at first sign of intrusion!
Corrosion has reached segment 58
of tube no. 6! Here it comes!
Rei!
Rei's imitation body is moving!
That's impossible!
The corrosion is spreading even further!
It's attacking the imitation body's
pituitary system!
-Rei's status?
-Unharmed!
Emergency eject all plugs!
Have those lasers ready!
-An A.T. Field?!
-That can't be!
What... the hell?
Analysis pattern, blue.
No doubt about it... it's an Angel!
An Angel?!
You let an Angel infiltrate HQ?!
I'm sorry, sir.
Spare me the excuses.
Physically isolate Central Dogma!
Quarantine it from the Sigma Unit!
Physically isolating Central Dogma.
Sigma Unit will be...
We're abandoning the Box!
All personnel, evacuate!
What are you doing?! Hurry!
Isolating Sigma Unit from Floor D.
All bulkheads closing.
All personnel within
affected areas must evacuate.
Yes, I'm aware. I'll leave it to you.
Turn off that alarm.
D-Disabling alarm!
It was a false alarm.
Due to a faulty sensor.
That is what you will tell
the government and Council.
Yes, sir.
Polluted area spreading downwards.
It's spreading out from the Pribnow Box
to the entirety of the Sigma Unit!
-That's a dangerous spot.
-Yes, it's too close to Adam.
Contain the spread
to within the Sigma Unit!
If need be,
sacrifice the Geo-front to do it.
The Evas?
Standing by at Cage Seven. We can launch
once the pilots are retrieved.
Don't bother waiting for the pilots.
Launch them to the surface immediately.
Unit 01 has top priority. Sacrifice
the other two units to do so if necessary.
Unit 01, sir?
But, sir, without the Evas,
we can't physically destroy that Angel.
If the Evas are contaminated
before then, all is lost. Do it!
Yes, sir!
All areas of the Central Dogma
below the Sigma Unit
will be completely locked down
in 60 seconds.
So that's the Angel, huh?
I guess my work is on hold for a while.
Central Dogma now completely locked down.
Deep underground facility
has been overrun by the intruder.
Now, then, how do we attack
this Angel without any Evas?
Look, there's the heavy water boundary.
That's a high-oxygen area.
It has a definite preference.
The area where ozone is pumped in
to maintain aseptic conditions
is free of contamination.
So it's vulnerable to oxygen?
It would seem so.
Now pumping in ozone.
Concentration is increasing.
I think it's working!
Will this do it?
Zero-A and Zero-B appear to be recovering.
Tube area has returned to normal values.
That core area is pretty resilient.
All right, increase ozone levels.
That's strange.
Huh? It's spreading...
This is weird. Heat release is increasing!
Contaminated area is spreading again!
The ozone has lost all effect!
It's now steadily ingesting the ozone!
Halt ozone flow!
Amazing...
It's evolving before our eyes.
What's wrong?!
Subcomputer is being hacked into!
Intruder identity unknown!
No, not now!
Crap! Using Mode C as a countermeasure!
Lowering firewall!
Deploying decoy interface.
Decoy interface circumvented!
-Eighteen seconds to trace!
-Firewall up!
Firewall has been penetrated!
Deploying another decoy interface!
No human could do this...
Trace successful!
It's coming from inside this facility!
Origin, beneath B Wing...
It's the Pribnow Box!
Optical pattern is changing!
The glowing lines are electrical circuits.
This thing is a literal computer!
Deploying decoy interface.
Failed! Attempt prevented!
Physically sever the main cable.
Negative! Not responding to command!
Shoot it with the lasers!
It's generating an A.T. Field!
Ineffective!
It's accessing Security's main banks.
Now brute-forcing the password.
Twelfth digit... Sixteenth digit...
D-word discovered!
Security Department's main banks
have been compromised!
It's accessing the main bank!
I can't cancel it!
What's it after?
It's searching through the main path...
Wait, that's the code for... Oh, no!
It's trying to crack the Magi!
Crash the I/O system.
Go on your mark!
Three! Two! One!
Power won't shut down!
Angel intrusion continuing!
It's accessed Melchior!
I can't stop it!
It's being taken over by the Angel!
Melchior has been
reprogrammed by the Angel!
Artificial intelligence Melchior has
proposed autonomous self-destruct.
Rejected.
Melchior is now proceeding
to hack into Balthasar!
Damn, it's fast!
Its computational speed is crazy!
Change logic mode!
Set synch code to 15-second intervals!
Roger!
How much time did that buy us?
Judging from its prior speed,
about two hours.
To think that the Magi
have turned against us...
We speculate that this Angel is composed
of nano-machines the size of microbes.
These gathered to form a colony
and rapidly evolved to the point
where it formed AI circuitry
in a very short time.
-Evolution?
-Yes, sir.
They are constantly evolving themselves
to work out the ideal system
to cope with any given situation.
A perfect example of the system
that life employs to survive.
The only effective method against a target
that corrects its weaknesses
and constantly evolves
is mutual destruction.
Our only choice is
a Magi-Angel double suicide.
I propose the physical elimination
of the Magi system.
Unthinkable. Scuttling the Magi
is tantamount to sacrificing HQ.
Then I formally request it
as Chief of Operations!
Request denied. This is a job
for the Technology Department.
Why are you being so stubborn?!
Because it was my negligence
that caused this.
You've been this way
as long as I've known you.
Always shouldering the burden by yourself.
You never ask for help, do you?
If the Angel is continuously evolving,
it means we have a chance.
-Encourage its evolution, you mean?
-Yes, sir.
The ultimate end of evolution
is self-destruction. Death itself.
So the solution is to
accelerate its evolution?
If the Angel decides it is the most
efficient way to avoid death,
then it may opt for
coexistence with the Magi.
But how do we do that?
If the target is the computer itself,
we connect Casper directly to the Angel.
We can then reverse-hack it and plant
a self-destruct acceleration program.
But...
It would also mean lowering
its firewall against the Angel.
Is Casper faster, or is the Angel?
-It will be a race.
-Yes, sir.
I assume you'll have
the program ready in time?
Because if Casper is also turned,
it's all over.
I keep my promises.
Alarm Code R is in effect.
An emergency situation
has occurred inside Nerv HQ.
All Class D personnel, please evacuate.
What on earth are all these?
Notes left by the developer.
Wow! It's a backdoor code!
This is the Magis' backdoor code!
So it's a treasure trove of Magi hacks?
Am I cleared to see this stuff?
Wow, I never thought of that!
This is c-as-integer!
This will let us knock out that program
in no time! Right, Senpai?
Thank you, Mother.
We'll be ready in time for sure now.
Hand me that socket wrench.
This reminds me of our college days.
Hand me that no. 25 keyboard.
Hey, tell me a little about the Magi.
It's a long story.
And not a very interesting one.
Have you heard of
the Personality Transplant OS?
Yeah, it's that system where a person's
personality is transferred into
a seventh-gen organic computer
to let it actually think.
That's the same technology
used for piloting the Evas, right?
Supposedly, the Magi were
the first real-world use.
The tech was developed... by my mother.
Wait, your mother's personality
was transplanted into them?
Yes.
In a manner of speaking,
we're looking at my mother's brain.
Is that why you wanted
to protect the Magi?
No, I don't think so.
I didn't like my mother enough to do that.
It was a decision made
as a scientist, I suppose.
That's it!
Balthasar has been taken over!
AIs are voting in favor of
autonomous self-destruct.
-It's started?!
-In event of unanimous decision,
self-destruct will occur
.02 seconds later.
Self-destruct area will encompass
geoid depth -280, -140, and Floor Zero.
Due to Exception 582 being in effect...
Balthasar is hacking further into Casper!
-We're losing ground!
-Its speed is crazy!
Self-destruct device
will activate in 20 seconds.
Oh, no!
Casper will be taken over in 18 seconds!
Self-destruct device
will activate in 15 seconds.
Ritsuko! Hurry!
Don't worry. We have almost
a whole second to spare.
A second?!
That's not zero or a negative.
-Maya.
-Ready here!
Four seconds. Three seconds.
Hit it!
One second. Zero seconds.
REJECTED
Autonomous self-destruct
has been canceled by AIs.
-We did it!
-Yeah!
Furthermore, Exception 582
has also been lifted.
Magi system returning
to normal operating mode.
R-Alert lifted. R-Alert lifted.
All personnel,
stand down to condition one...
What's been going on out there?
Damn it! We can't leave these
stupid things if we're naked!
Somebody come and help!
Sigma Unit now open. Magi system
will restart in minus zero three.
Maybe I am getting old.
All-nighters do a number on me.
You kept your word yet again. Great work.
Thanks.
Misato, I can't ever remember when
your horrid coffee tasted so wonderful.
The night before she died,
Mother said something to me.
That the Magi were
three facets of herself.
The scientist in her. The mother in her.
The woman in her.
The Magi are those three sides of her,
constantly vying for control.
She deliberately incorporated
the inner conflict we all have.
Actually, the three have
slightly different programming.
I could never be a mother,
so I'll never understand that side of her.
As a scientist, though,
I had a great deal of respect for her.
But as a woman,
there was a part of me that hated her.
-You sure are talkative today.
-It's been known to happen.
Casper was implanted with my mother's
personality traits as a woman.
The woman in her held on
to the bitter end.
That's so like her.
TO BE CONTINUED
NEXT EPISODE
Seele, the cabal which secretly controls
Nerv and the Human
Instrumentality Project.
Are Cdr. Ikari's actions merely
the realization of the Dead Sea Scrolls?
Next episode!
"Seele, the Seat of the Soul"!
Tune in next time
for lots more fan service!
Translator: Dan Kanemitsu
Subtitle Editor: David Fleming