Like a cruel angel
Become a legend, young boy
When a blue wind
Knocks on the door to your heart
You just gaze back at me
And smile oh so gently
So eager for something
You touch so softly
Those innocent eyes
Know nothing of the fate that awaits
But one day, you will realize
That upon your back
You have wings
You can fly to the faraway future
The cruel angel's thesis
One day, you'll take off through a window
If your overflowing pathos
Leads you to betray your memories
Then embrace the heavens and shine bright
Become legend, young boy
Yes. That issue has already been
worked out with the Council.
The package left Sasebo yesterday
and is currently on the Pacific.
An Mi-55d transport chopper!
I never thought I'd get the chance
to actually ride in one!
Like they say, "Good friends are
a great blessing"! Right, Shinji?
You must be going stir crazy,
being stuck in the mountains every day.
So I thought I'd invite you
all out on a Sunday date.
You mean this is an honest
to goodness date, Ms. Misato?
I bought this hat on the off chance
that this day would come, Ms. Misato!
So, where are we going?
To enjoy a lovely cruise
on the Pacific aboard a luxury liner.
Five carriers!
Four battleships! It's a huge fleet!
Yep, good friends are a great blessing!
She calls that a luxury liner?
What it is is gorgeous!
That's the carrier that's the pride
of the UN fleet, the Over the Rainbow!
It's huge!
I'm amazed that
that old relic can stay afloat.
It's no relic!
It's a pre-Second Impact classic!
The nerve of these jackasses!
Their toy needed a special plug,
so they had one delivered!
It's some damn errand boys!
Oh, cool!
This is just too cool!
It's enough to bring tears
to a man's eyes!
Oh, cool!
Hey! Come back here!
Damn it! Stop! Hold it!
Hello, Misato. How have you been?
Not bad. Hey, have you grown in height?
Yep. And I'm filling out
in all the right places, too.
Allow me to introduce the Second Children,
Evangelion Unit 02's designated pilot.
Asuka Langley Soryu.
What the hell was that for?!
Admission for the show.
I'd call that a bargain.
Say what?!
Okay then, I'll return the favor!
What do you think you're doing?!
So, which one is the Third Children
that I keep hearing about?
Don't tell me it's this sleazebag!
No. This is him.
Doesn't seem like much.
Ah, I assumed you were a tour guide
who was escorting some Boy Scouts.
But it seems I was wrong.
I apologize for the misunderstanding.
Thank you for being
so understanding, Captain.
Not at all.
I haven't had the pleasure of looking
after someone else's children in ages.
Thank you for your cooperation
in transporting Eva-02.
Here are the specifications
for the emergency electrical plug.
Humph. I never received
any official request to allow
that doll run around here at sea.
Perhaps you could think of it as
a precaution in case of emergency.
The Pacific Fleet is escorting it
in the event of that emergency.
When did the UN Forces
become a delivery service?
As I recall, it was just after
a certain agency was founded, sir.
This is quite an escort
to deliver a single toy.
The entire Pacific Fleet is here.
Given the importance of the Evangelions,
I'd say this isn't enough.
-Now, if you'll sign this form.
-Not yet.
Eva-02 and its pilot were entrusted
to this fleet by Germany's Third Branch.
I won't stand for you bossing me around!
When will you relinquish them, then?
After they have been unloaded
at New Yokosuka.
The high seas are our jurisdiction.
You will do as you're told here.
Very well.
But remember that in an emergency,
Nerv's authority supersedes yours.
-What a badass!
-She's acting like Ms. Ritsuko...
Dignified as ever, I see.
Kaji-senpai!
Hello.
Kaji! I don't recall inviting you
up to the bridge!
My apologies.
-If you'll excuse us.
-This is a date?
-Please see us to New Yokosuka.
-This is too cool!
Shit! A bunch of kids
are supposed to save the world?
Times have changed, sir.
I hear that Congress has high hopes
for those robots as well.
For those toys? Those damn fools!
If they have that kind of cash,
it would be better spent on us!
What the hell are you doing here?!
I'm her plus-one. Germany sent me along.
How could I have missed this?
This situation was entirely plausible!
Hey! Watch the hands!
I can't help it!
Flight Three has launched on schedule...
So... You seeing anyone?
And just how is that any of your business?
Ouch! Why the cold shoulder?
So, I hear you're living with Katsuragi?
Um, that's right.
She used to flop around in her sleep.
She still do that?
Wha-- Wha--
What are you talking about?!
I take it she hasn't changed,
has she, Shinji Ikari?
Um, no. Hey, how did you know my name?
Why wouldn't I?
In our world, you're a celebrity.
The Third Children, the boy who piloted
an Eva without any prior training.
Come on, that was just luck.
Luck is part of destiny.
You have a gift, pure and simple.
-Well, I'll see you later.
-Yes, sir.
This is a sick joke... A nightmare.
So, what do you think of Shinji Ikari?
He's a letdown.
A guy like him, picked to be
the Third Children? I'm disillusioned.
He got tossed unprepared into a fight,
but his synch rate easily topped 40.
No way!
Man, that captain
was a real piece of work!
He's a proud man.
Anyone would make a snide
remark or two in his situation.
Mr. Kaji sure seems like
a fun and interesting person.
He hasn't changed one bit,
that damn moron!
Third Children!
Come with me for a minute.
Wow, Unit 02 is red. I had no idea.
It's not just the paint job
that makes it special.
Units 00 and 01 are really just
a developmental-use
prototype and test type.
The fact that you could synch with yours
without any training proves it.
But Unit 02 here is different!
Mine was built for combat operations,
the world's first real Evangelion!
It's the official type!
What was that?
An underwater shock wave!
That blast was nearby.
Is there...
-Oh, no! An Angel?!
-That's an actual Angel?
What do we do? We have to go
back to where Ms. Misato is!
Here's my chance!
All ships, take evasive action!
Mind your distance!
Where's that sit-rep?!
Cymbeline is dead in the water!
Titus Andronicus cannot locate target!
Damn it, what's going on out there?
Hello! Nerv here!
Would you like Intel on this unseen enemy
and how to effectively deal with it?
We're in combat!
Bystanders aren't allowed on the bridge!
This is just my personal opinion, but this
certainly looks like an Angel attack.
-All ships, engage target at will!
-You're wasting your time...
It's not enough to punch
through an A.T. Field, huh?
But why would an Angel come here?
Is it after Unit 02?!
Hey! Where are we going?!
Wait up here. I'll be right back.
Why is she so bossy?
Don't peek, you pervert!
Why are guys always so stupid and horny?!
Okay, Asuka... it's game time.
Why can't we sink it?!
I guess only an Eva can beat those things.
Okay, let's get out there.
You, too! You're coming with me!
Hey, why did we get changed
into plug suits?!
Are you an idiot?
Why do you think? We're going to
take that thing out with my Unit 02!
Is that okay? Shouldn't we get
Ms. Misato's permission?
I'll get her permission after my victory.
Okay, I'm going to show you
how a real pilot does it.
But don't cause any trouble, got it?
That's strange... It's almost
like it's looking for something.
Getting attacked by an Angel out here
wasn't part of the deal.
That is why Unit 02 is there.
I even sent a backup pilot.
If it comes down to it,
escape on your own.
Understood.
[speaking German]
There's a bug. What's wrong?
Cognitive noise!
I told you not to cause trouble, didn't I?
What did I do?
You're thinking in Japanese, aren't you?
Think in German, damn it!
Oh, okay...
Um, Baumkuchen--
Idiot! All right, fine!
Change cognitive linguistics!
Set basic to Japanese!
Evangelion Unit 02! Activate!
Message from the Othello:
Eva-02 is activating!
It's what?!
Way to go, Asuka!
Don't! Abort activation! Power it down!
Forget him, Asuka! Launch!
How dare you!
We have jurisdiction over the Eva
and its pilot! You will do as you're told!
Are you kidding?! This is an emergency!
Protocol can take a hike!
Hey!
Is she serious?
Unit 02 is still in its Type B loadout.
Won't we be in trouble
if we fall into the ocean?
So we don't fall in.
-You're in there too, Shinji?!
-Yes, ma'am.
There are two kids in there?!
May as well test it out...
Asuka! Launch now!
-Here it comes!
-We're on our way!
-Where is it?
-Over there!
-We only have 58 seconds!
-I know that!
Misato, have the emergency
power cable waiting on the deck!
-You got it!
-What's she trying to do?
-Right. Time to fly.
-Fly?
-Auxiliary power online!
-Direct feed to reactor established!
-Clear the flight deck!
-Ready for Eva landing!
-All hands, brace for impact!
-They're all lunatics!
Eva-02, coming in for landing!
What a waste...
Target closing in fast!
Here it comes! To port, nine o'clock!
Switching to external power!
Switchover complete!
-We don't have any weapons...
-A Prog Knife is all I need!
-That's thing's pretty big...
-Just like I hoped it would be!
What are they planning to do?
Close-quarters combat is
the best way to defeat an Angel.
Way to stop that thing, Asuka!
You've got to be kidding!
They're trashing my flight deck!
They fell in!
Asuka, you can't fight underwater
in that Type B configuration!
You never know until you try, right?
-What a horrible waste...
-Remaining cable length?
Down to 1,200!
-What are you going to do?
-They'll come up with something.
We have to come up with something!
You're almost out of cable!
Brace for impact!
Damn it!
Eva has lost the target!
How can I run out of disks
at a time like this?!
A Yak-38i!
-Hey there, Katsuragi!
-Kaji!
I have a delivery to make,
so I'll see you there.
Take us up.
Take care of things here, Capt. Katsuragi!
H-He bailed on us!
Target re-approaching the Eva!
Here it comes again!
I'll nail it for sure this time!
What the hell?! It's not moving!
We can't in Type B gear.
-What are we gonna do?
-You're asking me?
What a wimp! Aren't you supposed
to be the great Third Children?!
Here it comes!
A mouth?!
Yeah, it's an Angel...
Eva-02 has entered the target!
You mean they got eaten?
Man, it's like we're fishing!
Fishing? Yes! We'll go fishing!
-Out of the fire, back to the frying pan.
-Oh, who asked you?!
And get off me, you pervert!
But we have to break free somehow!
Asuka? Do you read me?
Whatever you do, don't let go!
-Captain.
-What?
I need your assistance.
Having my two surviving battleships
fire at point-blank range?!
Yes.
We scuttle the two evacuated battleships
along the umbilical cable to set the trap.
As they are sinking,
Eva-02 will pry open the target's mouth.
Both ships will enter it.
Then, after firing at point-blank range,
they will self-destruct,
thereby destroying the target.
That's insane!
This plan may be insane,
but I don't think it's impossible.
Very well.
All hands, abandon ship!
I say again, all hands, abandon ship!
All frigates, move in to rescue the crew!
But what about the Eva?
Don't worry. Those two will be fine.
Hey! Stop manhandling my Unit 02!
Okay, you two! Are you clear on the plan?
-We'll make it work somehow.
-We're counting on you!
Ships' Kingston valves have been pulled.
Now sinking towards Z-point.
Roger. Reel in the cable!
Eva starting to ascend! Contact in 70!
Damn it, stop messing with
the controls! Move aside!
But if we don't pry its mouth open,
we're gonna get blown up with it!
Contact in 60!
-The Angel's mouth?!
-Still closed!
Both battleships are sinking
towards the target.
Eva still ascending! Contact in 50!
-It's not working!
-We're almost out of time!
Target has passed beneath the Tempest!
There's not much time! Hurry!
-Don't get any funny ideas in your head.
-As if!
-Anyway, just concentrate!
-I know!
Contact in 20!
Contact in 15!
Open!
Open fire!
NEW YOKOSUKA (FORMERLY ODAWARA)
You made another mess, I see.
I really should have factored in
underwater combat.
That's unusual. Is that regret?
It's all good. At least we got
some valuable data out of it.
That's true.
Misato?
This really is valuable.
-M-Matching outfits!
-Rubs me the wrong way!
This is a new synchronization record!
It was just for seven seconds, so it was
probably just a rush of adrenaline.
Hey! Where's Mr. Kaji?
He ran off without us!
He's at HQ already, that jerk!
I must say, that was
quite the eventful voyage.
It was because of this, wasn't it?
Look at how far it's reconstituted itself.
It's encased in solidified Bakelite,
but it's alive. Without a doubt.
It's the key to the Human
Instrumentality Project.
Yes. This is the first human being.
This is Adam.
She might have been cute,
but, man, what a shrew!
Well, we'll never see her again.
But you're stuck with her
because of your job, big guy.
You have our sympathies, seriously.
I'm Asuka Langley Soryu. Nice to meet you.
TO BE CONTINUED
NEXT EPISODE
Unable to work as a team,
Shinji and Asuka get thrashed by an Angel.
Misato devises a plan to help them
achieve perfect unison.
Next episode! "Mind, Matching, Moment"!
Tune in next time
for lots more fan service!
Translator: Dan Kanemitsu
Subtitle Editor: David Fleming