Like a cruel angel
Become a legend, young boy
When a blue wind
Knocks on the door to your heart
You just gaze back at me
And smile oh so gently
So eager for something
You touch so softly
Those innocent eyes
Know nothing of the fate that awaits
But one day, you will realize
That upon your back
You have wings
You can fly to the faraway future
The cruel angel's thesis
One day, you'll take off through a window
If your overflowing pathos
Leads you to betray your memories
Then embrace the heavens and shine bright
Become legend, young boy
I wonder if he's going to
skip school again today.
SHINJI'S ROOM
Shinji, get up. How long are you
gonna stay home from school?
It's been five days already.
Unit 01 is as good as new.
Its pilot shouldn't be
sitting around like this.
Shinji?
TO MS. MISATO KATSURAGI
He ran away. I guess I can't blame him.
Shinji?!
Er, um...
We're in the same class as Mr. Ikari.
Our names are Aida and Suzuhara.
Aida and Suzuhara.
-Yes.
-Yes, ma'am! I'm Suzuhara.
Hang on, aren't you the two
who got into Unit 01's entry plug?
Yes, ma'am! We're really sorry
for any trouble we caused.
The thing is, we were worried because
Shinji hasn't been to school since then,
so we thought we'd check in on him.
Ah, Shinji's at Nerv's
training facility right now.
Oh, he is?
Um, these study guides
have been piling up on his desk.
You didn't have to
come all this way. Thanks.
Well, we should be on our way.
Say hi to Mr. Ikari for us.
Sure, I'll do that. Bye.
Well, this is an unexpected development.
What a babe.
Shinji, you little idiot!
Idiot...
TOKYO-3 LOOP LINE NO. 7
Next stop is Nagao-touge, Nagao-touge.
Please exit on the right side
of the train.
Thank you for using
Tokyo-3 Loop Line No. 7.
This train is no longer in service
after this stop.
Please remember to collect
your belongings before exiting.
I got to go home.
Hey, buddy! Step right in!
It's a real bargain!
-You really couldn't detect it?!
-No!
An object tens of millimeters across
struck the South Pole at speeds
in excess of 10% of the speed of light!
It was beyond modern science's ability
to predict, much less prevent!
But look at what's happening outside!
What good is science?!
Atmospheric flux caused by axial shift
has decreased to 3%.
Has it gotten better outside, then?
No! There's a tsunami on the way!
Incoming at 230 meters per second!
Doctor! We must escape!
No, my duty is to stay here!
Doctor, dying is easy!
But you also have a duty
to bear witness to...
Idiot...
He is only 14 years old.
Placing the fate of the human race
on his shoulders is a lot to ask.
But we have no choice
but to have 14-year-olds pilot the Evas.
I know that.
So, any word from Shinji?
Nothing?
None. Maybe he's not coming back.
-What do you intend to do about it?
-Nothing.
He might be better off
if he didn't come back.
Why?
Well, after the last battle...
Why did you ignore my order?
I'm sorry.
-Aren't I your operations director?
-Yes, ma'am.
It's your duty to obey my orders.
Do you understand that?
Yes, ma'am.
-Don't let this happen again.
-Yes, ma'am.
Is this really getting through to you?
Yes, ma'am.
Listen, just repeating
"Yes, ma'am" isn't enough!
I understand just fine.
But why does it matter? We won.
It might feel easier to just superficially
play along with what others say,
but piloting an Eva with that attitude
will get you killed!
That's okay. I don't care.
I wish I could say that I'm glad
to hear you've got guts,
but you're way off base if you think
that will score you points, Shinji Ikari.
I'm not fishing for compliments.
I'm just the only one who can pilot it.
So I'll pilot it.
Ah, I see.
If piloting the Eva only brings him pain,
he's better off not piloting it.
He'll definitely die.
But we need a pilot.
Lieutenant, sir!
Aida, go on without me!
But I can't leave you, sir!
Don't be a fool!
Oof...
The new kid?
Ikari!
SUMMER TRAINING OVERVIEW
Tohji was sorry he hit you.
I hear his little sister chewed him out.
She said it was your robot
that saved us all.
It's hilarious that he got taken
down a peg by a grade-schooler.
Right?
I like it at night.
Those cicadas aren't buzzing away.
It was nice and quiet when I was little,
but there's more every year.
Ms. Misato said something about
the ecosystem rebuilding itself.
"Ms. Misato," huh?
I'm so jealous!
You live with a total babe
and you get to pilot that Evangelion.
I wish I could pilot the Evangelion
all by myself just once!
I wouldn't if I were you.
Your mother would be worried sick.
Well, that's not a problem.
I don't have one.
Same as you.
-You're hungry, right?
-Yeah.
Do you do this a lot?
I guess.
Is it training for guerrilla warfare?
What good would toys like this do?
I'm just having fun.
Shinji Ikari?
Yes.
We're with Nerv Security & Intelligence.
We're taking you to HQ under section eight
of the Safety Preservation Ordinance.
-Will you comply?
-Yes.
So you just stood there
and let them grab him?!
Give me a break. Those guys were
Nerv Security & Intelligence.
Pros.
What's that got to do with it?!
Don't you have any balls?
-Gross!
-Weirdo!
Ape!
Only an idiot picks a fight he can't win.
Balls don't enter into it.
-It's been a while.
-Yes, ma'am.
Has wandering around for the last two days
made you feel any better?
Not really.
Your Eva is ready and waiting.
Will you pilot it?
Or not?
You're not going to scold me
for running away?
I guess you wouldn't. You're not family.
What would happen with Unit 01
if I didn't pilot it?
I suppose Rei would pilot it.
You're not going to?
How could I do something like that?
I couldn't force it all on her.
Don't worry. I'll do it.
But you don't want to?
Of course not.
I'm not cut out for this stuff.
But you and Ayanami and Ms. Ritsuko--
Knock it off!
What others think doesn't matter!
If you don't really want to, then leave!
Forget about the Evas and everything else!
Go back to your old life!
If you keep acting like this,
you're more trouble than you're worth!
The Third Children
will leave Tokyo-3 tomorrow.
Then rewrite Unit 01's data to match Rei.
But, sir...
Regardless of Unit 00's
reactivation trial results,
we will press on with trials with Unit 01.
Reports from the Marduk Institute
indicate the Fourth Children
has not been found.
Meaning that we have
no replacement pilots?
Um, where is Ms. Misato?
I'd like to say goodbye.
You're no longer with Nerv.
You're not cleared for that information.
-Hey, Ikari!
-You forgot this!
Um... Can I have a minute?
Um... Thanks.
Tohji, out with it! Go on!
Ikari, I shouldn't have hit you twice.
Hit me back.
I can't do that!
Please. I wouldn't be able
to live with myself.
You know how melodramatic he is.
Look, if it helps bury the hatchet,
just hit him.
But...
Come on! You don't have much time, right?
Okay. Just one.
Okay! Let me have it!
Wait!
No holding back.
Ouch!
-How did you know I'd be here?
-Call it a hunch.
We've said goodbye to dozens
of classmates here lately.
If you don't stick around, we'll all
probably have to leave town eventually.
But we can't force you to stay.
We saw what it's like for you in that Eva.
I dare anybody to bad-mouth you!
I'll beat the crap out of the guy!
Don't give me that hangdog look, man!
-Take care.
-Hang in there.
Um...
It's time.
Stop that!
I'm the one who should be clobbered!
I'm dishonest! And a coward!
I'm a sneak... and a weakling.
Don't give us any more trouble.
He's gone, I guess.
Is this for the best?
The Hedgehog's Dilemma, huh?
The closer they get,
the more they hurt each other.
I get it now.
He talks like that because he doesn't
know how else to express his feelings.
Limited express maglev bound for Atsugi
now arriving on track two.
For your safety,
please stand behind the yellow line.
The train on track two
is an official-use train
departing for Atsugi at 4:20.
The public must remain behind the fence.
Also, the boarding of unauthorized
personnel is strictly forbidden.
Take extra care to obey these rules.
Keep it up.
Look!
It's the babe from Ikari's place!
Local train bound for Goura
now arriving on track four.
For your safety,
please stand behind the yellow line.
Passengers with small children,
please keep a close eye on them.
The train arriving on track four
is the 4:32 local train for Goura.
All passengers using this train
should board and wait.
Train now arriving.
Please step behind the yellow line.
I... I'm home.
Welcome back.
TO BE CONTINUED
NEXT EPISODE
Rei Ayanami leads a life where her
interactions with others are minimal.
Commander Ikari is the only one
she opens up to.
Shinji is perplexed by this girl who
is closer to his own father than he is.
Next episode! "Rei, Beyond the Heart".
Translator: Dan Kanemitsu
Subtitle Editor: David Fleming