Like a cruel angel
Become a legend, young boy
When a blue wind
Knocks on the door to your heart
You just gaze back at me
And smile oh so gently
So eager for something
You touch so softly
Those innocent eyes
Know nothing of the fate that awaits
But one day, you will realize
That upon your back
You have wings
You can fly to the faraway future
The cruel angel's thesis
One day, you'll take off through a window
If your overflowing pathos
Leads you to betray your memories
Then embrace the heavens and shine bright
Become legend, young boy
FIFTEEN YEARS AGO
2000 A.D.
Dad...?
Thanks for letting us
wait out the rain here, Shinji.
Where's Ms. Misato?
She might still be asleep. She's been
working a lot of all-nighters lately.
Well, she's got an important job.
Let's try to keep it down
so we don't wake her up, okay?
What the heck are you guys doing here?!
Waiting out the rain.
Hah! You're after me, I bet!
I'm getting changed,
so if you peek, you're dead men.
Oh, shut up! Jackass!
What sicko would want
to watch you get changed?!
She sure thinks highly of herself.
-Sorr--
-Sorry to be a bother, ma'am!
Hi, boys. It's good to see you.
Welcome home.
We're doing harmonics testing tonight,
so don't be late.
Yes, ma'am.
Asuka, did you get that?
I heard!
Allow me to congratulate you
on your promotion, ma'am!
Uh, congratulations.
-Thanks.
-The pleasure is all mine, ma'am!
Well, I'm off.
Have a nice day!
What was that about?
Did something happen to Misato?
The rank insignia on her collar!
It has two bars now!
She's been promoted from captain to major.
-Oh? I didn't notice.
-When did that happen?
Are you two for real?
Man, you're pathetic.
How can you be so blind
to the lives of others?
It must be hard for someone so young
to take care of two junior high schoolers.
It's just you and me. Nobody else here
considers other people's feelings.
Plugs Zero and Two are just short of
the contamination zone. This is the limit.
Plug One still has some room.
Try lowering the graph depth another 0.3.
He's almost at the contamination zone.
And he's still putting out values
like these? That's impressive.
His harmonics and synch rate values
are closing in on Asuka's.
I wonder if this is a sort of talent.
It's like he was born to pilot an Eva.
Yeah, even if he doesn't want to.
You can bet he doesn't enjoy this.
Good work, all three of you.
Shinji, you did very well.
What did I do?
Your harmonics levels are up
eight points from last time.
-Those are impressive numbers.
-But he's still 50 below me!
That's eight points in ten days.
That's a big deal.
That's no big deal at all!
Gee, it must be ever so nice
to be lavished with praise like that!
I'm going back to the apartment! Jerk!
And that was a postcard
from "Waa-kun" of Tokyo-2.
Look, just because
you got dumped, don't...
Uh, congratulations on your promotion.
Thanks. But to be honest,
I'm not too happy about it.
I know how you feel.
When I'm praised like I was back there,
I don't feel very happy about it.
And stuff like that only makes Asuka mad.
Why did she get angry?
I wonder what I did wrong.
-Does that bother you?
-Yes, ma'am.
She was angry at how you're always
so worried about what others think.
Congratulations!
Thanks.
Thank you, Suzuhara.
Nope. This guy is the mastermind
behind this shindig.
Yes! I, Kensuke Aida,
handled all the planning!
Thanks, Aida.
No, I didn't do anything special.
Anybody would have done the same.
How come you're here, Class Rep?
Because I invited her!
Right?
What about Rei?
I invited her over, I really did.
But that girl is so unsociable.
What's keeping Mr. Kaji?
-So is this Kaji guy really that cool?
-You better believe it!
He's like night and day
compared to this bunch of hicks!
It's an insult to Mr. Kaji
to compare them to him!
Them's fighting words!
Say that again, I dare you!
Do you still have trouble
with stuff like this?
No, it's just that I'm not
very good with crowds.
Why do we have to go to the trouble
of making such a big ruckus?
So, this promotion...
It means that other people
have recognized your value, right?
Yeah, something like that.
So that's why everybody is happy for you.
But you aren't happy for yourself?
Oh, I wouldn't say I'm unhappy.
I am, a little.
But that's not what I came here to do.
Why did you come here, then?
Why did you join Nerv?
It's been so long, I don't remember.
That must be Mr. Kaji!
I came straight from headquarters.
Look who I ran into.
This seems really fishy.
-Is that jealousy I hear?
-Why would I be jealous?
Anyway, my sincerest congratulations,
Major Katsuragi.
I guess I can't talk to you
informally anymore.
Give me a break, you idiot.
Still, it's unprecedented for both
the Commander and Deputy Commander
to be out of Japan at the same time.
It means that they trust you enough
to put you in charge while they're gone.
My father is out of town?
Commander Ikari is off at the South Pole.
Antarctica, a realm of the dead
where no life is permitted to exist.
No, perhaps "Hell" is more appropriate.
But here we humans stand.
As living things do, we survived.
Because we're protected
by the power of science.
Humanity makes up for
its limited strength with science.
That arrogance is what caused the tragedy
15 years ago, the Second Impact.
Look at what it got us.
Our punishment was far too severe.
This is a literal dead sea.
And yet, it is a pristine world,
untainted by original sin.
I prefer a world filled with humans,
sinful though it may be.
I have a report, sir.
Dispatch from Nerv HQ:
Angel detected in orbit
over the Indian Ocean.
It appeared out of nowhere
two minutes ago.
Re-tasking OBSAT no. 6 to target's orbit.
Contact in two minutes.
We have the target on visual.
Now, that's impressive.
Wow, that boggles the mind.
Now making contact with target.
Beginning scan.
Now commencing data transmission.
Receiving signal.
An A.T. Field?!
That's a novel way to use it.
It sure packs a punch.
That's an A.T. Field for you.
It's also using the energy from the drop.
The Angel itself is effectively a bomb.
Anyway, its first shot landed
way off target in the Pacific.
The second shot, two hours later,
impacted there.
It's definitely been
correcting as it goes.
Which means that it's learning.
Aerial N2 mines have had no effect.
The Angel dropped off
our scopes after that.
It's headed our way, I bet.
In its next attack, the whole thing
will come down on us.
Do you think the crater
would create Lake Ashi No. 3?
The Fuji Five Lakes area would turn
into a single lake linked to the Pacific.
Taking HQ with it.
Orders from Cdr. Ikari?
Due to the powerful ECM the Angel
is emitting, we can't get through.
What's the Magi saying?
-They unanimously recommend evacuation.
-So, what do we do?
You're the ranking officer right now.
Contact the government and its agencies!
On Nerv's authority, I am issuing
Special Declaration D-17!
Citizens within a 50 km radius
are to evacuate immediately.
Ask Matsushiro to begin
backing up the Magi.
We're abandoning headquarters?
No, but there's no reason
to put everyone in danger.
Special Declaration D-17 has been
declared by the government.
All citizens, evacuate to your
designated locations at once.
Everyone must move quickly and follow
your ward mayors' instructions,
with top priority given
to wards six and seven.
Citywide evacuation complete.
Evacuation of all noncombatants
and Class-D workers has been
completed as per Departmental Alert C.
-You're really going through with this?
-Yes, I am.
Do you want to throw away all three
Evas on an unsanctioned operation?
Its chances of success are 0.00001%.
Not even a million to one.
But it's not zero.
I'm just betting on the Evas.
Major Katsuragi!
I'm the ranking officer here.
I want to do everything I can.
Defeating the Angels is my job.
Your job? That's a laugh.
You're doing this for yourself.
You want revenge against the Angels.
Catch it?! With our bare hands?!
Yes. We station the Evas at
the estimated point of impact.
Then you catch the Angel directly
with your A.T. Fields at maximum.
What if the Angel
veers too far off course?
Then it's game over.
What if the Evas
can't withstand the impact?
Then it's also game over.
-What are our odds?
-Heaven only knows, you might say.
If this works, it will be a miracle...
Miracles are only worth a damn
when you make them happen yourself.
So, basically,
find a way to make this work?
I'm sorry, but we're out of options.
This operation is all that we have.
You think this mess
qualifies as an operation?
True, it really doesn't.
That's why you can refuse if you want.
Are you all on board?
Regulations say that you're supposed
to write out a will. Will you?
No, thanks. I don't plan on dying today.
Me, neither. There's no need to.
I'll pass, too.
Thanks, you guys. Once all this is over,
I'll treat you to a steak dinner!
-Really?!
-I promise.
-Yay!
-We'll hold you to it!
Look forward to it.
She equates special treats
with steak dinners, huh?
She should know better than to think
kids these days care about steaks.
This is why the Second Impact Generation
has such a poor-person image.
Come on, that's not their fault.
What was with that "Yay!" bit, huh?
You were laying it on a bit thick.
If that makes it easier for her to run
the operation, what's wrong with it?
Well, if she says she's going
to take us someplace special...
Let's see, what looks good?
And you're coming with us this time!
-I'm not coming.
-Why not?
I don't like meat.
Unable to track target due to
RF jamming from the Angel.
We can't get a precise fix, but based
on our data prior to losing contact,
the Magi have calculated
that it will impact
somewhere in here.
It's that big an area?!
From edge to edge,
that's a lot of ground to cover!
With the target using its A.T. Field,
it can utterly destroy HQ
no matter where it falls inside that area.
That's why I will position the Evas
in these three locations.
What is the positioning based on?
-Intuition.
-Intuition?
Sure. Women's intuition.
Talk about a stab in the dark. Our miracle
is slipping further and further away.
Ms. Misato plays the lottery,
but she's never won.
Geez...
-Hey.
-What now?
Why do you pilot your Eva, Asuka?
Why else? To show the whole world
how talented I am!
To let them know you exist?
Yeah, something like that.
You're not going to ask her?
I already asked Ayanami.
Gosh, aren't you two all chummy?
It's not like that.
What about you, then?
I don't know why.
You don't know?
What are you, a total idiot?
I really might be.
You really are an idiot.
T minus 120 minutes
to estimated time of impact.
Go ahead and clear out, you guys.
I can run things here by myself.
No, ma'am. This is our job.
We can't run away and let
those kids face the danger alone.
You don't need to worry about them.
No matter how badly they're damaged,
the Evas' A.T. Fields will protect them.
Sitting inside those Evas
is the safest place to be.
Shinji? Remember what you
asked me yesterday?
You wanted to know why I joined Nerv.
My father was a man who was
absorbed in his research.
A man who lived in his dreams.
I couldn't stand him for that.
I hated him, even.
Just like my father...
He never paid any attention to his family.
His own wife and daughter.
Everyone said he was a sensitive man.
But he was really just a spineless man
who couldn't stomach reality.
Who couldn't face the reality
that my mother and I represented.
He was almost childlike in that way.
When Mom decided to leave him,
I immediately backed her decision.
He made her cry so much.
The divorce seemed to blindside him,
but I laughed because
he deserved a rude awakening.
But in the end,
he gave his life to save me.
That was during the Second Impact.
After that, I didn't know anymore.
Did I hate my father or love him?
All I know for sure is that
I have to destroy the Angels,
the cause of the Second Impact.
That's why I joined Nerv.
Maybe it all boils down to me
wanting revenge against my father.
To free myself from his hold over me.
Don't run away...
Right. Don't run away.
Visual confirmation at max magnification!
Distance, roughly 25,000.
Our guest has arrived, huh?
All Evas to your start positions.
Our trajectory calculations are entirely
dependent on optical observation.
As such, the Magi will guide you
until it reaches a distance of 10,000.
After that, act on your own judgment.
We're entrusting everything to you.
Angel closing in!
Distance, roughly 20,000!
All right, commence operation!
Let's do it.
Mission start!
Distance, 12,000!
Field to maximum!
Unit 02, set field to maximum!
Already on it!
Do it!
Eat this!
Radio systems back online.
Incoming signal from
Cdr. Ikari at the South Pole.
-Put him through.
-Yes, ma'am.
I apologize. My unsanctioned operation
resulted in Unit 01 being damaged.
I assume full responsibility
for my actions.
That's all right. The Evas' mission
is to eliminate the Angels.
We can count our blessings that
the damage was so limited.
He's right. You did well, Major Katsuragi.
Thank you very much, sir.
Is the pilot of Unit 01 there?
Yes, sir.
I heard what happened. Good work, Shinji.
Thank you.
Very well, Major Katsuragi.
See to the post-mission cleanup.
Yes, sir.
ALL LANES INBOUND
TOKYO-3 LOOP LINE NO. 7
Next stop is New Miyanoshita.
New Miyanoshita.
Doors will open to the left at...
Okay, we're holding you to your promise!
Sure, no problem.
I pulled out plenty of cash, so I can
handle a full-course dinner if I have to.
Payday can't come soon enough.
RAMEN
We know how empty your bank account is!
Don't sweat it, Misato.
Besides, Miss Perfect said she'd come
if we went out for ramen.
I'll have the garlic ramen, hold the pork.
Shark fin with roast pork!
Make it a large!
Here you go! One shark fin and pork!
-Um... Ms. Misato?
-Yeah?
When my father said
what he did back there,
I finally understood why people say
that being praised makes them happy.
And I finally figured it out.
Maybe I pilot my Eva because I want
to hear my father say things like that.
Wait... That's why you're an Eva pilot?
You really are an idiot.
TO BE CONTINUED
An incident takes place
during a simulation plug test.
The facility is compromised
level by level.
In the end, Nerv is forced to
decide whether to self-destruct.
Next episode! "Angel Infiltration"!
Tune in next time
for lots more fan service!
Translator: Dan Kanemitsu
Subtitle Editor: David Fleming