Like a cruel angel
Become a legend, young boy
When a blue wind
Knocks on the door to your heart
You just gaze back at me
And smile oh so gently
So eager for something
You touch so softly
Those innocent eyes
Know nothing of the fate that awaits
But one day, you will realize
That upon your back
You have wings
You can fly to the faraway future
The cruel angel's thesis
One day, you'll take off through a window
If your overflowing pathos
Leads you to betray your memories
Then embrace the heavens and shine bright
Become legend, young boy
Major Katsuragi, you refused a direct
interrogation of the pilot of Unit 01,
the only actual participant
in this incident.
Yes, sir. His emotional state
is very unstable.
I felt it unwise for him
to stand before you at this time.
Then we will direct our inquiry to you,
Major Katsuragi, as his proxy.
In your opinion, is it plausible
that the Angels were attempting
to establish communication
with mankind in this incident?
I did not get that impression
from the subject's report.
My assessment is that
this was a freak accident.
Assuming his memories
of the incident are reliable.
There are no signs of
external memory tampering.
The Eva's AC recorder was not running.
You cannot be certain of that.
Could it be that Angels are now interested
in the human psyche? The heart?
I am unable to answer that.
Do Angels even have
the concept of hearts and minds?
Are they capable of understanding
human thought? We simply don't know.
This incident had a new element to it.
That Angel tried to assimilate the Eva.
Our projections indicate there will be
attacks from a 13th Angel and beyond.
Is this a prelude of things to come?
Their behavior patterns suggest the Angels
do not act in a coordinated manner.
Indeed. It is clear that they act
independently from one another.
Thus far, at least.
What do you mean by that, sir?
-We will ask the questions.
-Yes, sir.
-That is all. Dismissed.
What do you make of this, Ikari?
The Angels are becoming intelligent.
Which means our time--
Is growing short?
Is that what you're saying?
The patient in room 12?
The one hurt in that E-Incident, remember?
She's been here a long time.
There have been a lot
of complications, I hear.
She's just a grade-schooler...
Is that boy here again today?
Yes, he comes twice a week like clockwork.
What a thoughtful big brother.
No kidding.
Boys like him are a rarity these days.
SUZUHARA
Rei, are you finished for today?
Yes, sir. I'm going to go see
Doctor Akagi tomorrow.
I'll return to school the day after that.
How is school?
There are no issues.
I see. That's fine, then.
All rise! Bow!
Be seated!
Today's absentees are Ayanami,
yet again, and also Aida?
Where's Kensuke?
New Yokosuka. He went to go
check out another battleship.
Something about a ship called
the Myoko being in port.
Suzuhara!
Sir! Yes, sir!
Make sure you take the study guides
to Ayanami's after school.
Yes, sir!
So the situation at the First Branch
is normal, then?
Never mind, we'll have the Magi
confirm data accuracy with a flyover!
It vanished?!
The Second Branch has vanished?
Did I hear that right?
Yes, sir. We have full confirmation.
It vanished.
Well, this is a fine mess.
Admin and Investigations
were both freaking out topside.
General Affairs was in total panic mode.
-So, what was the cause?
-Still unknown.
Our only clue is this feed
from a satellite in stationary orbit.
Nothing else is left.
Ten seconds.
Eight. Seven. Six. Five.
Four. Three. Two. One.
Contact.
This is horrible...
Evangelion Unit 04 has vanished,
taking with it all research labs
and facilities within 89 kilometers.
Along with thousands of people.
Based on the project timeline,
we surmise there was
a mishap during a test install of
the S2 Drive that was fixed in Germany.
There are 32,768 possible causes, ranging
from material strength deficiencies
to errors made early on
in the design process.
Sabotage can't be ruled out, either.
But this wasn't just an explosion.
It was complete annihilation.
Disappeared without a trace.
It was probably swallowed by
a Dirac sea. Just like Unit 01 was.
And the S2 Drive
that we finally got fixed?
Poof. So much for our dreams of using it.
They shouldn't have played
with things they don't understand.
The same thing can be said of the Evas.
What's going to be done
with Unit 03, then?
We'll be taking it in here.
The US government doesn't seem keen on
the idea of also losing the First Branch.
They demanded construction rights
for 03 and 04 and just plowed ahead!
Now they dump their Eva on us when
things get hot? Talk about self-serving.
Who wouldn't get cold feet
after a catastrophe like that?
So, what about the activation test?
Will the Dummy be used?
They're about to decide that.
This is the prototype Dummy Plug.
Rei's personality has been
transplanted into it.
But you can't digitize
the human heart. The soul.
It's just a fake. A faux stand-in
It's merely a machine that imitates
a pilot's cognitive patterns.
It sends a signal pattern to the Eva.
What matters is that the Eva believes
a pilot is there and synchronizes with it.
Have the data uploaded
into Units 01 and 02.
There are still issues to be resolved.
-Irrelevant. Just get the Eva to activate.
-Yes, sir.
The UN has been entrusted
with the transportation of the Eva.
It should arrive here this weekend.
Take care of the rest once it does.
Yes, sir.
Our adjustments and the activation trial
will be conducted at Matsushiro.
And the test pilot?
The Dummy Plug is still too dangerous.
We'll review the candidates list--
And choose a Fourth?
Yes, sir. There's one child with which
a core could be prepared for right away.
-See to it.
-Yes, sir.
Rei, you can come out.
-Let's get something to eat.
Yes, sir.
All rise! Bow!
Sweet, it's chow time!
The best part of being at school!
You didn't bring a lunchbox for me?!
I was too busy with homework
yesterday to make anything!
That's your excuse for making me
go without lunch today?!
What is it now? Another lover's quarrel?
-Get real!
Why so serious all of a sudden?
For Unit 03's startup tests at Matsushiro,
we're going to use the Fourth
as our test pilot.
"Fourth?" You mean they've
found the Fourth Children?
Yesterday.
I didn't get a report from
the Marduk Institute.
You'll have the official
paperwork tomorrow.
Are you keeping secrets
from me again, Doctor Akagi?
Not really.
Okay, I'll drop it.
So, which kid got picked?
Of all the kids they could have picked,
they went with him?
There was always a chance. The candidates
are kept together for their protection.
It's going to be hard
to break this to him.
Asuka, I can understand.
Her pride drives her to be an Eva pilot.
Rei is also an exception.
But for anyone else, nothing good comes
of associating with us and the Evas.
Shinji understands that
better than anybody.
I don't want to make things harder
for him than they already are.
But we need children like them.
Our collective survival depends on them.
"Stop being such an idealist"? Is that it?
Later!
Suzuhara! You're on duty for the rest
of the week, so stay on top of things.
On top of what?
These study guides! The teacher
told you to drop them off, remember?
Come on, Class Rep.
Let the girl duty officer do that.
Ms. Ayanami is absent today!
Oh, Ayanami and I are on duty?
Well, ain't that a kicker!
Still, I can't pay a girl
a visit by myself.
-Then I can go with--
-Hey, Shinji!
Walk home with me!
AYANAMI
Ayanami? We're coming in.
It's not cool to go into
a girl's place without permission.
We don't have a choice. She'll never
see them if you put them in there.
Excuse us.
What the hell? A girl lives here?
Talk about spartan.
BULLETIN
Hey! She'll get mad
if you mess with her stuff!
I'm just straightening up.
Don't expect me to help!
I'm a man, not a maid!
Okay, but Ms. Misato hates guys
who say stuff like that.
So be it! It's the principle of the thing!
Man, what a change.
-In what?
-You.
To be honest, when I first met you,
I thought you were a real SOB.
I didn't peg you for a guy who would
go out of his way to help others.
Well, I guess you were stressing out
about everything back then.
We let ourselves in.
-Why?
-Those study guides have been piling up.
Sorry.
I tidied up a bit. I didn't touch
anything but the trash.
Uh... Thank you.
Seriously dude,
you Eva pilots are all weirdos.
"Thank you."
Words of gratitude. The very first words.
Words I had never spoken before,
not even to him...
The city. A paradise built
by the hands of man.
Man was cast out of the Garden of Eden
and forced to flee into a world where
death could come at any moment.
He created his own Garden of Eden
using the knowledge he was forced
to gain as the weakest of all lifeforms.
A paradise we built for ourselves
to insulate our kind from the terror
of death and satisfy our carnal desires?
This city is a stellar example of that.
An armed city, built for our protection.
It's a city of cowards. Shelter for those
fleeing an outside world full of enemies.
Cowards tend to live the longest.
There is no shame in that.
Tokyo-3...
Nerv's camouflaged
Angel interception fortress city.
The endlessly-delayed seventh
construction phase is finally ending.
The city is finally complete.
How are you going to report the accident
with Unit 04 to the Council?
I'll report the facts.
The cause is unknown.
Its loss is a severe blow at this stage.
Unit 04 and the Second Branch
are unimportant.
Even if the S2 Drive
and the samples were lost,
the data is secure in Germany.
Having Tokyo-3 and Unit 01
is all that matters.
The Council was clearly rattled.
This was an unforeseen accident.
Seele must be working feverishly
to revise their action plan.
Things happen. Things not foretold
in the Dead Sea Scrolls.
The old men needed to learn that lesson.
Ward Three's mode transition
and directed-energy weapons tests will...
This place's interception systems
are finally nearly done,
but nobody's throwing a party
to celebrate the occasion?
Nerv sure is a prudish outfit.
Because Commander Ikari is.
And what about you?
Careful, Mr. Kaji.
I'll tell Major Katsuragi and Dr. Akagi.
Not if I cover your lips with mine first.
So, how's your work going?
Oh, it goes, it goes.
Well, I should get back to work.
I don't mean to butt into
your private life...
but could you not make a move on
our girls during an emergency?
She's not under your command.
Does that mean you're fair game?
That depends on your answers.
You know the secrets behind Adam
and the Marduk Institute, don't you?
-Whatever do you mean?
-Don't play dumb.
It's not like you to come
to someone for help.
I can't let my pride get in the way.
I don't have that luxury anymore.
How did they find the Fourth Children
exactly when we needed him?
I'll just say this:
The Marduk Institute doesn't exist.
Nerv itself is pulling all the strings.
Nerv itself? Commander Ikari?
Dig into Code 7-0-7.
7-0-7? Shinji's school?
Ms. Misato?
Yeah?
Ms. Ritsuko wanted to talk to you
about a trip tomorrow.
Okay. Thanks.
-We'll talk later.
-Sure thing.
Need anything? How about some tea with me?
But I'm a guy.
You're not the respectable person
I thought you were, Mr. Kaji.
When you're relaxed around someone,
you don't pull any punches, Shinji Ikari.
Um, I'm sorry!
No, I'm the one who should apologize.
I didn't mean it as a dig against you.
Oh, hey! Let me show you
something special.
Are these... watermelons?
Yeah. Cute, huh? They're my hobby.
Don't tell anybody, okay?
It's great to make something.
To grow something.
You notice things and figure stuff out.
-Things you enjoy, for example.
-And things that hurt.
You don't like being hurt?
-I don't care for it.
-Did you find something you enjoy?
That's all well and good.
But listen, people who know what pain is
are kinder to others because of it.
That's not the same thing as being weak.
Hello?
It's Katsuragi. She says
they're about to start your synch test.
-Plug depth holding at 3.2.
-Just as I thought.
Shinji's synch rates are falling.
What's that mean?
It could be anything.
But something must have happened
during that last incident.
Something psychological.
It just keeps getting harder
to tell him about Unit 03's pilot...
But the pilot himself
will be formally notified tomorrow.
All rise! Attention! Bow!
-Tohji Suzuhara of 8th grade, class A.
-Yes, chow time!
Tohji Suzuhara,
report to the principal's office.
-What the hell?
-Did you do something?
Uh... Not that I know of.
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE
Tohji Suzuhara, sir!
So, you are Tohji Suzuhara?
So, how did it go at
New Yokosuka yesterday?
Excellent!
Actually, I heard
a troubling piece of Intel.
Eva-03?
Yeah, the one they were building
in the USA. It's finished, right?
I don't know.
I know you're supposed to keep
things secret, but I have to know!
Honest, I haven't heard anything!
You haven't heard about an activation test
at Test Site No. 2 in Matsushiro?
That's news to me.
They haven't decided
on a pilot yet, right?
I wouldn't know about that stuff.
I wonder if Ms. Misato
would let me be the pilot...
Could you ask her for me, Shinji?
I want to pilot an Eva!
Honest, I don't know anything.
Then what about the news
that Unit 04 was de-listed?
-How do you mean?
-You really don't know about that, either?
They say it blew up with
the whole Second Branch.
There was a big commotion
at my Dad's department.
-Seriously?
-Sounds like it.
Ms. Misato never said anything...
Well, that's stuff that you frontline
pilots don't need to worry about.
If she didn't tell you, it's got to be
because you didn't need to know, Shinji.
Sorry I've been pestering you
with all these questions.
Man, I wonder what's keeping Tohji?
And thus, mankind was able
to rise from the ashes after the living
hell that was the Second Impact.
The birth rate has been falling
with each passing year.
Sorry I'm late.
I was filled in. Take your seat.
You of the next generation,
on whose shoulders the future rests...
Come on, let's go home.
-What about Tohji?
-He's staying late.
He's class duty officer this week.
The school building will be locked soon.
Those students who are still...
Suzuhara!
You're on duty, okay?
Make sure the desks are lined up neatly
and write up the daily report.
I haven't eaten lunch yet.
I'll do it afterwards.
You always eat packaged food
from the school store, don't you?
Well, nobody can make me a lunch at home.
Suzuhara?
I have an older and a younger sister.
Their names are Kodama and Nozomi.
I always make lunches for us.
That sounds rough.
You'd never guess it,
but I'm actually a good cook.
Oh?
So, anyway, I usually have ingredients
left over from making them.
That's a waste.
If you have leftovers,
I can help get rid of them if you want.
Would you mind?
Mr. Kaji!
Is that you, Asuka? Sorry, but I'm busy.
Come back later.
You always have time for Misato...
Hey! This isn't the time.
This is our synch data, right?
Four pilots?!
What is this? What's going on?
How could he be the Fourth Children?
No way! This doesn't make any sense!
What the hell is this?!
AMERICA, NERV FIRST BRANCH
TO BE CONTINUED
NEXT EPISODE
America's Eva-03 arrives at
Matsushiro for its activation tests.
Unaware of the tragedy
the next day would bring,
everyone enjoys living
one last normal day.
Next episode! "Life and Death Decisions"!
Translator: Dan Kanemitsu
Subtitle Editor: David Fleming