2000 A.D., ANTARCTICA
You're talking about Dr. Katsuragi's
Super Solenoid Theory?
I must say,
that theory is far too radical.
It's still very much a hypothesis.
But the S2 theory is the only explanation
for how that giant is being powered.
There is no need to validate
what is already proven.
It exists right before us.
-We must accept it.
-Once all the data is in.
Scientists put far too much faith
in their beliefs.
You think they are dogmatic?
Their assumptions
are too deeply ingrained.
These are people who are unable
to accurately perceive reality.
And yet such people
seek the truth. How ironic.
There is nothing noble about what they do.
The act of discovery brings them joy,
and understanding leads to dominance.
What they seek is self-gratification,
nothing more.
Stop the surface luminescence!
It's exceeding threshold values!
The DNA that was inserted into Adam
has undergone physical fusion!
All the A.T. Fields are giving way!
-The spear! Pull up the spear!
-No-go! Magnetic field unstable!
It's sinking in!
Limit the damage any way you can!
Every bit counts!
Break up its component atoms
on the quark level! Hurry!
Initiate cooling cycle
the instant the Gates of Guf opens!
Incredible! It's walking!
Make it interfere with its own Anti-A.T.
Field! Even if only for a split second!
It's spreading its wings!
It's reached the surface!
Like a cruel angel
Become a legend, young boy
When a blue wind
Knocks on the door to your heart
You just gaze back at me
And smile oh so gently
So eager for something
You touch so softly
Those innocent eyes
Know nothing of the fate that awaits
But one day, you will realize
That upon your back
You have wings
You can fly to the faraway future
The cruel angel's thesis
One day, you'll take off through a window
If your overflowing pathos
Leads you to betray your memories
Then embrace the heavens and shine bright
Become legend, young boy
Hello, I'm not home right now.
Leave a message after the beep.
One last job to do.
It's the same color as blood.
What do you mean,
the deputy commander's been abducted?
It happened two hours ago.
His last confirmed location
was in Ward Eight in the west.
Wait, that's inside this facility!
Were you guys at Intel asleep on the job?
They had an inside man who was
leaking Intel and stirring up trouble.
He gave us the runaround.
A man who could outwit Intel Section Two?
Oh, don't tell me...
Ryoji Kaji. We believe him to be
the mastermind behind the disappearance.
Which is why you came to see me.
It's helpful that you catch on so quickly.
As colleagues, we hate having to suspect
our own chief of operations,
but this is our job.
Considering my history with him,
it's the logical step to take.
Thank you for your cooperation. Bring her.
It's been quite some time, Chairman Keel.
This is a rather rough welcome,
don't you think?
Apologies for rude behavior
are not warranted here.
We needed to have an uninterrupted chat.
It was the logical step to take.
You never change. My convenience
has never been a concern for you.
This matter requires immediate attention.
It couldn't be helped.
Please understand.
It must be, if you're appearing to me
as Seele rather than the Council.
We have no intention
of creating a new god.
We require your assistance,
Professor Fuyutsuki.
"Professor Fuyutsuki," is it?
Professor! Professor Fuyutsuki!
Oh, hello, boys.
Have any plans, sir?
Want to grab a beer at Kamogawa?
Again?
Ryoko and her friends say they'll come,
but only if you do.
The other professors say you ought
to join in every once in a while.
All right, all right.
It's good for you to go out for
a drink every now and again.
Yes, sir.
You're very talented,
but you should give more thought
to cultivating relationships.
I'll take that to heart, sir.
By the way, Fuyutsuki,
there's a student over in Bioengineering
who's put together a fascinating report.
Do you know a student
by the name of Ikari?
Ikari? No, sir.
When I mentioned you and your work, Ikari
expressed an interest in meeting you.
This student will be in touch soon.
Be accommodating, will you?
"Ikari," was it? Very well, sir.
METAPHYSICAL BIO, LAB NO.1
(FUYUTSUKI)
I've taken the liberty
of reading your report.
There are a few points I'm not sold on,
but it was a stimulating read.
Thank you, sir.
"Yui Ikari," was it?
Yes, sir.
What are your plans after graduation?
Get a job in the private sector?
Or take a position at a lab here, perhaps?
I haven't thought that far ahead yet.
And isn't there also a third option?
I've also thought about starting a family.
Assuming I meet the right person.
AGAIN, IN 2015 A.D.
By assimilating that S2 Drive...
...it has attained absolute existence.
Evangelion Unit 01...
A manifested god is of no use to us.
We mustn't create a god.
Much less allow it
to fall into that man's hands.
Gendoh Ikari... Can this man be trusted?
Gendoh Rokubungi?
Yes, I've heard the name.
No, I've never personally met him.
But he is the sort of man
whose reputation precedes him.
What? He's asking to be released
into my custody?
No, I'll come down.
When would be a good time?
I heard about you from a mutual friend.
I wanted to meet you for myself.
I wasn't expecting you to be
the trashy sort who gets into bar brawls.
He took a swing at me
before I could talk my way out of it.
Being liked makes me uncomfortable.
I'm far more used to being an outcast.
Well, your social skills
have nothing to do with me.
Prof. Fuyutsuki, you seem to be exactly
the sort of man I hoped you would be.
My first impression was that he
was a thoroughly unpleasant man.
It was autumn at the time. This was back
when this country still had seasons.
-Is that true?
-Yes.
I'm in a relationship with Mr. Rokubungi.
I could not hide my surprise
when I heard those words.
I'm surprised you have anything in common.
Now, now, Professor Fuyutsuki.
He's actually very charming.
No one knows it, that's all.
Then perhaps ignorance really is bliss.
Was my introducing you an imposition?
No. He's an interesting man, to be sure.
But I can't bring myself to like him.
In my circles, it was widely thought that
he had fostered a relationship with Yui
to gain access to her talents
and the group she was associated with.
Later on, I heard rumors that
this group's name was "Seele."
ANTARCTICA, 2000 A.D.
The Second Impact.
That tragedy struck in the final year
of the 20th Century.
And the first year of the 21st Century
could only be described as Hell.
There are no other words
to describe that year.
2002 A.D.
AICHI PREF., RUINS OF TOYOHASHI CITY
Another 30°C day today, they say.
It certainly is very hot here.
Not at all uncommon anymore.
Not in Japan these days.
Summer has lasted nearly an entire year.
It's really doing a number on me.
Why not move to the ship up there?
You mean the neighboring town?
That place constantly reeks of oil.
It's too much for me.
Even so, we didn't expect you to be
running a medical practice here.
It took considerable effort
to find you, sir.
There's a shortage of doctors here.
I may just be playing the part,
but I'm better than nothing.
Why go to Antarctica now?
It's a formal investigation of
the incident by the UN Security Council.
It's a provisional group,
but I think it will be a better way
to serve your fellow man
than being an unlicensed doctor
in the middle of nowhere...
Professor Fuyutsuki.
Former professor.
The space for who recommended me
is left blank. Who was it?
ANTARCTICA, THAT SAME YEAR
It's hard to believe that this
was once a continent of ice.
It's utterly unrecognizable.
Professor Fuyutsuki.
Oh, it's you.
I'm amazed you're still alive.
I heard you were on
the Katsuragi Expedition.
As luck would have it, I had returned
to Japan the day beforehand,
so I managed to avoid the tragedy.
I see. Look, Rokubungi--
Excuse me, Professor,
but I've changed my name.
A postcard? Not a business card?
WE'RE MARRIED!
GENDOH AND YUI IKARI
Ikari... Gendoh Ikari?
The missus insisted that I give this
to you, Professor. She's quite the fan.
I'm honored to hear that.
So, how is Yui? She's not coming
on this field expedition?
She wanted to come with us,
but we have a child now.
This organization you belong to.
Seele, was it?
I've heard nothing but bad things.
I can't say I approve of the way
they strong-arm the Security Council.
As principled as ever, I see.
But these days, no organization
that plays by the rules can survive.
This official investigation
of the Second Impact...
It would raise suspicions if it were
composed entirely of Seele members.
That's why the rest of us
were brought in, isn't it?
2015 A.D.
NERV ISOLATION FACILITY NO.4
I still don't like dark places.
Bad things always come back to me.
Who is she?
The sole survivor
of the original expedition.
2002 A.D.
Her name is Misato Katsuragi.
Katsuragi? The daughter
of Doctor Katsuragi?
Yes. She hasn't spoken a single word
in nearly two years.
That poor girl...
Whatever she saw,
it was bad enough to do that.
Mental trauma can take longer to heal
than simple physical injuries.
Very true.
Releasing our findings
will require careful attention.
Alteration of atmospheric composition
confined to a specific area.
The total eradication of all life,
right down to the microorganisms.
The remains of a vast subterranean
chamber beneath the epicenter.
And this giant of light...
Everything about this incident
is a mystery.
Afterwards, the UN would officially report
that the Second Impact was caused by
the impact of a meteor of enormous mass.
In my eyes, however,
it was clear that this was a cover-up.
I could catch hints of Seele, and a man
called Keel, at work behind the scenes.
I wanted to learn more about
the dark truth behind this incident.
Even if the name "Yui Ikari" popped up.
It's been a long time.
Yes. It certainly has.
Why would you conceal
the existence of the giant?
Your group knew the Second Impact
was coming, didn't it?
You knew it would happen that day.
You mentioned you were lucky enough
to leave the day before the incident.
Was it also luck that you gathered all of
your research material before you left?
I thought all those had been incinerated.
I'm surprised.
I've looked into your finances.
I realize that it takes
a lot of money to raise a child,
but don't you think you have far more
than any individual needs?
Impressive as ever, Professor Fuyutsuki.
Perhaps you should
change fields to economics.
I'm going public with how your Seele group
and the Dead Sea Scrolls
are connected to the Second Impact.
I refuse to let those responsible
get away with it!
As you wish.
But before you do that,
there's something I want you to see.
We're certainly going down a long way...
-Does that worry you?
-Somewhat, yes.
What on earth?
A structure that was left behind
by someone who wasn't us.
Eighty-nine percent of it is buried.
Then this was originally a perfectly
spherical underground space?
Is it identical to the subterranean
cavern in Antarctica?
The data is almost a perfect match.
Are you people trying to
recreate that tragedy?
Are you?!
See what we're doing
and judge for yourself.
All of mankind's resources
are being poured into that installation.
Oh, hello, Professor Fuyutsuki.
Akagi? You're involved in this, too?
Yes. This is the best place
to work out the basic theories
underpinning the biological computers
I'm trying to create.
I'm going to call them the Magi.
Magi? The three wise men from the East?
-Is that what you wanted to show me?
-No.
This way, please.
Ritsuko, we'll be right back.
What on earth...
Surely you didn't bring that giant here!
We Gehirn members refer to
that object as "Adam."
This isn't the giant.
It's not the original.
-So this is...
-Yes.
This is Eva, created by man from Adam.
Eva?
This is the prototype of the Adam
Rebirth Project, also called Project-E.
Eva-00.
The prototype of a god?
Fuyutsuki, will you join me in forging
a new history for mankind?
2015 A.D.
Um, Senpai?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Let's get Rei re-tested right away.
I haven't seen Ms. Katsuragi around today.
Oh, I hadn't noticed.
Ms. Katsuragi?
Yep, Misato Katsuragi!
Pleased to meet'cha!
Mother, I met a girl named
Katsuragi the other day.
People tend to give me a wide berth.
Whenever that happens, it drives home
how much weight your name carries.
But not her. She's totally at ease
around me for some reason.
I learned that she was the sole survivor
of that doomed expedition.
She says she suffered from aphasia,
unable to speak for a while,
but the way she goes on and on now,
it's like she's making up for lost time.
Ritchan, I'm still spending
all my time underground here.
I'm really tired of the boxed
lunches they give us.
The Tokyo-3 project is underway topside
as part of the 2nd Capital
Transfer Project.
Misato was away from school for a while,
and when I made her tell me why,
I couldn't believe it.
She said she'd been in bed
with her boyfriend the whole time.
They had just stayed there in bed
for a whole week.
I feel like I've learned about a side
to her I never knew existed.
She introduced me to him today.
He's handsome, but I'll never get used
to that carefree attitude of his.
Boys have never been your strong suit,
have they, Ritchan?
Maybe being raised by a single mother...
I'm sorry. I was never
a hands-on parent, was I?
I'm awful, I only act like a mother
when it takes no effort.
Act like a mother...
2003 A.D.
HAKONE, LAKE ASHI LEVEE
Another day that's the same as the last.
I can't tell you how much
I miss autumn in this country.
According to the scenario set out
in Seele's Hidden Dead Sea Scrolls,
the Third Impact will occur
some ten years from now.
Two groups exist for the sole purpose
of preventing that final tragedy:
Seele and Gehirn.
It's your views that I'm
in agreement with. Not Seele's.
Professor Fuyutsuki, breaking that seal
to the world is extremely dangerous.
I've given all of my research to Ikari.
This is beyond
what one single person can do.
I have no intention of repeating
my previous behavior.
I've also received subtle warnings.
It looks like they could eliminate me
with no trouble at all.
The rest of us survivors, as well.
It's a simple thing to destroy people.
Even so, there's no reason for you
to be the test subject.
I will ride along the currents.
That's why I'm with Seele.
This is also for Shinji.
2004 A.D.
HAKONE, UNDERGROUND
TESTING FACILITY NO.2
LCL pressure, +0.2.
No destrudo readings in transmitter.
-What is this child doing here?
-That's Director Ikari's son.
Ikari, this isn't a daycare center.
Today is an important day.
Sorry, Professor Fuyutsuki.
I was the one who brought him.
Yui? This is your experiment today.
That's exactly why. I want him to see
that he has a bright future ahead of him.
Those were Ms. Yui's last words.
That freak accident wiped her
from the face of the earth.
Just as I had hoped.
I'm a terrible woman, aren't I?
Ritchan, Director Ikari was
a changed man after that day.
Where have you been all week?
Grieve all you want, but remember that you
have responsibilities beyond yourself now.
I'm well aware. Fuyutsuki,
I'm proposing a new project today.
I've already submitted it
to Chairman Keel.
Surely you don't mean...
I do. The path to attain godhood,
which no one has ever achieved.
The Human Instrumentality Project.
2008 A.D.
Mother, congratulations on completing
the basic theories for the Magi.
I've been informally accepted into Gehirn.
I'm set to work as part of
Project-E starting next month.
Who's there?
Ritsuko Akagi, Technology
Development Department. My ID.
I heard that the Command Center has
been framed out, so I came to see it.
It's a real maze here, though.
The Director is there
with Dr. Akagi right now.
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
I have no regrets about my work.
Liar. You can't let go of Ms. Yui.
But I can live with that.
2010 A.D.
GEO-FRONT ARTIFICIAL CANOPY
VENTRAL POINT DEFENSE EMPLACEMENT NO.2
(PLANNED SITE)
That's Gehirn HQ.
Good morning, Director.
You have your son with you today?
Oh, I thought you had a boy.
This isn't Shinji.
I'm looking after a friend's daughter.
Her name is Rei Ayanami.
Hi there, Rei.
She reminds me of someone...
Ms. Yui?
All files pertaining to Rei Ayanami
have been deleted.
She's a blank slate. What's going on?
SUPERCOMPUTER MAGI SYSTEM
COMPLETED
Magus Casper, Magus Balthasar,
and Magus Melchior.
The Magi are the three sides of me.
Me as a scientist.
Me as a mother. Me as a woman.
Those three sides are constantly
vying for control.
Three of you, Mother...
All that's left is to power it on.
I'm leaving early today.
Misato is coming back.
Oh, right. She's also
joined Gehirn, hasn't she?
In Germany, right?
Yes, she works at the Third Branch.
-A long-distance relationship, then?
-She says they broke up.
Oh? That's too bad.
They seemed like the perfect couple.
Men and women are hard to figure out.
There's no logic to it.
Ever the aloof ice queen, I see.
Careful, happiness is going
to pass you by.
I have even more trouble with
how to define happiness.
I should go. It's been forever
since I went out for a drink.
-Good work today.
-You, too.
Can I help you, Rei?
I got lost.
Oh, really? Well, do you want me
to show you the way out?
No.
But you can't find your way out
by yourself, right?
I don't need your help, you hag.
What?
I can find my own way out,
so leave me alone, you hag.
Calling someone a hag is very rude.
But you are one, aren't you?
You're making me angry.
You need a scolding from Director Ikari.
-He's the one who says that about you.
-What?
Things like, "That old hag is such a nag."
Or, "I don't need that hag anymore."
"That hag is such a nag."
"I don't need that hag anymore."
He's the one who says that.
Even if you die, there will be another
to take your place, Rei...
Just like me.
On that day, the Human Instrumentality
Project, chaired by Keel Lorenz,
dissolved Gehirn,
its research organization.
The Special Agency Nerv was founded
as the execution organization
for all of its projects.
And then we were all
transferred over to Nerv.
Except for Dr. Akagi,
the key figure behind the development
of the Magi System.
2015 A.D.
Well, let's get to it.
-Oh, it's you.
-It's been a while, sir.
The guard outside is getting
a little shut-eye.
Doing this will mean your neck.
I just want to get closer to the truth.
The truth inside me.
Plus, they're about to figure out
that I was the one
who snuck the Adam sample
to the Commander.
If I don't take steps to endear myself,
things could get hairy for me.
From various quarters.
Thank you for your cooperation.
-I'm free to go?
-Yes. The issue has been resolved.
I see.
-And him?
-Unknown, ma'am.
Hi. What took you so long?
I'm home.
MESSAGE
PLAY MESSAGES
Hi, Katsuragi. It's me.
By the time you get this message,
I've probably made life difficult for you.
Sorry about that.
And apologize to Ritchan for me, okay?
I shouldn't be asking favors,
but I've been growing some flowers.
If you could water them for me,
I'd appreciate it.
Shinji knows where they are.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Keep going and don't look back.
If I see you again...
I'll say the words that I couldn't
say to you eight years ago.
Bye.
Message left at 12:02 p.m.
You idiot...
You're such an idiot...
All I could do was hide from Misato.
I knew there was nothing I could do.
Nothing I could say.
I was just a child.
TO BE CONTINUED
NEXT EPISODE
Asuka is in a mental downward spiral
over being one-upped by Shinji.
Wasted energy in the form of impatience
only results in exhaustion
and frustration.
And then a mental attack
unleashed by an Angel
delivers the final blow to her heart.
Asuka loses her only means
of bouncing back.
The harshness of reality
wears down everyone's hearts.
Shinji has no words
with which to console her.
Next episode, "Staying Human".
Translator: Dan Kanemitsu
Subtitle Editor: David Fleming