Like a cruel angel
Become a legend, young boy
When a blue wind
Knocks on the door to your heart
You just gaze back at me
And smile oh so gently
So eager for something
You touch so softly
Those innocent eyes
Know nothing of the fate that awaits
But one day, you will realize
That upon your back
You have wings
You can fly to the faraway future
The cruel angel's thesis
One day, you'll take off through a window
If your overflowing pathos
Leads you to betray your memories
Then embrace the heavens and shine bright
Become legend, young boy
It's my lucky day!
I never thought you would
come shopping with me, Mr. Kaji!
Hey, now... This is the swimsuit section!
Look at this one! What do you think?
I'm not so sure. Isn't that a little
risqué for a junior high schooler?
You're so behind the times! No one
bats an eye at suits like this nowadays!
Oh. Is that the case?
This is our big school trip!
We have to cut loose and have fun!
Where are you going?
Okinawa!
The itinerary even has
scuba diving listed!
Scuba diving, huh?
It must be three years
since I last went diving.
So, where did you go for your school trip?
Oh, us? We didn't have one.
Why not?
The Second Impact had just happened.
We can't go on the school trip?!
-Nope.
-Why not?
-You have to be on standby.
-Nobody said anything about that!
-I just did.
-Who made that decision?
I did, as your operations director.
You! Stop sipping that tea
and stand up for us!
Be a man, damn it!
Actually, I figured that something
like this would probably happen.
Meaning you had already written it off?
You're so pathetic. There's nothing
worse than a domesticated man!
Come on, don't put it like that.
I can sympathize, Asuka.
But this is out of our hands.
There might be an Angel attack
while you're away on your trip, right?
Day after day, it's always the same!
Standby, standby, standby, standby!
We're always on the defensive against
an enemy that could attack at any time!
Why don't we figure out where they are
and take the fight to them for once?!
Trust me, we would if we could.
Besides, you two should think of this
as a great opportunity.
You'll be able to focus on your studies
while your classmates are away, right?
Did you think I didn't know?
Did you really think you could
hide your test results from me?
I can easily find out every last score
you got on your tests at school.
They're so idiotic. Test scores
and grades don't mean anything!
A system that penalizes errors instead
of rewarding brains is so unenlightened!
When in Rome, do as the Romans do.
I need you to get adjusted
to school life in Japan.
Screw that!
Asuka, I'll bring you
some great souvenirs!
Aw! Tough luck, you guys!
We'll have enough fun for the both of you!
Paste a copy of the Mt. Asama
observational data
from Balthasar to Melchior
as soon as possible.
A school trip? That's a frivolous
distraction in these trying times.
They want to have fun while they can
for precisely that reason.
What are you doing?
Studying for science class.
Geez, you're such a goody two-shoes.
Make fun of me if you want,
but I need to do this.
Ta-dah!
Since I can't scuba dive in Okinawa,
I'm gonna dive right here!
Um, okay.
So, what are you reviewing?
Let me have a look.
What, you can't solve
an easy equation like this?
There, all done. It's simple!
How come you can do this tough stuff,
but you flunk our tests at school?
I couldn't figure out
what the test sheets said.
You mean you couldn't read the questions
that were written in Japanese?
Yup. I haven't learned
all of your kanji characters yet.
I didn't learn them in college back home.
-College?
-Yeah, I graduated last year.
So, what does this one say?
It's about thermal expansion.
Thermal expansion?
Wow, you're reviewing elementary stuff.
Long story short,
stuff expands when it gets hot
and shrinks when it gets cold.
Yeah, I suppose so...
I wonder if my boobs would
get bigger if I warmed them up.
Don't ask me! How should I know?
You're one seriously boring guy.
Hey, Shinji! Check this out!
Back-roll entry!
It's impossible to make anything out.
But I concur with the Mt. Asama
Earthquake Research Institute.
This shadow is troubling.
We can't dismiss it, of course.
-What was the Magi's assessment?
-Fifty-fifty, ma'am.
-Is anyone on-site?
-Capt. Katsuragi is already there.
We're at its limit!
No, give me another 500.
Depth, 1,200. Cracks appearing
in pressure bulkhead.
Ms. Katsuragi!
If it breaks, we'll reimburse you.
Give me another 200.
Sensor readings!
-Begin analysis.
-Yes, ma'am.
Probe has imploded due to pressure.
Did you finish?
Just barely. It's Pattern Blue.
Then we know for sure. It's an Angel.
This facility is hereby sequestered!
It is now under Nerv jurisdiction!
No one is allowed in or out,
and all information pertaining to
the last six hours is now top secret!
Request approval for an A-17
from Cdr. Ikari! On the double!
Be careful, ma'am.
This line is not secure.
I know that!
Hurry up and switch me over
to a secure line!
A-17?! We're going on the offensive?
Correct.
It's too dangerous. Don't pretend you've
forgotten what happened 15 years ago.
This is a golden opportunity.
We can finally take the fight to them,
rather than remain on the defensive.
The risk is too great.
This is a living Angel specimen.
I needn't stress the significance of that.
Failure will not be tolerated.
Failure? Failure would mean
the extinction of humanity.
Are you sure this is wise?
-That's an Angel?
-Yes.
It seems to be in a pupal stage,
an undeveloped state prior to maturity.
The top priority of this mission
is to capture this Angel.
You are to recover it alive,
with as little damage as possible.
And if we can't?
-Immediate destruction. Understood?
-Yes, ma'am.
-This operation's pilot will be--
-Me, me! I'll do the dive!
I'll probably get stuck
doing it again anyway.
Asuka.
-Carry out the operation in Unit 02.
-Yes, ma'am!
-This will be a piece of cake!
-What about me?
Unit 00 is a prototype, so it's
incompatible with special equipment.
Rei, you and Unit 00
will stay at HQ on standby.
Yes, ma'am.
Gee, that's too bad! You won't be able
to go to the hot springs with us!
The A-17 is already in effect,
so we need to get to work right away.
-Go suit up.
-Yes, ma'am.
This is supposed to be heat resistant,
but it doesn't seem any different.
Press the button on the right cuff.
No!
What the hell is this?!
Unit 02 is suited up, too.
No!
What is it wearing?!
Gear that protects against heat,
pressure, and radiation.
Type D configuration,
meant for localized warfare.
That's my... That's my Unit 02?
No way! I'm out!
I can't be seen in public like this!
Embarrassment is Shinji's thing,
so let him do it!
I'm sorry to hear that.
I was hoping to see you in action, Asuka.
No!
I don't have the guts to let you
see me dressed like this, Mr. Kaji!
-This is a problem.
-It certainly is.
Um, I'll--
I'll go in Unit 02.
I don't want you laying a finger
on my Unit 02! Sorry, girl!
If it means stopping the First, I'll go.
I know you look terrible,
but hang in there, okay?
Eva-01 and 02 have arrived.
Stand by for further instructions.
Expedite the laser firing
and the crane preparations.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey, where's Mr. Kaji?
That idiot won't be here.
There's nothing for him to do.
Crud, and here I was hoping
to show off in front of him.
An A-17 declaration, huh?
That allows for the freezing
of available assets.
That will ruffle the feathers
of a lot of people, I think.
Why didn't you stop them?
There was no reason to.
The order was issued legitimately.
Failure on Nerv's part will spell
the destruction of the world.
They're not that arrogant.
What are those planes?
The UN Air Force
is on standby alert above us.
Until this operation ends.
They're here to help?
-No, to clean up the mess.
-If we fail, that is.
Meaning what, exactly?
They'll incinerate the Angel using
N2 mines. And us along with it.
That's horrible!
Who would give an order like that?
Commander Ikari.
-Laser firing complete.
-Ingress route clear.
Type D gear is good to go.
Unit 02 is in launch position.
Roger that.
-Asuka, are you ready?
-Ready whenever you are.
Launch!
Wow, that looks hot!
Unit 02 about to enter magma.
Hey, check this out, Shinji!
Giant strong entry!
Depth, 170. Rate of descent, 20.
All systems show green.
Visibility, zero.
I can't make anything out.
Switching to CT monitor.
Even with this,
visibility is still only 120.
Depth, 400. Four hundred and fifty.
Five hundred. Five hundred and fifty.
Six hundred. Six hundred and fifty.
Nine hundred. Nine hundred and fifty.
One thousand. One thousand and twenty.
Exceeding design depth!
Depth, 1,300.
Now at predicted target location.
Asuka, can you see anything?
I'm not reading anything. It's not here.
The convection current must be
stronger than expected.
There's a deviation in
the target's movement speed.
Recalculate it ASAP.
Continue operation.
Resume descent, please.
Depth, 1,350. Fourteen hundred.
Cracks appearing in conduit pipe no. 2.
Depth, 1,480!
We've exceeded operating depth!
We still haven't made contact
with the target.
Keep going.
-What's your status, Asuka?
-Still good for now.
I want to wrap this up
and hit the showers!
I know a good hot spring near here.
Let's go there after we're done.
Keep at it just a little more.
Operating depth +120!
Eva-02 has lost Prog Knife.
Operating depth +200!
Ms. Katsuragi, we can't keep this up!
This isn't an unmanned probe!
I'm in command of this operation.
Please keep going.
Misato is right.
Don't worry, I'm still good to go.
Depth, 1,780. Now at revised
estimated target position.
There it is!
-We have visual confirmation of target.
-Prepare for capture.
You're both being swept along
by convection currents,
so you'll only have one shot at this.
I know. Leave it to me.
T minus 30 to target contact!
Relative speed, 2.2.
Our trajectories are matched.
Super EM photon screen engaged.
Systems green.
Target captured!
Nice one, Asuka!
Capture operation complete.
Will now begin ascent.
-Asuka, are you okay?
-Of course I am!
Like they say,
"The fear is greater than the danger."
Didn't I say this would be easy?
Damn, this is more like
a sauna suit than a plug suit!
I want to jump into a hot spring so bad.
She sure got over
her case of nerves quickly.
-Oh?
-This operation also had you worried.
A little.
If we had failed, we would have had
another one on our hands.
You're right... Another Second Impact.
One was more than enough.
What's it doing?!
Oh, no! It's starting to hatch!
This is sooner than we predicted!
-What about the cage?
-It won't hold!
Abort the capture! Drop the cage!
Change operation! Top priority
is now destruction of the Angel!
Unit 02, prepare for combat
and be ready for withdrawal!
Music to my ears!
I forgot! I dropped my knife!
It's coming at me!
Releasing ballast!
It's fast!
This is bad news... I've lost the target.
Plus, visibility is bad.
It's damn hot in here,
and my sweat is making this suit
all clingy and gross!
-Can this get any worse?
-Asuka!
Unit 01 is going to toss
its knife to you! Catch it!
Roger!
Oh, crap! Where's that knife, Shinji?!
Knife arrival in 40.
Angel closing in fast!
No! Stay away!
Hurry up, damn it!
It's taking too long!
Damn it!
I can't believe it!
It opened its mouth down there!
Its physiology is incredible.
-Damage to left leg!
-Isolating heat intrusion!
Damn you to hell!
It's adapted to this high-heat
and high-pressure environment.
-That Prog Knife is useless.
-What can we do, then?!
-I've got it!
-That science problem!
Chew on this!
I see what she's doing! Thermal expansion!
Divert all coolant pressure
to conduit no. 3! Hurry!
No fair, I killed the thing...
This sucks. Is this the end of the line?
Shinji?
Dummy. You're really pressing your luck.
OUMIYA
Hello?
Is there anybody from Nerv here?
Coming!
COLD-SHIP PACKAGE
Sign here, please.
Here you go. Thanks!
It's from Mr. Kaji? I wonder what it is.
The bath is down the hall, on the left.
GENTLEMEN
I'm in Heaven...
I never knew a bath could feel this great.
Shinji? Can you hear me?
-Yes, ma'am?
-Could you toss us your body shampoo?
-We ran out over here!
-Sure!
-Here it comes!
-Ready!
Ow! Idiot!
Watch where you're aiming, you klutz!
Sorry.
I can't believe he hit me there!
Huh? Where?
Wow, Asuka!
Your skin is so soft and supple!
Hey, don't! I'm ticklish there!
Oh? How about here?
Hey, don't touch me there!
Oh, don't be such a baby!
I expanded down there...
Talk about embarrassing.
Oh, this? I got hurt during
the Second Impact.
You know, don't you? All about me.
Well, it's my job.
That's ancient history.
Don't let it bother you.
TO BE CONTINUED
NEXT EPISODE
Someone who resents Nerv
cuts all power to Tokyo-3.
While Nerv HQ can't use any of its
modern equipment, an Angel attacks.
Next episode! "In the Still Darkness"!
Tune in next time
for lots more fan service!
Translator: Dan Kanemitsu
Subtitle Editor: David Fleming