Like a cruel angel
Become a legend, young boy
When a blue wind
Knocks on the door to your heart
You just gaze back at me
And smile oh so gently
So eager for something
You touch so softly
Those innocent eyes
Know nothing of the fate that awaits
But one day, you will realize
That upon your back
You have wings
You can fly to the faraway future
The cruel angel's thesis
One day, you'll take off through a window
If your overflowing pathos
Leads you to betray your memories
Then embrace the heavens and shine bright
Become legend, young boy
Good morning, Shinji. How are you feeling?
I'm used to it. It's not so bad now.
Glad to hear it.
Eva egress points, emergency
ordnance structures, recovery points...
-Do you have them all memorized?
-I think so.
Let's go over it one more time, then.
An Eva usually runs off an external,
cabled power feed.
When it switches to internal battery
in an emergency,
capacity limitations mean
it can only run at full for one minute.
It can run for five minutes at most
by using a low gain mode.
That's as far as our science can go.
Understood?
Yes, ma'am.
Then we'll pick up from yesterday.
Starting induction mode.
Center the target... and pull the trigger.
Keep calm. Center the target.
Pull the trigger...
Next!
I'm amazed that Shinji was willing
to go through with this.
He does whatever he's told.
That's how he makes his life easier.
Center the target, pull the trigger.
And now we go to Matsuzaki,
where Natsuko Shinohara is waiting!
Hello! Good morning! Shinohara here!
This morning, we're here to do
some diving at Matsuzaki in West Izu!
Ms. Misato? It's morning.
I just got off duty...
I just need to show up
before sunset today, so let me sleep...
Well, I need to go.
Right, today's Thursday!
Take out the burnable garbage, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
Have you gotten settled in at school?
Okay... Have a nice day.
I'm off, then.
Hello?
Oh, it's you, Ritsuko.
So, are things working out
with the new boyfriend?
Boyfriend? Oh, you mean Shinji.
It's been two weeks since
he started school, and nothing.
Nobody ever calls him.
Calls him?
It's a necessity, so I got him
a cell phone a while ago.
But there's no sign of him ever using it
or anyone ever calling him.
I'm starting to think
he doesn't have any friends.
Shinji might be the sort of person
who can't make friends easily.
Have you ever heard of
the Hedgehog's Dilemma?
Hedgehog? Those spiky animals?
Hedgehogs have a hard time sharing
warmth with other hedgehogs.
The closer they get, the more
they hurt each other with their quills.
People are also like that.
I think some part of Shinji
is afraid to take that risk
because he's afraid of being hurt.
He'll figure it out eventually.
Part of growing up is trying again
and again and using trial and error
to work out the right distance
to avoid hurting each other.
What is it, Class Rep?
Did you deliver all those
study guides like I asked?
Oh, um... Yeah.
Actually, it doesn't seem like
anyone's home at Tohji's place.
You and Suzuhara are friends,
aren't you, Aida?
Aren't you worried that he's
missed school for two weeks?
Maybe he got hurt badly or something.
In that incident with the giant robot?
But the TV said no one got hurt.
No way. You saw the crater
at Mt. Takanosu.
Units were called up from
not only Iruma and Komatsu,
but even from Misawa and Kyushu.
There must have been way more than ten
or 20 casualties. Some fatalities, too.
-Tohji!
-Suzuhara!
Well, damn.
There sure are a lot fewer of us.
They evacuated. They all transferred out.
That's what happens when there's
a huge battle in the middle of your city.
I bet you're the only guy that loves this.
Getting to see a firefight up close.
I guess.
So, what's up, Tohji? Why did you
stay home from school for so long?
Did you get mixed up in that mess?
My kid sister...
My kid sister got buried
under a pile of rubble.
She survived, but she's been
in the hospital ever since.
My old man and uncle
work at the labs, remember?
They can't tear themselves away
from work right now.
So if I don't stay with her,
she'd be all alone in the hospital.
I swear, the pilot of that damn robot
is totally worthless!
He pisses me off so bad!
He's supposed to be on our side,
and he trashed the city!
About that. Have you heard the rumors
about the new transfer student?
Transfer student?
That kid over there.
He transferred in while you were gone.
He showed up right after the battle.
Don't you think that's fishy?
All rise!
And so, this is how humanity
was faced with its greatest ordeal.
In the closing year of the 20th Century,
a meteor of extraordinarily high mass
made impact on Antarctica.
That continent of ice
was melted in an instant.
Sea levels rose,
the planet's axis shifted,
and abnormal weather assaulted the globe,
threatening all life on Earth.
Half of mankind,
along with thousands of species,
were forever lost.
This is what we now refer to
as the Second Impact.
Economic collapse,
ethnic conflicts, and civil wars.
Those who survived
experienced hell on earth.
ARE YOU REALLY THE PILOT OF THAT ROBOT?
In fifteen short years, we have
bounced back and rebuilt so much.
While this is surely...
IT'S TRUE, ISN'T IT?
...a testament to
the greatness of mankind,
it is also the result of the blood,
sweat, tears, and hard work
of your fathers and mothers.
I was living in Nebukawa at the time.
But that's now underwater...
Come on! Class isn't over yet!
Sit down!
There you go,
bossing everyone around again!
-Give it a rest!
-I will not!
-Wow!
-Um...
-So, how were you chosen?!
-Was there a test or something?
-Weren't you scared?
-What's the cockpit like?
Um, well... All that stuff is secret.
-Aw, don't hold out on us!
-What's the name of that robot?
I don't know for sure, but everyone
calls mine "Eva" or "Unit 01."
Any special attacks?
They said it has something called a...
a "something" Knife...
It uses vibration to...
No, ultrasound or something...
This is so cool!
You're the pride of our school!
That's so awesome!
And that brings us to--
-That's all for today.
-Where do you live, Ikari?
All rise! Bow!
Hey, at least try to be polite
at the end of class, everyone!
Sorry, newbie. But I have to punch you.
I couldn't live with myself otherwise.
Sorry, buddy.
His little sister got hurt in that battle.
That's just how he is.
It's not like I pilot that thing
because I want to.
Emergency call-up. I'll meet you there.
A special state of emergency has
been declared for the Toukai region
and the surrounding mid-Kanto area.
All residents, proceed to your
designated shelter immediately.
I repeat...
Visual confirmation of target.
Has entered territorial waters.
All personnel to
condition one battle stations.
Roger! Prepare for
surface-to-air intercept!
Initiating deployment of Tokyo-3
into combat configuration.
Retracting central block structures.
Retraction of central block structures,
as well as Wards 1 through 7,
now complete.
Government and appropriate agencies
have been notified.
Air defense systems currently
operating at 48% capacity.
Status of noncombatants and civilians?
Evacuation has been reported as completed.
TOKYO-3 DISASTER PREVENTION DIV.
AREA: 2000m2, MAX OCCUPANCY: 250
Students in grades 1-9,
stay with your class.
Residents, remain with other
residents of your block.
Damn, again?
Nothing but text again, huh?
It's a press blackout.
They're keeping us civilians in the dark.
Damn it,
this is a once-in-a-lifetime deal!
The 4th Angel strikes
while Commander Ikari is away.
It's sooner than we thought.
Last time was after a 15-year gap.
This time, only three weeks went by.
Not very considerate of others, are they?
Women hate people like that.
What a waste of taxpayer money.
The Council is requesting
that we launch an Evangelion again.
Bunch of pushy jerks.
We were going to do that anyway.
Entry sequence has started.
-Ionizing LCL.
-Pressure clamps unlocked.
Father isn't here to watch,
so why am I doing this again?
I was even beaten up because of it...
Hey, I need to talk to you
about something.
Shoot.
In private.
All right, all right...
-Hey, Class Rep.
-Yes?
We need to take a leak!
Oh, come on! You should have
done that before we came here!
Okay, what's up?
I have to see one before I die, just once.
What? That fight up top?
There's no way to know when or if
the enemy will come again.
Kensuke, you're a real piece of work.
Sir! This might be
our only opportunity, sir!
So, please, help me unlock the door!
-Going outside might get you killed!
-The same thing might happen in here.
If I might die either way,
I want to see what's going on.
You dumbass. Nerv's there to stop that.
Exactly, and what is Nerv's
decisive battle weapon?
It's the new kid's robot!
He protected us in the last battle.
And then you had to deck him.
Twice.
We'll all be dead
if he doesn't get in and pilot it again.
Tohji, isn't it your duty
to watch him fight?
Fine, fine.
You're a real slave to
your passions, aren't you?
Shinji, are you ready for launch?
Yes, ma'am.
Remember. Pallet rifle volley fire as
you neutralize the enemy's A.T. Field.
Just like we practiced. Can you handle it?
Yes, ma'am.
Launch!
Wow, it was worth all the trouble!
And here we go!
There he is!
-A.T. Field raised.
-Center the target...
-Proceed according to plan. Okay, Shinji?
-Pull the trigger...
Yes, ma'am.
That idiot! That smoke and dust
is obscuring the target!
What the hell?
He's getting his ass kicked already!
Don't worry.
We're putting out a spare rifle!
Grab it!
Shinji? Shinji!
Oh, man...
That beatdown
must have really rattled him.
Screw you!
Umbilical cable severed!
Eva has switched to internal power!
Active time remaining,
four minutes, 53 seconds!
It's headed right for us!
Shinji, are you okay? Shinji?!
-Damage report!
-None. He's good to go.
-Shinji's classmates?!
-What are they doing there?!
Why isn't he fighting back?!
Is it because we're here?
His hands are tied!
Unit 01 active time remaining,
three minutes, 28 seconds!
Shinji, let those two into your cockpit!
After you've retrieved them, retreat!
We'll start over!
Do you think you can allow unauthorized
civilians into that entry plug?!
I'm authorizing them.
You're overstepping your authority,
Capt. Katsuragi.
Unit 01 active time remaining,
three minutes.
Mission on hold under standing orders.
Eject the entry plug in the meantime.
You two, get in! Hurry!
What is this, water?
My camera! My camera!
Abnormalities in nerve circuits!
There are two foreign bodies
in the entry plug.
There's noise mixed in
with the nerve pulses.
Now! Retreat!
-Use recovery route 34. Pull back to...
-Hey, newbie! She said to retreat!
-Don't run away. Don't run away.
-Newbie!
Don't run away!
Progressive Knife equipped!
Shinji, obey my order! I said to retreat!
Shinji!
That idiot!
Unit 01 active time remaining, 30 seconds!
Twenty-eight!
Twenty-seven! Twenty-six!
Twenty-five!
Fourteen! Thirteen!
Twelve! Eleven!
Ten! Nine!
Eight! Seven!
Six! Five!
Four! Three!
Two! One!
Eva-01 has ceased operation.
Target is completely inactive.
It's been three days now.
Since they read us the riot act?
Since he stopped coming to school.
Who?
The transfer student, who else?
-I wonder what he's up to.
-You worried about him?
Who said I was worried?
It's because you're so bull-headed
in spite of being so socially awkward.
If you had apologized
the last time we saw him,
you wouldn't have spent
three whole days agonizing over it.
Here. This is the new kid's phone number.
If you're worried, call him.
TO BE CONTINUED
Unable to get a handle on his feelings,
Shinji runs away from even Misato.
However, the organization
unceremoniously drags him back.
No one there had any kind words for him.
Next episode! "Rain, After Running Away"!
Tune in next time
for lots more fan service!
Translator: Dan Kanemitsu
Subtitle Editor: David Fleming