Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
In the year 2015 AD
The Third Angel
Sachiel’s Attack
Conventional weapons
were found to have no effect
on the Angel.
The UN force, having failed to
accomplish their task...
...transferred command to the
special organization “NERV.”
At midnight of the same day,
the Angel arrived above
NERV Headquarters.
Also on the same day,
this individual was acquired.
The Third Child
Shinji Ikari
He was accepted as pilot for...
...Evangelion Unit 01, and
sortied in its first engagement.
NERV thereby experienced
its first combat.
The First Battle of
Tokyo-3
Eva Unit 01 sustained damage
to its head component and
went out of control.
There was complete silence.
Then...
...it went berserk!
Although there was a great deal of
damage as a result...
The Third Angel and Unit 01...
...the fact that a boy with no prior
experience completed a mission against
an unknown enemy...
...were both observed
generating an AT Field.
...makes Shinji Ikari deserving of
special notice.
Unit 01 penetrated the
enemy’s AT Field.
However, for the Department of
Strategic Operations, it was a battle
that revealed many problems.
The Angel was destroyed.
The Intercept Facility was
slightly damaged.  Eva Unit 01
received moderate damage.
The number of victims
incurred during this incident
was not made public.
My sister’s only in the 2nd grade.
She got hurt in that stupid disturbance,
and she was hurt by our own stupid
robot, not by the enemy.
There’s no way I can forgive anyone
who did something so stupid.
I’m going to let them feel my anger
and teach the jerks who hurt my
sister a lesson.
The Fourth Angel
Shamshel’s Attack
The performance ratio of the
surface-to-air intercept
system was 48.2%.
The operation ratio of the Tokyo-3 battle formation was 96.8%.
We’d already had a lot of evacuation
training at the school, so we didn’t really
think it was so serious.
All the guys were acting like jerks, like
they were on a field trip, and none of
the girls were afraid either.
The Angel arrived above Tokyo-3.
The Second Battle
of Tokyo-3
Although the power supply
cable was accidentally cut...
...Eva successfully defeated
the Angel.
NERV acquired a completely
intact Angel specimen.
As of yet, however, no final report or analysis has been submitted or published.
The Fifth Angel
Ramiel’s Attack
To combat this nearly
impregnable enemy...
...Captain Katsuragi proposed Operation Yashima, for which she received approval.
The First Child
She received her first combat
experience in the rehabilitated
Eva Unit 00.
At midnight of the same day,
part of the Angel penetrated
into the Geo-Front.
NERV carried out
Operation Yashima.
Ikari didn’t actually tell me anything,
so this is just a guess on my part.
I think Ayanami tried to sacrifice herself
to protect Unit 01 from the enemy’s
particle beam attack.
I’m really sure about this,
and the reason I’m so positive
is Ayanami herself.
I think that Ayanami really doesn’t have
a great deal of respect for the value
of her own existence.
Operation Yashima
was successfully completed.
It’s not just that she’s more
pessimistic than normal 14-year-olds,
it’s something much, much more.
Eva Unit 00 sustained
heavy damage.
However, its pilot returned alive.
The Sixth Angel
Gaghiel’s Attack
This did not occur in accordance
with our scenario.
Nevertheless, the result was within the
projected parameters.  We can make
the necessary adjustments.
The Second Child
The first engagement in
Eva Unit 02...
...involved hand-to-hand combat
over the open sea...
...and...
...the first underwater sortie.
The encounter took place in the region of the former Ito Peninsula.
The Angel was destroyed.
The UN Navy lost a third of its
entire fleet in this encounter.
The lost ships belonged to your country.
The damage is negligible.
True, it was quite fortunate that so much
of the damage was inconsequential.
The Seventh Angel
Israfel’s Attack
This was the first Angel encountered to possess
the ability to separate and recombine parts of its body.
Eva Units 01 and 02 utilized a
simultaneous, synchronized
attack...
...and the Angel was destroyed.
The Eighth Angel
Sandalphon was detected in the volcanic crater of Mt. Asama.
NERV ordered a
Special Command A-17.
The capture operation was
performed under top priority
conditions.
The target was trapped within
an electromagnetic barrier,
but...
...the cage was destroyed and
the operation was aborted.
Immediately, the objective of
the operation was altered to
destruction of the Angel.
Eva Unit 02 accomplished
the operation.
The Angel was destroyed.
Repair and upgrades on
Eva Unit 00 were completed.
The Eva was returned to
operational status.
The Ninth Angel
Matarael’s Attack
This was the first simultaneous
operation of all three Eva units.
The Angel was destroyed.
The Tenth Angel
Sahaquiel’s Attack
The enemy dropped onto targets directly from the stratosphere.
All three Eva units
intercepted the target.
The Angel was destroyed.
The Eleventh Angel
There is a rumor that this Angel
penetrated into NERV HQ.
However, this Angel’s existence has not yet been confirmed as fact.
This is no good.
Human Instrumentality Project
Special Conference
It’s happening too early.
That’s true.  This did not occur in
accordance with our predictions of
when an Angel would invade NERV.
And to make it worse, you let it intrude
into Central Dogma itself!
If contact had occurred then, our entire
project could have ended in disaster.
The report to this committee was in error.
There is no truth behind this tale
of an Angel invasion.
Are you saying that the Eleventh Angel’s
intrusion did not occur, Ikari?
Correct.
Speak with caution, Ikari.
Making false statements to this
conference is punishable by death.
Check the MAGI’s recorders.
Nothing concerning such an incident
was recorded.
This is absurd.
Hiding the truth is your specialty.
The time schedule is being carried out in
accordance with the details prescribed
by the Dead Sea Scrolls.
All right.  We won’t discuss any possible
guilt or punishment at this time.
But let me remind you that you won’t
create a new scenario.
I understand.  Everything is proceeding
according to SEELE’s plan.
Episode 14:
SEELE, Throne
of Souls
Mountain...
Heavy are the mountains.
But that changes over time.
Sky...
Blue sky.
What your eyes can’t see.
What your eyes can see.
Sun...
There is only one.
Water...
Comforting.
Commander Ikari?
Flower...
So many alike.
So many useless.
Sky...
Red, red sky.
Red is the color.
Red is the color I hate.
Water flowing.
Blood...
The smell of blood.
A woman who never bleeds.
From the red earth comes man,
from the soil.
Born of man and woman is man.
Town...
A human creation.
Eva...
A human creation as well.
What is human?
A creation of God?
Is it a human creation?
The things I possess are
my life and soul.
I am a vessel for my heart.
Entry plug...
The throne of a soul.
Who is this?  This is me.
Who am I?
What am I?  What am I?
I am myself.
This, that which is, is myself.
That which is formed is me.
This is the me that can be seen,
yet it feels as if this is not myself.
A strange feeling.
I feel as if my body is melting.
I can no longer see myself.
My shape is fading.
I feel the presence of someone
who is not me.
Who is there, beyond me here?
Ikari?
I know this person.
She is Major Katsuragi.
Doctor Akagi.
Others.
Classmates.
The pilot of Unit 02.
Commander Ikari?
Who are you?
So, how does it feel to be piloting
Unit 01 for the first time?
It smells like Ikari.
First Compatibility
Experiment
Subject: Rei Ayanami
Her synch ratio is almost the same
as with Unit 00.
Unit 00 and 01’s personal data patterns
are almost identical as well.
That’s what makes this synch
experiment possible.
Error is 0.03.  Harmonics are normal.
No detectable problems found for
compatibility between Rei and Unit 01.
Okay, the experiment is finished, Rei.
You can get out now.
Yes.
87th Joint Operations
Experiment
Subject: Asuka Langley
Data bank for Unit 02 complete.
Harmonics are all normal.
Pilot status: normal.
Of course.
First Compatibility
Experiment
Subject: Shinji Ikari
What about Unit 00’s personal data?
Already reconfigured.
Currently reconfirming it.
Subject status?
He’s a bit nervous, but no problems are
being found in his nerve patterns.
This is his first time in Unit 00...
...and his first time piloting any
other Eva.  That’s natural.
Nonsense, why should he care?
He’s Shinji.
I know it, and that’s why he’s stupid.
Speaking of which, why don’t I have to
take the compatibility experiment?
You don’t want to pilot any
other Evas, do you?
Darn right.
Certainly, Unit 02 wouldn’t
be compatible.
Entry has commenced.
LCL electrolyzed.
Initiating first connection.
Shinji, how do you feel in
Unit 00’s entry plug?
It feels kind of odd.
A sense of incompatibility?
Not like that, but...
...it smells like Rei.
What does that mean?  He’s a pervert!
Data received.  Reconfirming.
Pattern Green.
Main power supply
connection complete.
All restraints are normal.
Acknowledged.
Now let’s shift the mutual compatibility
tests to the second stage.
Unit 00 will enter into second contact.
How is it?
As I thought, the synch ratio is
lower than that of Unit 01.
Harmonics are all normal.
But these are still good readings.
This means that we can
accomplish the plan.
The dummy system, you mean?
I disagree...
I understand your feelings on this,
but we always have to be prepared in
order to guarantee survival.
I highly respect you, ma’am, and I will
do my duty, but I am not convinced
about this project.
People with a fastidious nature will
always feel some difficulty living
amongst others.
Once you’ve been sullied, you’ll
regretfully find the truth in this.
Initiating third connection.
Self state of psychograph is stable.
Hey, Shinji, what’s it like?
Mom’s breast?  Or inside her womb?
Asuka, stop interrupting.
The noise can penetrate.
Yes, ma’am.
Why do they spoil Shinji?
Commence linkage of
A-10 nerve connections.
Harmonics level up 20.
What is this?  Something’s trying
to get into my brain...
A...Ayanami?
Rei Ayanami?
This impression is Rei, isn’t it?
Ayanami?
Isn’t it her?
What is it?
We’ve got a problem occurring in
the pilot’s nerve pulse!
Mental contamination is taking place!
Impossible!  This can’t happen
at this plug depth.
It’s not from the plug!
The intrusion’s coming from the Eva!
Unit 00 is out of control!
Shut off all circuits!
Cut the power supply!
Eva has switched to backup power.
The Eva is still active!
How’s Shinji?
The circuit is closed!
We can’t monitor him!
Unit 00 is rejecting Shinji?!
Negative!  The auto ejection’s not working!
The same thing as before?
Is it going to try to absorb Shinji?
Rei, get back!!
Activation will be terminated in 10...
Rei!
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Zero!
Unit 00 has ceased activation.
Hurry up and rescue the pilot!!
I don’t believe this!
Did Unit 00 just try to kill Rei?
Was this somehow related to the
earlier berserk incident when
Rei was the pilot?
I can’t tell you much right now.
The only thing I’m sure of is that
we must reconfigure Unit 00 for Rei’s
personal data...
...and run a new synchronization
test between them as soon
as possible.
As Director of Strategic Ops, I ask
that you do so as soon as possible,
before it creates more problems.
I understand that, Major Katsuragi.
Unit 00 wanted to attack me.
I’m sure of it.
The next contestant for the
World’s Most Amazing Exhibition is,
Math Puppy!
Wow, that sounds awesome!
Here we go, math genius puppy,
Kana, from Niigata!
Wan!
He sounds good.
Do you understand me?
Wan!
Oh, right.  Now let’s ask him.
What is 325 minus 324?
Wan!
This is amazing!  He’s correct!
Again...  I hate this ceiling.
Wan!
Shinji’s conscious.
No signs of mental contamination.
He doesn’t remember what happened.
I see.
Hi!  I’m fine, but the world is worrisome
due to terrorism in the Nansa Islands.
Misato and Kaji won’t tell me about her...
This year-long heat creates some
crazy bastards, y’know?
...and Shinji doesn’t know anything.
What I can’t stand is that those idiots go
and involve innocent people!
Just what is the First Child?
About that Angel invasion that
deviated from the plan.
The Instrumentality Committee is
applying pressure regarding the facts
of that incident.
They’re just riff-raff who can’t do
anything except complain.
We hold all the tiles.
There is nothing they can do.
But we don’t want to irritate them.
If SEELE starts interfering,
there could be trouble.
Everything has been carried out
as the scenario required.
There is no problem.
What about the Unit 00 incident?
That wasn’t in my scenario.
It will not interfere.
The re-synchronization test for Rei and
Unit 00 was successful.
He’s too concerned about Rei.
What is the status of the Adam Project?
Proceeding without difficulty.  It is less
than two percent behind schedule.
Then, the Lance of Longinus is...
It’s going as we planned.
Rei is carrying out the operation.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
With her friends getting married
one after another, Misato
begins to feel uneasy.
She could end up being a perpetual
wedding shower attendee and never
have anyone for herself.  This stinks!
Her twenties are running out and
her thirties are approaching!
Could a reunion with Kaji
be her last chance?
Next episode: “Lie and Silence.”
And there’ll be lots more
fan service again!
Next Episode:
Lie and Silence