Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
Hi!  I’m not in right now,
so leave your message after the beep!
This may be my last assignment.
This looks like blood.
Episode 21:
The Birth of
NERV
The Vice-Commander was abducted?
Two hours ago.
He was last seen in the 8th District.
That’s inside our installation.
What in the hell were you idiots
in Intelligence doing?
The whole thing was set up by someone
inside our operation.
We were taken by surprise.
Someone who could outwit Section 2?
It couldn’t be him?!
Ryoji Kaji is suspected of being the
mastermind behind this plot.
Then, that’s why you came for me.
We believe that you can
be of use to us, yes.
As your colleagues,
we regret having to consider
the Director of Operations a suspect...
...but that is the nature of our profession.
Considering our relationship,
it’s a natural precaution.
I appreciate your cooperation.
Take her away.
It’s been a while, Chairman Keel.
This is a rather rough reception.
I will not apologize
for necessary discourtesies.
This was necessary in order for us
to speak with you outside of the
Commander’s presence.
You haven’t changed.  You still have no
concern for the circumstances of others.
The subject to be addressed
has become an immediate concern.
Thus, these measures were unavoidable.
Please understand our situation.
What a surprise.
Not the committee, but SEELE itself!
We have no intention of
creating a new god.
We hope that we will have your
cooperation, Professor Fuyutsuki.
Professor Fuyutsuki, is it?
Professor!  Professor Fuyutsuki!
Hello, boys.
Why don’t you join us for a beer
by the Kamo River?
What, again?
Ryoko and the other girls said
they’ll come if you come.
The professor said that you shouldn’t
be so unsociable.
All right, I’ll be there.
It’s nice to have a drink outside
for a change.
Yeah...
You’re very competent,
but you tend to underestimate
the value of relationships with others.
I’m sorry, sir.
Speaking of which, Fuyutsuki...
...there’s a student who wrote
a very interesting research paper
for the bio-engineering class.
Her name is Ikari.  Do you know her?
Ikari?  No, sir.
I’ve told her about you,
and she says she’d like to meet you.
She’ll be calling you soon,
and I’d like you to take her on.
And her name is Ikari?  I understand.
I’ve read your paper.
There are a few things I disagree with,
but it’s really very interesting.
Thank you, sir.
Your name is Yui Ikari, right?
Yes.
What are your career plans?
Corporate research?
Or joining the school research facility?
I haven’t really thought about it.
And there may be a third option.
I’m also thinking about getting married...
...assuming that I meet the right person.
By incorporating the S2 unit into itself,
it has achieved its ultimate form.
Evangelion Unit 01!
A supreme being which we created.
What blasphemy!
The creation of a god is unacceptable.
Man must not create gods.  We cannot
allow him to possess such power!
Can we trust Gendo Ikari?
Gendo Rokubungi?
Well, I have heard the name.
No, I’ve never met him.
However, he does seem to be
at the center of many rumors.
He wants to be released into my custody?
Yes, I’ll come visit him.
What time should I come?
I’ve been hearing some interesting things
about you.  I’ve been wanting to meet you.
You were drunk and got into a fight.
How pathetic.
I didn’t even have a chance to say
anything before they jumped me.
I’m not used to being liked.  Being hated,
on the other hand, is quite familiar.
That’s not my concern.
Professor Fuyutsuki, you are exactly the
kind of person I expected you to be.
My first impression of him was that
he was a total son of a bitch.
Back then, there were still seasons
in this country.  It was autumn.
Are you serious?
Yes, I’m dating Mr. Rokubungi.
When she told me that,
I couldn’t hide my shock.
It’s hard to imagine you walking with him.
Now, Professor Fuyutsuki...
...he’s actually a very sweet person.
It’s just that nobody really knows him.
Sometimes ignorance can be bliss.
I’m the one who first mentioned you
to him.  Does that bother you?
Well, I’ll admit that he’s an interesting
fellow, but I just don’t like him.
Actually, it was generally believed that the
real object of his overtures to Yui...
...was her talent and the support of the
organization that was backing her.
According to the rumors,
that organization was called SEELE.
Second Impact...
...it was in the last year of the 20th century
that this tragedy occurred.
Then, in the first year of the 21st century
there was nothing but hell.
I can’t find any other words
to describe that year.
This used to be a continent of ice?
There’s no sign left of it!
Professor Fuyutsuki...
Is that you?  You survived?
I’d heard that you were with the
Katsuragi research team.
Fortunately, I returned to Japan
the day before the incident.
You don’t say.
Mr. Rokubungi, you...
Excuse me, but I’ve changed my surname.
A postcard?  Not a business card?
Ikari!  Gendo Ikari!
My wife’s been asking me to send this to
you.  She says she’s a fan of yours.
What an honor.
How is Yui doing?
She’s not participating in this expedition?
Yui wanted to come too,
but we have a child now.
Your organization, SEELE or whatever it’s
called, is at the root of many ugly rumors.
I don’t like the way that it manipulates
the committee by force.
You’re still too scrupulous.
No completely chaste organization
can survive in this day and age.
If this official investigation of the Second
Impact was composed solely of SEELE
personnel, there would have been trouble.
So, are we just here for
political convenience?
I still hate the darkness.  All it does is
bring back the most horrible memories.
Who is she?
The only survivor of the research team.
Her name is Misato Katsuragi.
Katsuragi?
Is she Doctor Katsuragi’s daughter?
Yes, she hasn’t said a word in two years.
How terrible...
She saw hell firsthand.
Her physical wounds are healed,
but repairing the damage to
her mind will take time.
That’s true.
The results of our investigation
aren’t easy to analyze.
The origin of this Giant of Light is but one
of many mysteries we have yet to solve.
The Second Impact was caused
by a massive meteorite strike, or so
the United Nations officially declared later.
However, from my point of view...
...the announcement was obviously
a fabrication.
The organization known as SEELE and a
man named Keel were behind this artifice.
It became my goal to find
out the truth about the incident...
...even though I discovered that
Yui Ikari was involved.
Why did you conceal the
existence of the Giant?
You knew that the Second Impact was
going to happen, didn’t you?
You may have said that it was just
luck that you returned the day
before it happened...
...but how do you explain the fact that you
brought back copies of all
the documentation?!
I’m surprised that those weren’t destroyed.
I’ve checked into your finances as well.
Bringing up a child and educating him is
expensive, but isn’t this a bit much?
Very impressive, Professor Fuyutsuki.
Perhaps you should be teaching
economics.
I’m going to go public with the real
truth about the Second Impact, about you,
SEELE and the Dead Sea Scrolls.
I can’t forgive anyone who would have
caused something like that.
As you wish.
However, before you do that,
there’s something I’d like to show you.
We’re getting rather far down, aren’t we?
Are you worried?
A little.
What is this?
We didn’t create it,
someone else excavated this cavity.
89% of its total volume is buried.
Was this originally a giant sphere?
This facility is what has been consuming
the total resources of mankind.
Hi, Professor Fuyutsuki!
Doctor Akagi, you’re here, too?
Yes, this is the ideal place for
our research into creating a functioning
bio-computer system.
I’m going to name them the “MAGI.”
“MAGI”?  The three wise men of the east.
Is this what you wanted to show me?
No, it’s over this way.
Ritsuko, I’ll be back soon.
Is this...
This can’t be THE Giant?
No, here at Gehirn,
we refer to that giant as “Adam”...
...but this isn’t the original one.
Then, this...?
...was created from Adam by man, Eva.
Eva?
Our operation to revive Adam is referred
to as Project E.  This is Eva Unit 00,
our system prototype.
This is a prototype of a god!
Fuyutsuki, let us create a new genesis
for mankind, together.
Hey, boss...
I’m sorry.  Let’s proceed with Rei’s re-test.
Where is Major Katsuragi today?
I don’t know.
Miss Katsuragi?
Yeah, Misato Katsuragi,
pleased to meet you.
Mother, I have just become acquainted
with a girl named Katsuragi.
Most people tend to keep their distance
from me once they find out who I am...
...which forces me to remember how
important your name is around here.
However, Misato is different.
She’s very open and honest, even with me.
I’ve heard that she is the only survivor of
the original research team...
...and that she was once mute.
She talks quite a lot now, almost as if
she’s trying to make up for lost time.
Dear Ritsuko,
I’m always underground these days...
...and I’m getting sick of living on the
box lunches they provide here.
On the surface, they’ve started
construction of Tokyo-3, as directed
by the Second Capitol Transfer Directive.
Misato didn’t show up for classes the last
few days, and I finally forced her to tell
me why.  Talk about stupid!
She’d spent the whole week having
non-stop sex with her new boyfriend!
I think there’s another side to her
I haven’t seen before.
She introduced me to him today.
He’s handsome,
but his unkempt manner bothers me.
You’ve always been a little
boy-shy, Ritsuko dear.
I think it’s because you only had a mother.
And I’m afraid I didn’t take
care of you properly.
I’m ashamed to admit that I only acted like
a mother when it suited my whims.
Like a mother...
Why is there a child in here?!
That’s Director Ikari’s son.
Ikari, this is not a day-care center.
This is a very important day!
I’m sorry, Professor.  I brought him here.
Yui, this is your experiment today.
That’s why I brought him.  I want to show
him how bright the future will be.
Those words would be Yui’s last.
A freak accident wiped her
from this existence.
Just as I had hoped it would.
What a disgusting woman I am.
Ritsuko, after that day, Director Ikari
completely changed.
Where have you been all week?
I understand your grief...
...but you must be aware of your
own importance!
I know.  Fuyutsuki, as of today we
will begin the new project.
I have already made the proposal
to Chairman Keel.
You’re really going to do it?!
Yes, that which has never been achieved
before, the path to becoming a god!
The Human Instrumentality Project.
Mother, congratulations on completing
your “MAGI” theorems.
I have good news which I think
will please you, too.
I have been officially accepted by Gehirn!
I’ll start working on Project E next month.
Who are you?
Technology Development Section,
Ritsuko Akagi.  Here’s my ID.
I heard that the basic installation of
the Command Center had been completed,
so I came to see it.
But it’s a real maze down here, isn’t it?
The Director and Doctor Akagi will
see you in the Command Center.
Are you really all right?
Yes, I have no regrets about my work.
You’re lying!  You still can’t forget
about Yui, can you?!
But that’s acceptable to me.
That’s Gehirn Headquarters.
Good morning, Director.
Did you bring your child?
Oh, I thought you had a son.
This isn’t Shinji.  I’ve decided to take
care of an acquaintance’s child.
Her name is Rei Ayanami.
How are you, Rei?
She resembles someone...
Yui?!
All of the records concerning Rei Ayanami
have been deleted?
They’re all blank!
What’s going on here?
S.C. MAGI
System
Complete
MAGI Casper...
MAGI Balthasar...
MAGI Melchior...
The MAGI are the three aspects of me.
Myself as a scientist, myself as a mother
and myself as a woman.
Those three aspects are in constant
conflict with one another.
Three mothers...
The only thing left to do
is to switch the power on.
I’ll be taking off early today.
Misato just got back.
Yeah, I heard that she joined Gehirn.
In Germany, if I remember correctly?
Yeah, she’s stationed with the 3rd Branch.
So, she’s having a
long-distance relationship.
They broke up.
Oh, but they seemed like
such a perfect couple.
The things that happen between men and
women are hard to comprehend.
They’re not logical.
You’re always so cold about these things.
You may lose your chance at happiness.
The definition of happiness is
even harder to fathom.
Well, I can’t wait to see her.
Have a good time.
A good time it is.
What’s the matter, Rei?
I’m lost.
Is that so?
Do you want to come with me then?
No.
But how will you get home by yourself?
That’s none of your business, old hag.
What?
I can get home by myself.
Leave me alone, old hag.
You shouldn’t call someone a hag.
But you are an old hag, aren’t you?
I’m getting angry.
Director Ikari will spank you.
The Director is the one
who calls you that.
That’s...
“That old hag is annoying.
That old hag is no use anymore.”
...old hag...  old hag...
“That old hag is annoying.
That old hag is no use anymore.”
The Director said...
...that old hag is annoying.
...no use...  no use...
You little bitch!  Did you know you’re
replaceable, too, Rei?
Replaceable just like me!
Keel Lorenz, chairman of the
Instrumentality Committee...
...dissolved the Gehirn Research
Organization immediately.
In order to complete the project, the
special organization “NERV” was formed.
We all transferred to NERV,
except for one person...
...the one who had rendered
such remarkable service to the
MAGI System, Dr. Akagi.
Oh, it’s you.
Yes, it is.
It’s been a while.  The guards are sleeping.
This action could result in your death.
All I want is to get closer to the truth...
...to have it in my grasp.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Is it over?
Yes, the problem has been solved.
I see.
Where is he?
I have no idea.
Oh, hi!  You’re a little late.
I’m back.
Katsuragi, it’s me.
I’m sure you’re listening to this message,
especially after I caused you
so much trouble.
Sorry.
Please tell Ritsuko “I’m sorry,” too.
And there’s one more thing to trouble you
with.  I’ve been growing melons.
I’d appreciate it if you could
water them for me.
Shinji knows where they are.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Don’t hesitate, move ahead!
If I ever see you again...
...I’ll say the words that I couldn’t
say eight years ago.
Bye.
This message was recorded at 12:02 PM.
You fool...
You were always such a fool...
All I could do was run away from the
tragedy Misato was facing.
There was nothing I could say.
I was just a child...
...but I understood.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Having been surpassed by Shinji yet again,
Asuka falls into a dark pit of despair...
...and the damage inflicted in the next
Angel’s attack is even more horrifying.
Shinji can find no words to soothe
her shattered soul.
It’s the next episode,
“At Least, Be Humane.”
Next Episode:
At Least,
Be Humane