Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
The second and third Ashino Lakes, I
hope there won’t be any more of those.
I received a complaint from Chairman
Keel yesterday regarding the delay.
He came directly to me.
He was very upset.  Towards the end,
he even threatened to dismiss you.
Adam is growing well...
...and work on the dummy plugs for
the Eva Project is proceeding.
What are the old men of SEELE
complaining about now?
The all-important Instrumentality
Project is behind schedule.
All the projects are linked.
There are no problems.
Including Rei?
Well, never mind.
By the way, what should
we do about that man?
Leave him alone for now.  The same
with the Marduk Institute.
I agree, let him work for us a while.
What started here, 16 years ago?
Episode 15:
Lie and Silence
It’s me.
Ah, so it is.
Shannon Bio, a foreign chemical firm.
This has been here for nine years, nine
years and not a single change.
The Marduk Institute has 108 affiliated
companies.  106 of them are
dummy corporations.
And this is the 107th?
This is the corporate registration.
And you want me to take a look at the
board of directors, don’t you?
You know about it already?
I know all of the names.
Marduk is supposedly an advisory
body controlled by the Instrumentality
Committee to select Evangelion pilots.
What it really does is not clear.
Your duty is to investigate NERV.
Getting involved with the Marduk
Institute is inappropriate.
Well, be that as it may, I want to see
everything for myself.
Hi, this is Kaji.  I’m out right now.
Please leave your name and message.
Help me, Kaji!
Don’t touch me, you pervert!
That’ll do it!
What’s going on?
Well, I want to go out tomorrow.
So I’ve been calling Kaji to ask him to
take me, but he’s been out.
He’s always out lately.
So you’ll have time tomorrow?
Regrettably so.
Then, I have a favor to ask you.
Well, it’s like this...
A date?!
A friend of my big sister,
Kodama, keeps asking me to
introduce you to him.
I beg you!
Get to work!
I’m sorry.
YOU!  Get to work!
Necrosis operation complete.
Graph measurement complete.
Which dress will you wear tomorrow?
Synch ratio is normal.
For the wedding?
I wore the pink suit for
Kiyomi’s wedding...
...and the dark blue dress for
Kotoko’s shower...
What about the orange one?
You haven’t worn that one
lately, have you?
Well, there’s a reason for that...
It’s too tight?
Yeah, so what?!
Should I get a new one
on the way home?
It’s an extra expense.
We’ve been invited to so many
showers lately...
...that the cost of all the gifts
is starting to add up.
Everyone’s just rushing to get married
before they’re thirty.
No one wants to be the
last one still single.
Okay, you can take off now.
Good work.
I’m tired of these stupid tests.
By the way, Shinji looks even more
downcast than usual today.
That’s because of tomorrow.
Yeah, tomorrow.
Tomorrow...  I have to see my father.
What should I talk to him about?
Why do you ask me?
Because I’ve seen you talking
happily with him.
Say, my father...
what kind of person is he?
I don’t know.
I see.
You’ve been watching me because you
wanted to ask me that?
When we were cleaning today...
...you were squeezing the cloth.
The way you squeezed it
was like a mother.
A mother...
I thought it was like a mother.
I think you’ll make a good
mother, Ayanami.
You’re embarrassing me.
You’re the one who caused
us to break up!
I’m home.
You’re the one who caused
us to break up!
What’s up?
I was wrong.  I must have been insane.
You’d better go to bed.  Aren’t you
going on a date tomorrow?
I was wrong.  I must have been insane.
You’d better go to bed.  Aren’t you
going on a date tomorrow?
I don’t care how you were!
Yeah, with a hunk.
I’m different now anyway!
Hey, that’s right, let me use your
lavender perfume!
I’m different now anyway!
Hey, that’s right, let me use your
lavender perfume!
But I still love you!
Absolutely not.
Jeez, cheapskate!
But I still love you!
You can’t reverse the hands of a clock!
It’s not for kids.
Is Shinji in his room?
You can’t reverse the hands of a clock!
We can’t go back to that time!
He’s been shut up since he got back.
But I still love you!
It looks like he doesn’t want
to see his father.
But I still love you!
It looks like he doesn’t want
to see his father.
I tell you, it’s impossible!
If he doesn’t, why doesn’t he just say
so.  I don’t understand you Japanese.
I tell you, it’s impossible!
If he doesn’t, why doesn’t he just say
so.  I don’t understand you Japanese.
It took me three years to forget you!
Well, he doesn’t really hate him...
...that’s the problem.
It took me three years to forget you!
Go away!
Well done, Shinji.
Shinji?
I’m opening the door.
Are you scared?
Of seeing your father by yourself?
Don’t run away.
Unless you step forward,
nothing will change.
I know that!
You’ll begin to realize...
...after that first step, it’s just as
important to take another step.
Anyway, go see him tomorrow with
your chin held high...
...because you’ll be seeing your
mother, too.
Well, good night.
Hey, you bought a new dress for
tomorrow, didn’t you?  Lemme see!
Oh, you wanna see?
It’s an expensive one.
The price doesn’t always
reflect the design.
Tell me about it.
Did you pick one to Kaji’s taste?
I don’t think so.  Not anymore.
Well...
...see you...
...later.
Place three bags in your heart...
Ladybugs with red, blue
and yellow dresses...
Now, let us proceed with
the reception...
Little Ryo’s late.
That idiot has never been on
time in his entire life!
For your dates, you mean?
He’s always on time for work.
Hey, girls!
You look marvelous today!
I couldn’t get off work.
I don’t believe that,
you never do anything anyway.
Why didn’t you shave?  That stubble’s
awful.  Look, your necktie is crooked.
Well, thank you.
You two act like you’re married.
Good point, Ri-baby.
Who the hell would marry this dork!
It’s been three years since the last time
we came here together.
I ran away then...
...and haven’t been back since.
My mother is resting here...
...I don’t really believe that.
I don’t even remember her face.
Man survives by forgetting
his memories.
But there are some things a man
should never forget.
Yui taught me about the
irreplaceable things.
I come here to confirm that.
You have no pictures of her?
There are none.
This grave is merely a decoration, too.
There’s no corpse.
So the teacher was right.
You threw them away.
I keep everything in my heart.
That is enough.
It’s time.  I’m leaving now.
Father!
Well...  I’m glad...
we could talk today.
Indeed...
Not bad!  I didn’t know you played.
I’ve been studying since I was five,
but I’m not very good.
I don’t really have any talent.
“Perseverance is power.”
I’m impressed.
I started studying because my
teacher told me to, but I could
have quit anytime.
So why didn’t you?
Because nobody told me to stop.
I should have known!
You came back early.
I thought you’d have dinner, too.
He was just so boring!
So while he was waiting in line for
the roller coaster, I left.
That’s harsh.
Really, Kaji is the only cool guy.
It’s getting late.
I’m going to the bathroom.
Are you gonna leave me alone?
High heels...
We haven’t really gotten together to
drink lately, have we?
Misato’s drinking too much, isn’t she?
She’s acting a little out of control.
Sometimes one drinks to keep oneself
under control.
We all do.
As someone who lived with her, your
words carry a certain weight of truth.
Well, I did live with her, but that
was before Katsuragi started wearing
heels like a real woman.
That’s not how we saw it back
when we were in school.
I was a kid.
That wasn’t really life.
Kid’s play is what it was.
Life isn’t that easy.
Oh yeah, I forgot to give you this.
A souvenir from a cat.
Oh, thank you.  You’re very honest.
Only with the ladies.
When it comes to work, I’m less so.
I somehow doubt that.
What about Misato?
I lost once before.
It’s not my style to keep fighting a
battle I’m sure to lose.
I think you still have a chance to win.
What about you?
It’s my policy to never
talk about myself.
There’s nothing amusing about me.
Why is Katsuragi taking so long?
Fixing her make-up maybe?
What were you doing in Kyoto?
No, that’s from Matsushiro.
Don’t try to fool me.
You’ll get your fingers burned if you
get involved in this too deeply.
That’s the advice of a friend.
I’ll take it seriously...
...but I’d prefer to be burned by the
heat of my passion for you.
Should I buy you some fireworks?
...but I’d prefer to be burned by the
heat of my passion for you.
Should I buy you some fireworks?
Welcome back!
You never change, do you?
Of course I change,
living means changing.
Homeostasis and transistasis.
What are those?
One is a force to maintain the
status quo, and the other is
a force for change.
Anything that contains these two
conflicting forces is alive.
Like men and women.
Well, I’ll be leaving now.
I’ve still got some work to do.
Really?
Sorry to hear it.
Later.
Hey, Shinji?  It’s me.
I’m with Kaji.
We’re gonna be out drinking.
Yes...  okay, later.
Was it Misato?
Yeah, she’ll be late,
so don’t wait up for her.
Is she gonna stay out until morning?
I don’t think so, she’s with Kaji.
Are you an idiot?!
That guarantees it!
Drinking so much you throw up like
a kid!  How old are you?
I know, but I’m not a kid.
Well, neither of us are.
Damn right.
I can’t believe you wear high
heels now, Katsuragi.
Time’s really flown.
Rough face...  You need to shave.
I can walk now.  Thank you.
Kaji, do you think I’ve changed?
You’re even more beautiful.
I’m sorry that I insisted on
breaking up with you.
When I said I had somebody else,
you knew...
...that it was a lie, didn’t you?
No.
It’s just that I realized...
...you were so much like
my late father, Kaji.
When...
...I realized that I wanted a man...
...like my father, I was terrified.
I was so afraid.
Being with you, Kaji...
...being a woman...
...everything scared me.
I hated my father, but fell in love with
someone just like him.
I chose to break everything
off and join NERV.
However, it turned out that my father
had worked for NERV, too.
I tried to bury my feelings by swearing
vengeance against the Angels.
That was your decision, Katsuragi.
You don’t have to be sorry.
No!  That wasn’t a decision!
I just escaped from reality.
Escaped from the reality
called “Father”!
I’m just like Shinji.
I’m a coward.
I’m really sorry.  I had to get drunk
just to tell you this.
That’s enough...
I’m just a child myself.
I have no right to tell Shinji anything.
That’s enough.
I’m a coward!
I just use men when I need to.
In the past, Kaji, I may have just...
just used you!
I’m so pathetic!
That’s enough!  Stop it!
I can’t stand myself!
Hey, Shinji, do you want to kiss me?
What?
A kiss...  kiss.  You’ve never
kissed a girl, have you?
What?
A kiss...  kiss.  You’ve never
kissed a girl, have you?
Then, let’s do it.
But why?!
Because I’m bored.
Is that a reason?!
Do you not want to kiss on the
anniversary of your mom’s death?
Afraid she may be watching
you from heaven?
It’s not that.
Are you scared?
Why would I be scared of a kiss?!
You brushed your teeth, didn’t you?
Then, here I come.
Stop breathing, it tickles me.
I should never kiss to kill time!
All right, here we are.  Hang on.
Kaji...
Kaji!
Well, I’ll be leaving now.
Why don’t you stay with us, Kaji?
I’d be laughed at if I went
to work in this.
It’ll be okay.
Hey, Kaji, it’ll...
Later.
Lavender perfume...
Please take care of Katsuragi.
Sure.
Well, night.
Good night.
What’s wrong?  You look sad.
It’s because you kissed me!!
Well, let me call the girls’ roll...
Ayanami...
Oh, Ayanami’s absent again?
Hi, how are you feeling today?
I’m sober now, thanks.
I’m glad to hear that.
Is this your real job or your other job?
What do you think?
Ryoji Kaji of NERV’s Special
Inspection Department...
...and at the same time Ryoji Kaji of
the Japanese Department of Interior.
Oh, so you know.
You underestimate NERV.
Is this an order from
Commander Ikari?
No, my sole discretion.  If you keep
doing this other job, you’ll die.
As long as Commander Ikari is using
me, too, I can still do it.
However, let me apologize for using
you, Major Katsuragi.
It’ll make us even for your
help yesterday.
Thanks very much...  but...
...the Commander and Ritsuko are
hiding something from you, too, and...
...this is it.
This is...
Eva?  No!
Impossible...
Yes, this is the source of
everything since the Second Impact.
The most important factor.
This is Adam.
Adam?  Why is the First Angel here?
You’re right.
I don’t know NERV at all.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Shinji Ikari gets ahead of Asuka
and jumps to the top place in the
synch tests.
He’s proud, but then he’s swallowed
by a Sea of Dirac.
With Eva’s energy supply running out,
fear, loneliness and cold crash
in upon him...
...teaching him a new level of
anguish and despair!
It’s the next episode,
“Sickness Unto Death, and...”
Of course, we’ll give you some
more fan service, too!
Next Episode:
Sickness Unto
Death, and...