Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
Are you refusing to allow us to question
the pilot of Unit 01, the only one directly
involved in the incident, Major Katsuragi?
Yes, sir.
Because he is emotionally very unstable...
...I believe that it would be unwise
to have him here.
Then, as his proxy, let us ask you,
Major Katsuragi.
In this incident, didn’t the Angel attempt
to communicate with a human being?
I find no suggestion of that
in the subject’s report.
I believe this was an irregularity,
a coincidence.
If, and only if, his memory is correct.
There is no evidence that his memory
has been tampered with.
However, the Eva’s AC recorder was not
functioning.  There’s no way to confirm it.
Was the Angel interested in the
human spirit?  In the human mind?
I am unable to answer that question.
Whether the Angels even have a
concept of what “mind” is...
...or whether they can understand
human thoughts or not...
...is completely unknown.
A new factor has been added with
this incident, in that the Angel
tried to take Eva into itself.
Is there any possibility that this
aspect may be linked to the predicted
Thirteenth Angel and all Angels thereafter?
Based on the previous patterns, there
would appear to be no systematic
organization among the Angels.
That is correct!  It is indeed obvious that
they have worked independently, so far.
What do you mean, sir?
You are not allowed to ask questions.
Understood.
That will be all.  Dismissed.
Yes, sir.
What do you think, Ikari?
The Angels appear to be getting
more and more intelligent.
There’s not much time left.
Episode 17:
The 4th Child
Left for us, you mean?
Who’s the patient in Room 12?
That’s the emergency room patient
from the first Eva incident.
She’s been here for a long time.
Her injuries were very severe, poor girl.
She’s still in elementary school.
He’s here again today?
Yeah, he comes to see her
at least twice a week.
He’s a good brother,
thinking about his sister like that.
Yeah, boys like that are pretty rare.
He has a good heart.
Rei, are you all right today?
Yes, sir.  I will be with Dr. Akagi tomorrow.
And the day after I’ll be at school.
How is school?
No problems, sir.
I see.  That’s good.
Stand up!  Bow!  Sit down!
Let me see, Ayanami is absent
as usual, and Aida, too?
What’s up with Kensuke?
Professor Koike is absent today...
He went to New Yokosuka,
to see a battleship.
...so modern Japanese will be self-study.
He went to New Yokosuka,
to see a battleship.
...so modern Japanese will be self-study.
A ship called Myoko or something
like that is in port.
And finally, the student on duty today is...
A ship called Myoko or something
like that is in port.
Mister Suzuhara.
Y...yes, sir!!
Will you deliver this document to
Miss Ayanami after school?
Yes, sir!
Don’t worry, First Branch is okay.
The data from the recon plane will
be confirmed by the MAGI.
It disappeared?!
The entire Second Branch just vanished?!
Yes, sir.  It’s been confirmed.
It’s gone.
Dear God...
The Administrative and Investigative
sections are going crazy...
...and General Affairs is in a total panic.
What was the cause?
It’s still under investigation.
Our only clues are these recon photos
from the geosynchronous satellite.
There’s nothing else left.
10 seconds...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Contact.
This is horrible.
Evangelion Unit 04, its support group and
all other facilities within an 89 km radius
were completely destroyed.
Along with thousands of people.
Looking at the time schedule...
...it would appear that they were in
the middle of installing the experimental
S2 engine from Germany.
Potential causes range from insufficient
structural integrity to a calculation error
during the preliminary design stage.
That’s 32,768 possibilities right there.
And that’s not mentioning sabotage.
But it wasn’t an explosion, was it?
It was a “disappearance.”
In all probability, they were swallowed by
a Sea of Dirac, just like Unit 01 was.
And the restored S2 engine?
Gone.  Along with our hopes.
It’s all because we’re being forced to use
things that we don’t really understand.
Things like the Evas.
What’ll we do with Unit 03?
We’ll receive it here.
The US government doesn’t want to
lose the First Branch as well.
Didn’t they insist on the right to
build Units 03 and 04?
And now they’re foisting it off on us?
They’re really pushing their luck.
After a disaster like that,
anyone would get nervous.
And how are you going to
do the test activation?
Will you use Rei’s dummy plug?
I’ll have to make a decision.
This is the dummy plug prototype.
Rei’s personal data has
been loaded into it...
...but it’s not really possible to digitize
a human mind and soul.
A fake, that’s all it is.
It copies a pilot’s thinking process.
In the end, it’s only a machine.
It transmits a signal pattern to Eva...
...and Eva believes that there is a pilot
and synchronizes.  That’s good enough.
Load the data into Unit 01 and Unit 02.
There are still some problems with it.
That’s not important.  As long as the
Eva activates, it’s sufficient.
Understood.
I’ve delegated the transportation
of the unit to the UN.
It will arrive by the end of the weekend.
You’ll take care of it from there.
Yes, sir.
We’ll perform the modifications and
activation test in Matsushiro.
And the test pilot will be...
Use of the dummy plug is not
recommended at this time.
One of our prospective candidates...
...will be chosen as the Fourth Child?
Yes.
There is one child whose core can
be prepared immediately.
Then, I’ll trust you to make it so.
Yes, sir.
Rei, we’re finished now.
Let’s eat.
Yes, sir.
Stand up!  Bow!
Lunch time!  Lunch time!
This is the single best thing about school.
You didn’t make lunches for us?!
I didn’t have time to cook last night.
I had too much homework.
And that’s your excuse for me having
to go without lunch?!
A husband and wife quarrel?
It’s not like that!!
What is it?  You look so serious.
It’s the Unit 03 activation test.
We’ll be using the Fourth as the pilot.
The Fourth?
The Fourth Child’s been found?
Just yesterday.
But I haven’t received a report from
the Marduk Institute yet.
The official documents will be
delivered tomorrow.
Dr. Akagi, are you hiding something
from me again?
No, nothing at all.
Well, okay.  So, who’s the kid?
Christ!  It’s HIM?!
It can’t be helped.
All of the prospective candidates have
been gathered together to protect them.
It’s so hard to tell them.
Asuka will be fine.
She’s committed to piloting an Eva.
Rei is exceptional...
...with no problems with her Eva
or our work.
Shinji probably knows the most
about the down side.
I don’t want him to suffer
any more hardships.
But we need children of this kind...
...in order for us all to survive.
Are you saying not to
complicate the issue?
Bye!  Later!  See ya!
Suzuhara!  You’ve got the duty
this week, get to work!
What do you mean?
The class printout!
Didn’t our teacher tell you to deliver this?!
Come on, Class Rep, you can ask the
other person on duty, can’t you?
Miss Ayanami is absent today!
Ayanami and me?
Then I guess there’s no choice.
But I don’t want to go to some
girl’s place all by myself.
Well, I can go with you...
Shinji!
Walk home with me, will you?
Ayanami!
We’re coming in.
You can’t enter a girl’s room
without her permission!
We’ve got no choice.
She won’t see it if we leave it there.
Excuse us...
My God!
Is this a girl’s room?  It’s so decrepit.
Hey!  You shouldn’t touch anything!
She’ll get pissed!
I’m just cleaning up.
I won’t help you!
That’s not a man’s job!
Okay, but Misato hates guys like that.
I don’t care!  It’s my policy!
Come to think of it, you’ve changed.
What?
You, Shinji.
The first time I saw you,
I really thought you were a jerk.
You didn’t seem like someone who’d
do something for someone else.
I guess you’re just really reserved.
Excuse us!
What?
Those are the school bulletins
that have piled up.
I’m sorry.
I took it upon myself to clean up a little.
But I didn’t touch anything except trash.
Th...thank you.
Eva pilots are sure weird all right.
Thank you...
Words of gratitude...
Words I’ve never used...
Not even to him...
The city, a paradise made by mankind.
Driven from Paradise...
...man escaped to this earthly existence,
on the edge of death.
Created by the weakest of beings...
...created by the sapience born from that
weakness, this paradise is our creation.
To protect ourselves from the fear
that death instills...
...to satiate our beings with pleasure...
...we create a paradise by
and of ourselves.
This city surely is such a paradise.
A city armed to protect us.
A city for those who run in fear from the
outside world, the world of our enemies.
But cowards do live longer.
That’s to our benefit.
The third New Tokyo,
NERV’s hidden intercept base...
...the long delayed seventh construction
phase will soon be finished.
At long last, it will be completed.
Unit 04’s “accident,” how will you
report it to the committee?
With the facts, the cause is unknown.
But this is a major, catastrophic loss.
Unit 04 and the Second Branch
are of no consequence.
The S2 engine prototype may have
been lost, but the data is still on
record in Germany.
This installation and Unit 01
will be sufficient.
But the committee is in a panic.
Of course, it was an
unscheduled accident.
SEELE must be busy changing
the schedule.
Incidents not depicted in the
Dead Sea Scrolls may occur.
This ought to teach the old men a lesson.
3rd District Transformation & Directional
Weapon experiment is on schedule.
The intercept system is completed...
Will Dr. Nishizono of the Technical
Department, Section 2...
...and they’re not going to have a party?
Will Dr. Nishizono of the Technical
Department, Section 2...
...and they’re not going to have a party?
...call Section 2 of the Development
Division immediately.
NERV is the most inflexible organization.
...call Section 2 of the Development
Division immediately.
NERV is the most inflexible organization.
It’s because of Commander Ikari.
And are you a prude, too?
Are you serious, Mr. Kaji?
I’ll tell Miss Katsuragi and Dr. Akagi.
Not if your mouth is covered with mine...
So, how’s it going?
Well, it’s going, I guess.
Well, I have work to do.  Excuse me.
Far be it from me to make judgments
on your private life...
...but under these circumstances should
you be hitting on girls in this organization?
Who’s under whom isn’t your concern.
Or would you prefer I hit
on you, Katsuragi?
It depends on how you
answer my questions.
You know the secrets behind the
Marduk Institute and that Adam thing
down there, don’t you?
What secrets?
Don’t try to feign ignorance!
Asking for help isn’t like you.
You know, at the moment I don’t care,
I’m not feeling very reserved.
The Fourth Child was conveniently
found at just the right time.
What’s the truth behind that?
I’ll tell you one thing.
The Marduk Institute doesn’t exist.
NERV is pulling the strings all by itself.
NERV itself?
Commander Ikari is?
You need to check Code 707.
Code 707?
Shinji’s school?
Misato!
What is it?
Ritsuko says she’s expecting you for a
meeting about tomorrow’s business trip.
All right.  Thank you.
See ya.
Yeah, yeah.
Buy you a drink?  Cup of tea?
But...  I’m a boy.
I thought you’d be a more
serious person, Kaji.
You’re saying that to someone as arrow
straight and reliable as me, Shinji Ikari?
I...I’m sorry.
I’m sorry, too.
I didn’t mean to sound rude.
Hey, I want to show you something.
Watermelons?
Yeah, aren’t they cute?  This is my hobby.
Keep it a secret, okay?
Growing...  making something
grow is really great.
One can see and learn so many
things from the process.
It also brings pleasure.
But pain, too, right?
Do you hate pain?
I don’t like it.
But have you found what
gives you pleasure?
That’s not so bad.
If you’ve known pain and hardship,
it’s easier to be kind to others.
Being kind isn’t a weakness.
Yes?  Hello?
It’s Katsuragi.
The synch test will be starting soon.
Fix the depth at 3.2.
I thought so.
Shinji’s synch ratio is dropping.
Fix the depth at 3.2.
I thought so.
Shinji’s synch ratio is dropping.
LCL thickness is nominal.
I thought so.
Shinji’s synch ratio is dropping.
Harmonics level is negative 1.1...
What’s that mean?
I can’t say.
Harmonics level is negative 1.1...
...0.5
I’m assuming that something may have
happened during the incident.
...0.5
I’m assuming that something may have
happened during the incident.
...0.9
I’m assuming that something may have
happened during the incident.
...0.8
I’m assuming that something may have
happened during the incident.
...0.9
Something in his mind.
Current exponent is 0.9.
This makes it even harder to tell
him about Unit 03’s pilot.
Current exponent is 0.9.
This makes it even harder to tell
him about Unit 03’s pilot.
All results will be posted to Melchior.
The pilot will be officially
informed tomorrow.
All results will be posted to Melchior.
The pilot will be officially
informed tomorrow.
Stand up!  Attention!  Bow!
Attention student Toji Suzuhara...
Lunch time!
Toji Suzuhara...
Report to the Principal’s Office.
What the...
What did you do?
I don’t know.
Excuse me, I’m Toji Suzuhara.
You’re Toji Suzuhara?
How was your trip to New Yokosuka?
Way cool!
Speaking of which, I picked up
some disturbing information.
Eva Unit 03?
Yeah, the one they built in America.
It’s completed, isn’t it?
I don’t know.
I know it’s classified,
but please tell me something!
I really don’t know!
Haven’t you heard the rumor that the
activation test will be held at the second
test facility in Matsushiro?
I haven’t.
The pilot hasn’t been chosen yet, right?
How would I know?
Misato could pick me for it.
Shinji, would you ask her for me?
I really want to be an Eva pilot!!
Really, I don’t know.
What about the story that
Unit 04’s been lost?
What was that?
You really don’t know?
It disappeared along with the
entire Second Branch.
My dad’s section was in a panic.
Really?
I think so.
Misato didn’t tell me anything.
Well, I guess it doesn’t directly
concern the pilots.
If she didn’t tell you, it’s probably because
you don’t need to know.
I’m sorry about bothering you
with weird questions.
But Toji hasn’t come back yet...
Thus, we, mankind, survived the hell
called the Second Impact and rose again.
The number of children has been
decreasing yearly...
Sorry I’m late.
I know about it.  Be seated.
Anyway, it is you, the younger
generations, who will lead the
way to the future...
Let’s go home.
What about Toji?
He’ll be late.
He’s got class duty.
The school is now closing.  All students
must go to their homes immediately.
Suzuhara!
You’re on duty.
Line up the desks and write up
the daily record!
I haven’t had lunch yet.
I’ll do it as soon as I’ve eaten.
Suzuhara, you always buy your lunch
from the school shop.
That’s because there’s no one
who cooks for me.
Suzuhara...
I have two sisters.  Their names
are Kodama and Nozomi...
...and I always cook lunch for them.
That must be a lot of work.
So, I’m actually a good cook,
though you might not think it.
Really?
And I always end up cooking
too much for our lunches.
That’s a waste...
If you need help getting rid of
your leftovers, I’ll help.
Yes, help me.
Kaji?
Oh, Asuka?  Sorry, I’m busy right now.
Can it wait?
But you have time to
see Misato, don’t you?
Damn it!  Not right now!
These are our synch data reports.
Four of them?
What in the hell is this?
Who made HIM the Fourth Child?
No!  I don’t understand!  What is this?!
Eva Unit 03 is delivered
to Matsushiro from America.
People glory in the last peaceful day,
unaware of the coming tragedy.
On that day, all eyes will be focused
on the children’s tragedy.
The quiet days that collusion has
camouflaged are gone...
...and Misato’s heart is filled with the
sound of Shinji screaming.
It’s the next episode,
“The Judgment of Life.”
And I’ll give you lots of fan service again!
Next Episode:
The Judgment
of Life