Zankoku na tenshi no youni
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Aoi kaze ga ima
Mune no door wo tataitemo
Watashidake wo Tada Mitsumete
Hohoenderu Anata
Sotto fureru mono
Motomeru koto ni muchu de
Unmei sae mada shiranai
Itaikena hitomi
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
Sono senaka niwa
Haruka mirai mezasu tameno
Hanega arukoto
Zankoku na tenshi no thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobitatsu
Hotobashiru atsui Pathos de
Omoide wo uragiru nara
Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Is he going to skip school again?
Shinji’s Lovely Suite
Shinji, wake up!  How long are you
going to keep skipping school?
It’s been five days now.  Unit 01 has
already been completely repaired.
You’re the pilot, are you going to
just leave it like that?!!
Shinji?!
Misato Katsuragi
He’s run away...
That’s not too surprising...
Episode 4:
Rain, Escape
and Afterwards
Shinji?
Well... uh...
We’re Shinji’s classmates, Aida
and Suzuhara, ma’am.
Aida and Suzuhara...?
Yes, ma’am.
Yes!!  I... I’m Suzuhara.
Aren’t you the boys who got in
Unit 01’s entry plug?
Yes, ma’am.
Yes, ma’am.  We’re sorry for
causing so much trouble.
The reason we came here today...
...is that Ikari’s been absent ever since
then.  So, we came to see if he was okay.
Shinji...  He’s at the NERV training
facility right now.
Oh, I see.
These are the printouts that were
building up on Shinji’s desk.
Oh, sorry for your trouble.  Thank you.
Well, we’ll be leaving now.
Please say “hi” to Shinji for us.
Uh, yeah.  I will.  Bye.
This is an unexpected development.
She was a real babe, wasn’t she?
Shinji, you idiot!!
Jerk!
The next station is Nagao Toge,
Nagao Toge.  The exit will switch
to the right side.
Thank you for using the Tokyo-3 Loop
Line.  This train will be going out of
service at this station.
Please, make sure you take all of your
belongings with you as you exit the train.
I’ve got to go back.
Hey there!  We’ve got some great
deals!  Hot young babes serving
heavenly refreshment!
Special services to heal your tired body,
services to fill you with energy!
You really couldn’t detect it, Doctor?!!
Yes.  An object only ten millimeters in
diameter crashed into Antarctica at
close to the speed of light.
The technology we had was unable to
predict or prevent such a thing.
It’s like hell out there!  Just what is
the purpose of science?!
The atmospheric flux caused by the
change in the Earth’s axis has
decreased by 3%.
So, it’s getting a little better?
No, there’s still a tidal wave
approaching at 230 meters a second!
Doctor!  We must evacuate!!
It’s my duty to remain here.
Doctor, choosing death is easy, but
you have an obligation to watch
this living hell!!
The World Flood Chronicles
Second Impact
The Second Tokyo...
All Night Showing Today
Elevator 100 Meters Ahead—Caution
Idiot.
Drop Off Only
Hakone Mountain Shuttle
He’s only 14 years old...
It seems so cruel, making him bear the
burden of mankind’s destiny.
We have no choice.  We have to use
14-year-olds to pilot the Evas.
I know.
So, has he called or made contact?
Nothing?
Nothing.  I don’t think he’s going
to come back again.
What are you going to do?
Nothing really...
If he’s not going to come
back, that’s okay too...
Why?
Because of what happened
after that last battle...
Why did you ignore my order?
I’m sorry.
I’m the one who’s in charge of your
operations, right?
Yes.
You’re supposed to obey my orders,
you know!  Do you understand?
Yes.
I’m warning you, never do it again.
Do you really understand
what I’m saying?!!
Yes.
Hey, you’re not going to get out of this
by just saying “yes” to everything I say.
I know that.  That’s enough, isn’t it?
We won the battle anyway.
You know, it may seem easy to go along
with whatever anyone else wants...
...but if you get into the Eva with that
attitude, it’ll kill you!
I don’t care.
It’d be nice if I could say you’ve
got the right attitude...
...but if you think you’re going to get
any praise out of me, you’re
wrong, Shinji Ikari.
That’s not the point.  In any case, I’m the
only one who can pilot it, aren’t I?
I’ll do it.
I see...
If piloting an Eva means nothing
but pain to him, he shouldn’t
get into it again.
Otherwise, I’m sure he’ll get killed.
But we need pilots.
Captain!!
Aida, go on ahead!!
But I can’t go and leave you behind!
You fool!
No!
There!
The new kid?
Ikari!
Today’s Operation Schedule
15:00 Deployment
16:00 Attack Preparation, Open fire
Toji was sorry about that.
He said that his kid sister scolded
him and said that “it was the robot
who saved our lives!”
That’s pretty embarrassing, being
chewed out by a second grader.
Right?
I like it at night because those noisy
cicadas don’t chirp.
I remember that it was pretty quiet
when I was a kid but there have been
more and more of them each year.
The ecosystem is returning
to its former state.
That’s what Misato said.
I see, Misato said so.
I really envy you.  Living with such a
beautiful woman and piloting the
Evangelion.
Oh God, I wish I could get behind
the controls just once!
You shouldn’t.  I think your mother
would be worried.
Oh, don’t worry about that.
I don’t have one.
I’m the same as you.
You’ll have something to eat, won’t you?
Yeah.
Do you usually do this sort of thing?
Umm... well, sure.
Is this some kind of training for
guerrilla warfare or something?
How could I fight with toys like
those?  It’s just for fun.
You’re Shinji Ikari, aren’t you?
Yes.
We’re from NERV Security Intelligence.
Under Article 8 of the Security Act,
we’re taking you to NERV Headquarters.
All right?
Yes.
And all you did was stand there?
That’s easy for you to say!  But it’s
like I said, they were NERV Security
Intelligence... professionals.
So what?!  Don’t you have any
balls at all?!
Sissy!
Pervert!
Ape!
Only an idiot fights when he knows he
can’t win.  Balls have nothing
to do with it.
Long time no see.
Yes.
Do you feel any better after
wandering around for two days?
I don’t know...
The Eva is on standby.  Will you pilot it?
Or won’t you?
You’re not going to scold
me for running away?
Of course not, I’m no relation
to you, am I?
If I say that I won’t pilot Unit 01,
what will you do with it?
I suppose that Rei will do it.
Won’t you pilot it?
It seems unrealistic for you to
force everything on her.
Don’t worry.  I’ll pilot it.
But you don’t want to do it?
Of course not.  To begin with, it’s not
something that comes to me naturally...
...but Ayanami, Miss Misato
and Miss Ritsuko...
Cut that out!
This has nothing to do with any of us!
If you don’t like it, get out of here!  Just
forget all about Eva and us and go
back to where you came from!
We don’t need someone with
that attitude piloting.
The Third Child is leaving
Tokyo-3 tomorrow.
Then we’ll reconfigure Unit 01’s
system for Rei.
But...
Regardless of the results of the Unit 00
reactivation experiments, we’ll move
on to experimenting on Unit 01.
According to the Marduk Institute’s
Report, the Fourth Child hasn’t
been found yet.
That means we can’t get
any pilot recruits?
Excuse me, where is Miss Misato?
I’d like to say goodbye.
You’re no longer NERV personnel.
Therefore, we can’t give you
any information.
Ikari!!
You left this stuff behind, Ikari!
Could you excuse me a moment...?
Well, thank you.
Hey, Toji.
Come on, say something!
Ikari, I’m sorry I hit you twice.
Please, hit me back!
I can’t do that.
Please!  Otherwise, I won’t be satisfied.
See?  He’s a pretty embarrassing
guy isn’t he?
But if it’ll put an end to this dispute,
why don’t you go ahead and hit him?
But...
Hurry up!  You don’t have much
time, do you?
Okay, but only once...
Okay!  Come on!
Hold it!!
Stop.  Don’t hold back.
Right.
Ouch...
How did you know I’d come here?
It was just a hunch.  We’ve seen dozens
of classmates off before.
If you’re leaving, we’ll have to leave
this city sometime soon, but...
...we can’t blame you for that.  We saw
how you suffered in the Eva.
And if anyone tries to blame you...
...I’m gonna give them a headbutt!
Hey, don’t look so gloomy.
Take care.
Well...
Your time is up.
I’m the one who deserves to be hit!  I’m
mean, cowardly, dishonest and weak...
...sneaky and... a sissy...
Don’t give us any more trouble...
He’s gone.
Do you really think this is for the best?
The “Hedgehog’s Dilemma”... the closer
we become, the more deeply we
hurt each other...
Now I understand.
That boy...
He can’t let others know how he
feels in any other way.
The Express Linear Train, bound for
Atsugi, is arriving on Track 2.
For your safety, please step back to the
area inside the yellow lines.
The train arriving on track 2 is for
special government use only and
departs at 4:20 for Atsugi.
No civilians are allowed
inside the fence.
Please be aware that the boarding of
this train by unauthorized persons
is strictly prohibited.
Hang in there.
Hey, look!
Hey, it’s that babe!
The local train bound for Gora is now
arriving on track 4.  For your own safety,
please stay inside the yellow lines.
If you’re accompanying small children,
please ensure that they are properly
supervised.
The train arriving on track 4 is the
local shuttle to Gora, departing at 4:32.
If this is your train, please step inside
and wait until departure.
The train is now approaching.
Please stay behind the yellow line.
I... I’m home.
Welcome home.
To Be Continued
NEXT
EPISODE
Rei Ayanami limits her association with
others as much as possible.
The only one she seems to open up
to is Commander Ikari.
Shinji is at a loss to understand how
this girl can be closer to his own
father than he is.
But before he can settle his mind on this
subject, a beam shot by the Fifth Angel
melts Eva Unit 01’s chest!
Shinji’s scream reverberates
in Misato’s ears.
It’s the next episode,
“Rei, Beyond Her Heart.”
Next Episode:
Rei, Beyond
Her Heart