Like an angel that has no
sense of mercy...
Rise, young boy, to the heavens
like a legend.
Cold winds, as blue as the sea,
Tear open the door to
your heart, I see.
But unknowing you seem, just
staring at me...
Standing there smiling serenely.
Desperate, for something to touch...
A moment of kindness like
that in a dream.
Your innocent eyes, have yet no idea...
Of the path your destiny will follow.
But someday you’ll become aware of...
Everything that you’ve got behind you.
Your wings are for seeking out a new...
Future that only you can search for.
The cruel angel’s thesis enters through
the window of your soul.
If you should betray the chapel
of your memories.
The cruel angel’s thesis bleeds through
a portal like your pulsing blood.
So, boy, stand tall and embrace
the fire of the legend,
Embracing the universe like
a blazing star!
La raison d’être
The reason for existence
The reason that allows
one to exist.
The Case of Shinji Ikari
This boy wished for death.
The other boy accepted
that wish.
The last Angel is no more.
Yet, Shinji Ikari is still full
of anguish.
Why did you kill him?!
There was no other choice!
Because he was an Angel!
Kaoru was an Angel!
Although he was human
as well?
He was still an Angel!
He was still one of the enemy!
Although he was human
as well?
He wasn’t!  He wasn’t!  He was not!!
Even though he was
as human as me?
No!  He was an Angel!!
Is that why you killed him?
Yes!  Otherwise we all would have died!
We would all have been destroyed!
So that’s why you killed him?
I didn’t want to kill him!
I didn’t have a choice!!
Help me...
Help me.
Help me!
Somebody, please, help me!
I’m begging you!
Somebody, please, help me!!
You know, it was Kaoru who
should have survived.
He was much better than I am.
He was the one who should
have survived.
No, the one who survives is the one
who has the will to survive.
He wished for death.
He neglected his will to survive
and chose a false hope.
You weren’t wrong, Shinji.
Are you sure?
Are you sure it was right?
I don’t understand.
What can I do?
What am I supposed to do?!
What was that?
I fear myself.
I fear being hated.
But by whom?
Who is it?
It’s my...
...father!
My father abandoned me.
He hates me.
If others hate me, what will I do?
What will I do?
Where am I?
Where am I supposed to go?
I can’t see anything.  I don’t
understand what I feel.
Misato?
Misato?!
Hey, where are you, Misato?
Hey, where am I supposed to go?
Misato?  Asuka?  Ayanami?
Toji?  Kensuke?  Ritsuko?  Kaji?
Father?
Mother?
Somebody, please!  Please tell
me what I have to do now!
Evangelion Unit 01...
I still have to pilot it?
Even after it made me kill him?
My father and the others tell me that
I have to pilot it no matter what.
Why do I have to keep fighting
after all that’s happened?!
Mother!
Say something!  Answer me!!
Because everyone tells me to.
What do you mean?  It’s for the sake
of mankind!  Isn’t that good enough?
That’s right!  Is there something
wrong with that?!  I’m doing
the right thing!
When I do it the others appreciate
me!  The others like me then!
You’re lying!
Are you stupid?!
You know damn well that
you do this for yourself!
You’re just making excuses,
the way you always do!
I do?
Pretending that you’re sacrificing
yourself for the sake of others is
just another cop-out, isn’t it?
It makes you feel so superior
to play the martyr!
I’m not sure that’s true.
You’re feeling lonely and
isolated, nothing more.
Am I?
Of course you are!  You live on
sympathy!  You gain it through your
symbiosis with your Eva, Shinji!
It could be true.
You love having others depend on
you!  It really satisfies your
twisted little mind!
That could be.
All you’re doing is sitting there
and waiting for someone else
to bring you happiness!
But it’s a false happiness!
But isn’t that what you’ve
been doing?
The Second Character
The Case of
Asuka Langley Soryu
I didn’t want to be in this Eva again.
They’re forcing me to pilot this.
But this piece of junk won’t work!
But it’s only junk because of what
I’ve become.  I’m the garbage now.
I’m worthless.  Nobody needs me.
Nobody needs a pilot who can’t
even control her own Eva.
You seek your own value in
the perception of others.
Shut up!
Do you fear being alone?
Are you afraid that you will lose
your identity if others leave you?
You pilot the Eva so that you’ll
be praised by others.
Shut up!  Shut up!  Just shut up!
How can a wind-up doll like
you dare to tell me that?!
Who am I?
You are Rei Ayanami.
But who are you?
Are you Rei Ayanami as well?
Correct, I am that which is
recognized as Rei Ayanami.
We are all things that are known
as Rei Ayanami.
How could all of these be me?
It is simply because the others call
us Rei Ayanami, that is all.
You possess a false soul and a fake
body?  Do you know why?
I am neither false nor fake.
I am simply me.
No, you are an empty shell with
a false soul, created by a man
named Gendo Ikari.
You are just an object that is
pretending to be a human.
See, look deep within yourself.
Do you perceive the almost
intangible, invisible presence that
lurks inside your darkest dreams?
It is there that your true identity lies.
No, I am me.
I became myself through the
instrumentality of the links and
my relationships with others.
I am formed by interaction
with others.  They create
me as I create them.
These relationships and interactions
serve to shape the patterns
of my heart and mind.
“Those are bonds?”
Yes, that is the name for what I share
with those who have created the
being known as Rei Ayanami.
That is what will continue
to shape me.
“Those are bonds.”
However, there is someone else
who is your true self.
You don’t know her, but she exists.
You deny that fact and attempt to
suppress that facet of your reality.
“Because of fear.”
Because she might not
have a human form.
Because then your present
self might cease to be.
“This is fear.”
This is what you fear,
that you will become nothing.
You are frightened that you will
disappear from the minds of
others if another exists.
I’m afraid?  Why is that?
Because then your current self
will have never existed.
“You are scared, aren’t you?”
Because you will cease to be.
No, I’m happy.
Because I want to die.  I want
despair.  I want to return to nothing.
But I can’t.
He won’t let me return to nothingness
yet.  He won’t let me return yet.
I still exist because he needs me.
But when everything is over...
...when I am of no use anymore...
...he will abandon me.
I’ve prayed for the day he
would abandon me.
But now...  I fear it.
Well, let’s go.  This is the day for
which you were created, Rei.
Yes, sir.
And—
The Complementation of
Man Via the
Instrumentality Begins
Episode 25:
The Ending World
What is this feeling?
I think I’ve experienced this
sensation before.
It’s as though my physical form
were disappearing.
It feels nice.
As though my being is spreading
itself out to cover the entirety
of existence.
This is the beginning
of Instrumentality.
That which the
people had lost...
...the minds which
had disappeared...
...is rushing in to fill
the void in the mind.
The complementation,
Instrumentality for the
mind and the soul,
begins.
Instrumentality, which
will return all things
to nothingness...
...has begun.
Incorrect.  It is not a return
to nothingness.
It is merely a return to the
state of beginning.
It is no less than a return to
the primal womb that we
lost so long ago.
All individual souls and minds
will become one, thereby attaining
a state of eternal peace.
The final goal is nothing
more than that.
And that’s Instrumentality?
Yes, there is an emptiness at the very
core of our souls, a fundamental
incompleteness...
...that has haunted all beings since
the very first thought.
On a primal level, man has always
been aware of the darkness
at the core of his mind.
We seek to escape this void
and the fear it causes.
All man’s accomplishments proceed
from hopes of filling it.
Yet, the darkness will never vanish
as long as mankind is merely human.
And so you’ll just crush everyone’s
minds together to fill the gaps?!
How dare you presume to make the
entirety of human existence into an
experiment to prove your theory?!
And to use deception in order
to accomplish it?!
And yet, that is exactly as
you wished it to be!
Where am I?
This is the me that exists
in your mind, Misato.
And yet, at the same time this is also
the me which exists in your mind,
isn’t it, Shinji?
In order to establish my identity,
I have to communicate with the
minds of many people.
I have to examine that
which is at my core.
I have to stare at Misato who resides
on the inside of my mind.
What is it that you wish for, Misato?
“Do you want to be good?”
I have to be a good child.
“Why?”
Because I have no papa.
Because I have to be good and
not bother my mama.
But I don’t want to become
like my mama.
When my papa is not here,
she always cries.
I can’t cry.  I can’t depend
on anyone else.
So, I have to be good.
That way, maybe my papa
won’t hate me.
But I hated my father,
and I hated being a good child.
I hate it.
I’m tired of it.
I’m tired of keeping myself clean.
I’m tired of myself pretending
to be pure and noble.
I’m so tired of it all.
I want to disgrace myself.
I want to see my life and
my reputation ruined.
Is that why you slept with him?
With Kaji?
No!  I slept with him because
I loved him.
Did you really love him?
Yes, I did!  He accepted
me for myself!!
“Are you sure?”
He was kind!
No!  Don’t show this to Shinji!!
Why are you still embarrassed after
all that’s happened?
Because I’m ashamed of it!
Why does this embarrass you?
You aren’t ashamed.  Rather,
you take great pleasure in revealing
yourself to the one you love.
No, don’t do this!!
You’re happy to show this
to Shinji, aren’t you?
It’s a lie!  No, no, I’m not!!
Are you sure?  Or perhaps it’s your
father that you’d like to show this to?
No!
Wasn’t it really peace of mind that
you were seeking in Kaji’s bed?
No!
You wanted peace of mind and
warmth from Kaji, right?
No!!
You wanted to find your father in
Kaji’s embrace, didn’t you?
It’s not true!
It is true.
In Kaji, I had found
my father reborn.
And so, I fled from him.
I was so afraid.
He was so much like my father.
But at the same time, I was also very
happy.  I was never happier.
That was such a wonderful time.
That’s why I hated it.
That’s why I left.
So, no reason was required to
begin our love, but you needed
a reason for ending it?
You are so kind, Kaji.
You are so kind.  I beg you...
...disgrace me.
Just because you hate yourself is no
reason to injure yourself further.
Punishing yourself is simply
a cheat to make you feel better
for a little while.
Don’t do this to yourself.
And now, you’ll tell me to
take care of myself?
Men always do that.
They escape to their jobs, their own
world, and leave me behind.
They always leave me behind.
Just like my father did.
They always escape from
the harsh realities.
Harsh reality?  I am his harsh reality.
Of course, I’m a problem, aren’t I?
Stop that, Misato!
I despise myself!  I hate myself!
You’re vulgar and impure.
You’re pathetic.
You’re disgusting!
You’re a dirty whore!
I’ve never seen anyone in such
a disgusting relationship!
Congratulations on your promotion,
Major Katsuragi!
The me who is recognized is
the me who’s performing a role
in order to be appreciated...
...but she’s not the real me.
Your true self is always
crying, isn’t she?
Yes, but I’m happy.
“Am I happy?”
I am happy.
It’s true, I am happy!
“Am I happy?”
I’m not!  This isn’t the
happiness I want!
“What is happiness?”
This isn’t me, it’s not my true self!
I just don’t want to face
the harsh reality!
But we must.
We can’t live otherwise.
You’d be alone and afraid...
...unstable...
...if no one were sleeping next to you.
Are you afraid of sleeping alone?
Or does sleeping by yourself remind
you of how empty your life is?
She can’t stand not having
other souls around her.
So, you’ll sleep with
anyone, won’t you?
No!!
Yes, you just want to be infatuated
with primal ecstasy.
You want to fill the hole in your
heart with temporary escape.
You take advantage of men to soothe
the pain in your soul.
No!  No!  No!!
Where am I?
This is the me which exists
in your mind, Asuka.
And yet, at the same time this is also
the me which exists in your mind,
isn’t it, Shinji?
The Case of
Asuka Langley Soryu,
Part 1
What do you want, Asuka?
I want to live by myself!
I don’t want my papa and my
momma.  I’ll live by myself!
And then I won’t cry anymore!
But I’m still crying.
Why am I still crying?
I’m sorry, I just don’t like her.
What happened to you, the capable doctor?
I told you, I’m a human being
before I’m a doctor.
But how can a trained
professional like you...
She acts too much like an adult and
she rejects me absolutely.
Sometimes she even scares me.
Have you gotten such a
feeling from her?
No, and, in any case, you are
now Asuka’s mother.
That may be, but I’m your
wife before that.
Both duties are concurrent.
In a social perspective, yes.
But you can’t quit being her father.
I can quit being her mother anytime.
Well, you could say so.
No, Momma!  Don’t quit being my
momma!  I’ll be a good kid!
Don’t stop being my momma!
Don’t ignore me!
No, Momma!  Don’t kill me!
Your papa hates your momma.
He doesn’t need me anymore.
No, he didn’t love me to begin with.
He didn’t need me at all.
So, let’s die together because
Papa doesn’t need us.
Am I a waste?
Am I not worth anything?
Die with me!
No, I am not your doll!  I’ll think
for myself and live by myself!
Then, my momma was hanging
from the ceiling.
She looked so happy.
But I hated how she looked.
I don’t want to die.
I don’t want to disappear.
I hate boys!  I hate my papa
and my momma!
I hate everyone!
Nobody cares about me.
Nobody stays with me!
So, I don’t want to
depend on anybody!
But I hate it at the same time.
It’s a pain!
I don’t want to be alone!
I don’t want to be alone!!
Don’t leave me.
Don’t abandon me.
Don’t kill me.
What is this?
This is the Instrumentality which
your father is beginning.
This is it?
This is part of it.
You can’t tell what the truth is.
You can barely tell if what
you’re feeling is real.
The truth is within you.
And the facts that remain in
your memory are what will
become your truth.
Truth can be changed
from time to time.
This is all real.  This is the
result of everything?
This is real, but only one
of the many realities.
This is the conclusion you wanted.
Wanted?  Me?
Yes, total destruction.  You wished
for a world in which nobody
would be saved.
No!  I didn’t wish for this!
The others didn’t save me.
Nobody can save you.
This is what you wished for.
Destruction, death and a return to
nothingness...  you wished for these.
This is that reality.
What is reality?
This is your world.
A world for yourself that exists
without time, space or others.
A world in which every facet
was determined by you.
This is the world where you just wait
for others to give you something.
This is your world no matter what.
This is the world that is!
Nothing can change that!
No, you made the decision.
This is the world where your mind
decides what will be.
Whether it is the will to survive...
...or a wish for death,
it is all up to you.
Are you saying that this darkness,
this insane world, are what I
really wished to create?!
Yes.
You wished for a closed world that
was comfortable for you.
In order to protect your weakness...
...to protect your few pleasures.
This is merely a result of your wish.
In your closed world, in a world
where only you are allowed to be,
others cannot live with you.
But still you wished to close the
world that surrounds you.
Your wish ejected things you
disliked and created an isolated
and lonely world.
This is the world your wishes have
created, a private haven in the
recesses of your mind.
This is how it ends.  It is one of
many possible endings.
This is an ending you brought upon
yourself.  You chose this fate.
Instrumentality...
...Continues
NEXT
EPISODE
An end always comes
after a beginning.
Will our hopes result in
ultimate destruction?
Is our hope death itself?
It’s the final episode:
“The Beast That Shouted ‘I’ at the
Heart of the World.”
Final Episode:
The Beast That
Shouted “I” at the
Heart of the World